<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-02-10T18:03:28+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/atom.xml</id><title type="html">Sandy’s Palace</title><subtitle>Rosa&apos;s gay little website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Me 0.1 Seconds After I Get A New Phone</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/10/Me-0.1-Seconds-After-I-Get-A-New-Phone.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Me 0.1 Seconds After I Get A New Phone" /><published>2025-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/02/10/Me-0.1-Seconds-After-I-Get-A-New-Phone</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/10/Me-0.1-Seconds-After-I-Get-A-New-Phone.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/blog/graphene-1.jpg" alt="A picture of GrapheneOS being installed on a Pixel 8." /></p>

<div>
    <p>
        Yeah we running Graphene in this house keep scrolling
    </p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PiHole Blocking for Samsung Junk TVs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/05/PiHole-Blocking-for-Samsung-Junk-TVs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PiHole Blocking for Samsung Junk TVs" /><published>2025-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/02/05/PiHole-Blocking-for-Samsung-Junk-TVs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/05/PiHole-Blocking-for-Samsung-Junk-TVs.html"><![CDATA[<div>
    <p>
        I hate modern technology, I fucking hate smart applications and the Internet of Things, and I utterly despite Smart TVs. Naturally I had to turn this into a hobby.
    </p>
    <p>
        I already have a Raspberry Pi 4B running <a href="https://pi-hole.net/">PiHole</a> for my home network, which I might make another blog post about. What this post relates to is the specific blocking of Samsung TV's dumb shit, and preventing it from updating the firmware.
    </p>
    <p>
        By default, Samsung Smart TVs send way too much analytics back to home base. Out of principle, I wanted to shut this down. Previous blocklists running on the PiHole proved this could work. 
    </p>
    <p>
        Also blocking firmware updates has now become crucial, as the newer updates include <a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/home-entertainment/samsungs-2025-tvs-get-all-the-ai-extras-nobody-asked-for/">AI-generated total junk</a> that is burned into your home screen. The home screen is already fucking terrible as-is.
    </p>
    <p>
        With some light testing (read: adding lines until the updates stop and the TV doesn't break), I've created this blocklist that aims to block future updates, while still allowing the TV to function:
    </p>
    <p>
    <a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/assets/files/samsung_pihole.txt">Blocklist</a>
    </p>
    <p>
        I will update this post based on observations over the next few days. Feel free to link directly to the above URL, I've got plenty of server capacity.
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>5th Feb 2025</b>: PiHole is successfully blocking most Samsung CDN domains. Pop-up for firmware update hasn't appeared after a few soft resets. This may only occur a set amount of times per day, so I'll check for this tomorrow. TV otherwise working "well".
    </p>
    <p>
        <b>9th Feb 2025</b>: Popup notification for firmware updates have appeared again. I can't immediately see any queries going to Samsung domains. Fuckin delightful.
    </p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I hate modern technology, I fucking hate smart applications and the Internet of Things, and I utterly despite Smart TVs. Naturally I had to turn this into a hobby. I already have a Raspberry Pi 4B running PiHole for my home network, which I might make another blog post about. What this post relates to is the specific blocking of Samsung TV's dumb shit, and preventing it from updating the firmware. By default, Samsung Smart TVs send way too much analytics back to home base. Out of principle, I wanted to shut this down. Previous blocklists running on the PiHole proved this could work. Also blocking firmware updates has now become crucial, as the newer updates include AI-generated total junk that is burned into your home screen. The home screen is already fucking terrible as-is. With some light testing (read: adding lines until the updates stop and the TV doesn't break), I've created this blocklist that aims to block future updates, while still allowing the TV to function: Blocklist I will update this post based on observations over the next few days. Feel free to link directly to the above URL, I've got plenty of server capacity. 5th Feb 2025: PiHole is successfully blocking most Samsung CDN domains. Pop-up for firmware update hasn't appeared after a few soft resets. This may only occur a set amount of times per day, so I'll check for this tomorrow. TV otherwise working "well". 9th Feb 2025: Popup notification for firmware updates have appeared again. I can't immediately see any queries going to Samsung domains. Fuckin delightful.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celeste Is Good</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/30/Celeste-Is-Good.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celeste Is Good" /><published>2025-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/30/Celeste-Is-Good</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/30/Celeste-Is-Good.html"><![CDATA[<div>
    <p>
        Ticking off another game on the "quintessential games for enlightened catgirls" list, I played Celeste this month for the first time.
    </p>
    <p>
        It was my first proper 2D platformer since... one of the older Castlevania games I think? And it was an incredible title to pick - the level design, mechanics, and soundtrack are all built with a wonderful amount of love.
    </p>
    <p>
        I'm completely hooked, and am now going back to pick up every strawberry, and make a solid attempt at the B-sides. Chapter 8 and 9 will soon follow :3
    </p>
</div>

<p><img src="/assets/images/blog/celeste1.png" alt="A screenshot of Celeste after the first playthough. 94 out of 175 strawberries, 1738 deaths, and 9 hours and 54 minutes playtime." /></p>

<div>
    <p>
    In my defense a few hundred of these deaths were early B-side attempts lolololol
    </p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ticking off another game on the "quintessential games for enlightened catgirls" list, I played Celeste this month for the first time. It was my first proper 2D platformer since... one of the older Castlevania games I think? And it was an incredible title to pick - the level design, mechanics, and soundtrack are all built with a wonderful amount of love. I'm completely hooked, and am now going back to pick up every strawberry, and make a solid attempt at the B-sides. Chapter 8 and 9 will soon follow :3]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I Love Niche Problems</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/07/I-Love-Niche-Problems.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Love Niche Problems" /><published>2025-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/07/I-Love-Niche-Problems</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/07/I-Love-Niche-Problems.html"><![CDATA[<div>
    <p>
        At this point I still haven't typed up an explanation of my F1 archiving and distribution work, so out of context this will appear even more insane than usual.
    </p>
    <p>
        Long story short, I've been building up a rather popular niche in the high seas community. My archive of F1 media is solid, comparable to plenty of other buffs around the world, but I've made a commitment to sharing it as widely as possible, for as long as possible.
    </p>
    <p>
        It's more of a long-term safe storage solution, as most casual internet users won't go beyond a simple stream. But for those willing to make the extra effort, I've been making some great progress on building up the greatest archive of F1 media imagineable, one totally impossible within the confines of archaic copyright law.
    </p>
    <p>
        There's still years to go. But I receive the most wonderful messages from people online. Some talk about reliving their childhood memories watching their first ever season, decades on. Others have found special moments they never even knew existed in the sport. And some just love the archiving work.
    </p>
    <p>
        These are my toughest customers, and also my favourites. Because at no point before in my life did I ever think I'd receive a message on Reddit from a stranger, offering me the inaugural race of the 1985 Formula 3000 season with such eagerness. And I was always going to say yes please and thank you.
    </p>
    <p>
        The fellow crackheads continue their relentless assault. Three different collectors have come forward - two for F1, one for MotoGP. We will argue over broadcaster feeds, commentary tracks, video encoding standards. Together we will comb and merge everything, and create a work even more comprehensive than last year. And then we'll do it again, and again, and again.
    </p>
    <p>
        Such wonderful situations pose the most wonderful problems. Such as - how the fuck can I keep effectively storing this stuff? And how the hell am I going to have all the time to work through this?
    </p>
    <p>
        FOM wishes they had our freedom.
    </p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[At this point I still haven't typed up an explanation of my F1 archiving and distribution work, so out of context this will appear even more insane than usual. Long story short, I've been building up a rather popular niche in the high seas community. My archive of F1 media is solid, comparable to plenty of other buffs around the world, but I've made a commitment to sharing it as widely as possible, for as long as possible. It's more of a long-term safe storage solution, as most casual internet users won't go beyond a simple stream. But for those willing to make the extra effort, I've been making some great progress on building up the greatest archive of F1 media imagineable, one totally impossible within the confines of archaic copyright law. There's still years to go. But I receive the most wonderful messages from people online. Some talk about reliving their childhood memories watching their first ever season, decades on. Others have found special moments they never even knew existed in the sport. And some just love the archiving work. These are my toughest customers, and also my favourites. Because at no point before in my life did I ever think I'd receive a message on Reddit from a stranger, offering me the inaugural race of the 1985 Formula 3000 season with such eagerness. And I was always going to say yes please and thank you. The fellow crackheads continue their relentless assault. Three different collectors have come forward - two for F1, one for MotoGP. We will argue over broadcaster feeds, commentary tracks, video encoding standards. Together we will comb and merge everything, and create a work even more comprehensive than last year. And then we'll do it again, and again, and again. Such wonderful situations pose the most wonderful problems. Such as - how the fuck can I keep effectively storing this stuff? And how the hell am I going to have all the time to work through this? FOM wishes they had our freedom.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello World and FUCK JEKYLL</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/12/22/Hello-World-and-FUCK-JEKYLL.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World and FUCK JEKYLL" /><published>2024-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/12/22/Hello-World-and-FUCK-JEKYLL</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/12/22/Hello-World-and-FUCK-JEKYLL.html"><![CDATA[<div>
    <p>
        The initial opening line here was complaining at how the all-caps didn't render properly on the home page, until it just did. I'm not ignoring this.
    </p>
    <p>
        This supposedly simple project has been rendered excruciatingly difficult at every single stage by this utter piece of shit. In no particular order:
        <ul>
            <li>Documentation is totally at odds with GitHub Pages tutorials, despite Jekyll being the recommended site builder tool</li>
            <li>Directories and files that should have been generated with 
<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-plaintext" data-lang="plaintext">jekyll new my-awesome-site</code></pre></figure>
just... weren't. Their own documentation then expects you to be working with files that simply don't exist, and make no mention of how/where to create them</li>
            <li>Most themes built for Jekyll are not supported by GitHub Pages, nobody mentions this until far too late</li>
            <li>Compatability between Ruby's gems and Bundler is appalling. I have two different versions of so many things, which is gonna cause huge problems down the road</li>
            <li>Whoever wrote the documentation for Liquid needs to be beaten to death, as an act of sympathy and mercy</li>
        </ul>
    </p>
    <p>
        However we are here, with a functioning page on GitHub Pages, mostly because I gave up on hosting it on a dedicated server that also hosted a Swizzin seedbox. Far too many Nginx overrides meant I couldn't get the domain name to point to Sandy's Palace properly, so I've split the two, and left the seedbox to fester on its own IP address.
    </p>
    <p>
        Despite all forces in the universe trying to make it otherwise, I am committed to this being a fun and gay little website. Until I meet the Jekyll devs.
    </p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The initial opening line here was complaining at how the all-caps didn't render properly on the home page, until it just did. I'm not ignoring this. This supposedly simple project has been rendered excruciatingly difficult at every single stage by this utter piece of shit. In no particular order: Documentation is totally at odds with GitHub Pages tutorials, despite Jekyll being the recommended site builder tool Directories and files that should have been generated with jekyll new my-awesome-site just... weren't. Their own documentation then expects you to be working with files that simply don't exist, and make no mention of how/where to create them Most themes built for Jekyll are not supported by GitHub Pages, nobody mentions this until far too late Compatability between Ruby's gems and Bundler is appalling. I have two different versions of so many things, which is gonna cause huge problems down the road Whoever wrote the documentation for Liquid needs to be beaten to death, as an act of sympathy and mercy However we are here, with a functioning page on GitHub Pages, mostly because I gave up on hosting it on a dedicated server that also hosted a Swizzin seedbox. Far too many Nginx overrides meant I couldn't get the domain name to point to Sandy's Palace properly, so I've split the two, and left the seedbox to fester on its own IP address. Despite all forces in the universe trying to make it otherwise, I am committed to this being a fun and gay little website. Until I meet the Jekyll devs.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">To Do List for this Webbed Site</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/10/10/to-do-list-for-this-webbed-site.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="To Do List for this Webbed Site" /><published>2024-10-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/10/10/to-do-list-for-this-webbed-site</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/10/10/to-do-list-for-this-webbed-site.html"><![CDATA[<div>
  <p>
    At time of writing, this site has a basic home page, navbar, Blog Archive, and About page all typed up.
  </p>
  <p>
    It's been created via <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> as a static site generator, and the theme is a lightly modified version of <a href="http://jekyllthemes.org/themes/dark-poole/">Dark Poole</a>.
  </p>
  <p>
    Hosting is done by my own dedicated server, which also hosts a few other fun purposes. TLS certificates are done by <a href="https://letsencrypt.org/">Let's Encrypt</a>, and domain management by <a href="https://www.blacknight.com/">Blacknight</a>.
  </p>
  <p>
    While the site is in its simplest possible form, and before I start overcomplicating things, there's a few improvements to be made:
      <ul>
        <li>Get an 88x31 button created<s>, and new favicon icon</s></li>
        <li>Expand the home page to have a few more links to projects</li>
        <li>Create a basic webring</li>
        <li><s>Create a deploy script to automate the actions of Jekyll building, testing nginx, then reloading nginx via systemctl</s></li>
        <li><s>Build an easy and reliable way of editing/creating from my various machines. Currently I'm using Putty to SSH into the server, then using Nano to create and edit files... it's not fantastic</s>Put VS Code onto my main machine, it's alright, Putty does the job for the simple work, couldn't be arsed doing anything grander than that</li>
        <li><s>Link in the subdomain for the seedbox, for no reason other than showing off</s></li>
        <li><s>Add an icon of a little cat paw when hovering over the navbar :3</s> Already close to giving up on this one, it's a pain in the ass that I don't fully understand yet</li>
      </ul>
  </p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[At time of writing, this site has a basic home page, navbar, Blog Archive, and About page all typed up. It's been created via Jekyll as a static site generator, and the theme is a lightly modified version of Dark Poole. Hosting is done by my own dedicated server, which also hosts a few other fun purposes. TLS certificates are done by Let's Encrypt, and domain management by Blacknight. While the site is in its simplest possible form, and before I start overcomplicating things, there's a few improvements to be made: Get an 88x31 button created, and new favicon icon Expand the home page to have a few more links to projects Create a basic webring Create a deploy script to automate the actions of Jekyll building, testing nginx, then reloading nginx via systemctl Build an easy and reliable way of editing/creating from my various machines. Currently I'm using Putty to SSH into the server, then using Nano to create and edit files... it's not fantasticPut VS Code onto my main machine, it's alright, Putty does the job for the simple work, couldn't be arsed doing anything grander than that Link in the subdomain for the seedbox, for no reason other than showing off Add an icon of a little cat paw when hovering over the navbar :3 Already close to giving up on this one, it's a pain in the ass that I don't fully understand yet]]></summary></entry></feed>