<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-07-01T23:57:26+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/atom.xml</id><title type="html">Sandy’s Palace</title><subtitle>Rosa&apos;s gay little website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Muffin</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/01/Muffin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Muffin" /><published>2025-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/01/Muffin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/01/Muffin.html"><![CDATA[<div>
  <p>
    Muffin is a stupid little bastard boy with nothing in between his ears but chaos. He is dearly beloved and I will raze towns to the ground for his entertainment.<br /><br />

    Like Sandy, he's a rescue cat from North Kerry. We suspect they're cousins: their family tree more closely resembles a hedge. He was rescued along with his brother Nova, who happily subjugated Muffin during their weeks together.<br /><br />

    Until 8 weeks old he stayed with my friends who rescued him, fawned over by 2-3 dogs, attacked on the regular by 2 cats, and ignored by the other cat. A well-balanced upbringing to ensure that he'd want to burn everything to the ground in the future.<br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/muffin-1.jpeg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Nova (top) and Muffin (bottom) in their natural state</figcaption>
    </figure>

    To give him credit, he was an incredibly fun kitty who was full of beans 100% of the time, as he should be. Permanently wide-eyed and attacked everything on sight. Especially feet. <br /><br />
    
    Sandy never took to him as well as Chili though. The lack of playfighting really was telling. Even now, he's never really bonded with him particularly well. They do hang out and look after each other a bit though which is nice.<br /><br />

    One of his best qualities is his responsiveness. He will adapt to everything you say and do, and he's super clear on what he's feeling (hint: there's two brain cells and only one isn't thinking about food). His tail is basically a mobile exclamation mark. <br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/muffin-2.jpeg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">&gt;:3</figcaption>
    </figure>

    Around 6 months old, the energy wasn't abating in the slightest. At this point we realised we had a problem on our hands. Muffin was a 24/7 terminator, eternally aiming to kill flies, toes, bits of dust in the air, his own tail, any type of reflection, swaying grass, still shadows, dry food, sparks that came out of the fireplace...<br /><br />

    This all came to a head when he was around 9 months old. He was at his holiday home (ie. my parents') in Kerry for a weekend. We're all chilling in the sitting room, when he comes thundering in using only three legs. He put absolutely no weight on it, and would launch away from us if we approached. The last time this happened, a kitty x-ray revealed it was only a sprain, but this time it looked far worse.<br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/muffin-4.jpeg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Consequences of being Muffie</figcaption>
    </figure>

    A week later, the vet had confirmed that Stupid Bastard Idiot Boy had broken his tibia in three places. Most likely from jumping from too high a height, a sin he had committed before and learned nothing from.<br /><br />

    After a few days in the vets and a small fee of ONE THOUSAND FIVE HUNDRED EURO YOU FLUFFY DIPSHIT, Muffin returned to us with an array of splints on his leg, much less fur than before, and a shame cone he refused to wear for more than two seconds. The vet condemned him to four weeks in a cage, with a further two weeks indoors, before he could go outside again. Hell ensued.<br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/muffin-5.jpeg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">:/</figcaption>
    </figure>

    Muffin may have returned to the outdoors a little sooner than 6 weeks. I may have murdered him otherwise.<br /><br />

    After his recovery, he's become even more of a demon tyrant. He has found and executed a local resistance band of mice/voles, and has since turned his attention to the murder of fat birds. The line had been overstepped when he caught and released a garden bird into the house, then proceeded to de-feather the poor bastard. He's more of an indoor boy now.<br /><br />

    Muffin had his first birthday very recently. I have no idea how many more he'll live at this rate, but he finds a way of thriving even when everyone is desperate to stop him. Frankly it makes him worse :3

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/muffin-6.jpeg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Zonked by gay beams every day of his life, he never stood a chance</figcaption>
    </figure>
  </p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Muffin is a stupid little bastard boy with nothing in between his ears but chaos. He is dearly beloved and I will raze towns to the ground for his entertainment.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sandy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/01/Sandy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sandy" /><published>2025-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/01/Sandy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/01/Sandy.html"><![CDATA[<div>
  <p>
    Sandy is the oldest soul in a fluffy young vessel, living a life that I could only dream of. Also a bit of a weirdo. My weirdo.<br /><br />

    He was rescued in North Kerry, his mother having been run over by a car and 4 of his siblings being lost in the days following. Extracted at only 1-2 weeks old, he was nyoomed alongside his brother Astra to Cork, where he's been thrown straight into a life of being fawned over ever since.<br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/sandy-1.jpeg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Big Sandy doesn't want you to know this, but</figcaption>
    </figure>

    In hindsight, he was split up from Astra too early, at 6-8 weeks old. His rescuer had decided I badly needed some company in my then-current state, and he was probably right.<br /><br />

    Sandy spent his first 6 months with me in a tiny flat, plus a tiny concrete square about 1m² being the closest thing either of us had to a garden. He would spend about 16 hours a day napping on a little window bed I had mounted to some glass facing the main road, then when he couldn't take any more naps, he'd thump down to the ground and trot up to me squawking for attention. It was a nice little routine no matter how small it was.<br /><br />

    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/sandy-2.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">First few days in our flat together</figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video><br /><br />

    There's a picture of me that will never see the light of day. I'm in bed looking like absolute shit, to the extent that I'm almost unrecognisable to myself now. Sandy is lying on my chest, face smushed up against my chin, paw wrapped around my shoulder. He did that every morning when I couldn't get out of bed. I think about it a lot. If I ever got the chance to ask him about it, he'd probably just brush it off and claim he had nothing better to do, but I know the truth :3<br /><br />

    I would attempt to bring him on little car drives for enrichment, and some ill-advised walks on a lead around business parks at night where I almost lost him. It was enough to keep him reasonably entertained for a while, but he needed more.<br /><br />

    When I was dating my then-partner, I would occasionally try to bring Sandy over to meet her kitties on a cat date of sorts. He hated them beyond belief.<br /><br />

    We went on frequent weekend trips to my family, and he hated the cage so much that I let him wrap around my neck in the driver's seat. Would not recommend, but it was very funny for the year that I did it.<br /><br />

    I got my second cat<a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/05/25/Chili.html">Chili</a> as a treat for Sandy, and also some extra motivation for me to keep pushing and get them a better home. The two of them adored each other, and quickly outgrew that tiny place. He's never been the same after she left.<br /><br />

    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/sandy-3.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Sniffy Inspection Squad having a chill day in their new pre-renovation garden... which they significantly preferred</figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>

    I moved into my new home for them first and foremost. I didn't really need a garden otherwise. Thankfully they loved it, and even forgave me for the stress of moving... in time.<br /><br />

    Sandy has been, with no exeption on any day, a fluffy little delight. Very strange though. He's easily spooked, and seems constantly low-key stressed. He strikes me as the type of cat we could lose to the silliest little thing, even as cautious as he normally is.<br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/sandy-4.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">His signature comfy trademark</figcaption>
    </figure>

    What's great is his very clear preferences: the precise positioning of his food bowl, the need for a constant supply of dry food and special top-ups of wet, a constant desire for two Chilling Spots that he can move between at will, and his loving of antisocial loafing. Extremely autistic even as cats go.<br /><br />

    He will be three years old this summer, and he already acts like he's thirty. Fluffy bastard took one look at me in 2022 and decided on an early retirement &lt;3<br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/sandy-5.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">&lt;3&gt;</figcaption>
    </figure>
  </p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sandy is the oldest soul in a fluffy young vessel, living a life that I could only dream of. Also a bit of a weirdo. My weirdo.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quiet Places</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/30/Quiet-Places.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quiet Places" /><published>2025-06-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-06-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/30/Quiet-Places</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/30/Quiet-Places.html"><![CDATA[<div>
  <p>
    Step out of Tottenham Court Road Tube station, south exit. Above you is an atrociously out-of-place oversized apartment block, all around you is the chaotic intersection of Charing Cross Road, Oxford Street, Tottenham Court Road, and the A40. Hundreds of people individually raised for decades to serve the noble purpose of launching themselves in front of you with every step you take.<br /><br />

    Look left and slip through the southeast street into a newly purpose-built plaza that cost millions and serves nobody. Ignore the soulless food spots and attempt to cross the A40 - at least three buses will attempt to mow you down here.<br /><br />

    When the queue for Kanada-Ya appears in the distance, look right and there's a tiny entranceway to an alley you'd never otherwise notice.<br /><br />

    Keep going, and in 10 seconds all of the above becomes meaningless.<br /><br />

    I'm enamoured by hidden spots in city centres that totally nullify the chaos around them. The above example is St Giles in the Fields, a 900+ year-old Anglican church and garden that has preserved its sanity amongst the chaos in every direction around it. Outside of 6am when the campanologists go wild, there's no noise, no advertisements, absolutely nothing to suggest you're in a concrete jungle that becomes more hostile with every passing year.<br /><br />

    Plus, if you've truly made it in life, you can rent out the <a href="https://www.thevestryhouse.org/_files/ugd/fe99f5_145162aa150842e7a620cb4907a1c025.pdf">Vestry House</a> for the fanciest-looking dinner of your life with up to 11 other cool people. I will report back on this when I can.<br /><br />

    In Dublin, the best one I've found is the Garden of Remembrance. A cute spot that nobody knows about, just 2 minutes' walk north of O'Connell Street, possibly the shittiest main street of any city I've ever witnessed. The Garden is nice though. Pads the noise beautifully.<br /><br />

    In New York, it's at the end of Greenwich Avenue, the diagonal street that everyone mistakes on a map for Broadway. You buy all your cool stuff at Greenwich Village, then go northwest to Jackson Square to escape it all. Unfortunately this is where I found out via a homeless man that Donald Trump was just elected for the second time, so it loses a point for this.<br /><br />

    Where I currently live though? I'm less sure. The only public park in the city centre is under reconstruction, and will emerge with more concrete and less grass than ever before.<br /><br /> 
    
    There's a park 10 minutes away from the centre with a Hebrew-inspired name, ducking away from a local intersection designed and built by lunatics, but has little else going for it.<br /><br />

    I don't know where I'm going with this. Short of some overdue corporate terrorism, I don't know how we can create a convenient block of green space in our city. But I would dearly like to try.<br /><br />
  </p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Step out of Tottenham Court Road Tube station, south exit. Above you is an atrociously out-of-place oversized apartment block, all around you is the chaotic intersection of Charing Cross Road, Oxford Street, Tottenham Court Road, and the A40. Hundreds of people individually raised for decades to serve the noble purpose of launching themselves in front of you with every step you take.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Comments!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/25/Comments!.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Comments!" /><published>2025-06-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-06-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/25/Comments!</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/25/Comments!.html"><![CDATA[<div>
  <p>
    I'm pleased to announce that this gay little website has a comment section now!<br /><br />

    Big thanks to Caoimhe (no not me the other one, not Other Caoimhe I mean the original one) for hosting a <a href="https://comentario.app/">Commentario</a> instance that could handle adding Sandy's Palace as well.<br /><br />

    I'd looked into comment sections before, but couldn't get my existing servers to share a seedbox domain and a website/comments domain consistently - which is why I outsourced the website portion of things to GitHub Pages.<br /><br />

    Comments will be enabled for most pages apart from when they're not 👍<br /><br />

    Also my profile name is 'Caoimhe M' as I was not the first person to hold this mantle. This may get more complicated once I convince Caoimhe B to join the shitposting fray, we shall see...
  </p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm pleased to announce that this gay little website has a comment section now!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Test Recovery Please Ignore</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/23/Test-Recovery-Please-Ignore.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test Recovery Please Ignore" /><published>2025-06-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/23/Test-Recovery-Please-Ignore</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/23/Test-Recovery-Please-Ignore.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>

<b>Content warning: Abuse, PTSD &amp; Physiological effects of PTSD</b><br /><br />

A friend asked me recently to outline potential triggers for me. She was thinking of visual, auditory, or tactile stimuli. Anything that might cause a flashback or panic response. <br /><br />

Even after responding I know my words were lacking and took too long. The thoughts still only exist in a incomprehensible format, squashed into the back of my brain in the hopes that they'd rot.<br /><br />

--- <br /><br />

I was reading We Know The Devil recently. After Heaven Will Be Mine, I knew I'd be in for a good time; a short and sweet VN that would leave a lot resting on the mind. Of course, it did. <br /><br />

Each of the three main characters runs the risk of being isolated as the story takes hold. Each time you choose two of the three to interact, the third gets left behind. Saving a scenario where you tactically keep all three in equal contact, one of them is left exposed to their fears made manifest.<br /><br />

Second playthrough, I see Jupiter covered in blood, seeped into her hair and body. One of her myriad hands is gently cupping her chin. Another grips her from behind. Another holds a separate hand, reaching from impossible angles. It's only given a sparse few lines of text. I read through it all without a second thought.<br /><br />

Lying in bed afterwards, the imagery doesn't let go. I grab my Steam Deck and speed through through the entire thing again. This time I stare at it until my eyes hurt. Then stare at it until my face hurts, then my limbs, then my thoughts, then my thoughts, then my thoughts.<br /><br />

Jupiter's history is never quite said out loud. There might be an association, a hint that something has made her what she is, but you will never receive confirmation or closure. She tries, and fails, to create a combination of words that make sense. <br /><br />

There are no perfect descriptors, no perfect metaphors, but this one worked for me. WKTD achieved in 30 seconds what I failed to do for years. I didn't sleep for days after that. <br /><br />

---<br /><br />

In the medical world, there is this fundamental disconnect between practitioner and patient. The latter is always fighting to reach through to the former, to convince them that their experiences are real and worthy of more than brief, cursory attention. I've never once bridged this gap in a way that matters. <br /><br />

My mother and I used to look into the root cause of my seizures. The trail went cold after MRIs turned up ok - the desire to investigate them further disappeared once they couldn't tie back to symptoms identifiable in a book. When asked whether they could be brought on by other stresses, the neurologist folder her arms and stared at me in silence until I left.<br /><br />

It's so brushed aside that a consistent term still doesn't exist. The most modern version - functional seizures - drifts in between a mental and neurological space. To the extent that most medical professionals simply refer you back to the other category rather than think about it too hard.<br /><br />

Functional seizures can trigger based on a variety of stressors that I don't fully understand. Though I can identify the cascade of effects: from when the senses become overloaded, to when the body gives up, to when I'm on 5% of brainpower, fighting to ignore the tsunami of sensory signals from every direction, and just faintly aware that my tongue is stuck in my throat.<br /><br />

Tellingly, they most frequently happen when I'm on my own.<br /><br />

From a sensory perspective, the only thing that makes sense is that it doesn't make sense. All you can see is black but not quite black, yet the brightest thing you've ever seen. All you can hear is an advertisement for tinnitus. You'll taste something metallic and inorganic. You can feel the nerves in your limbs but not what they touch. <br /><br />

They were much easier to suppress when I didn't think about things very hard. Unfortunately I now care about my life, and my hormonal balance lets me actually feel emotion. Which has once again exposed this stupid bastard of a thing. <br /><br />

Things are better though. I can identify the slide towards a seizure, the 2-second warning before I hit the floor, and post-collapse recuperation. Two out of these three primarily involve Lucozade Sport, but if it works it works. <br /><br />

---<br /><br />

The wonders of modern medicine have left me to work on this myself. What seems like the biggest disconnect is a lack of easily-treatable symptoms. Sure you passed out from thinking about sharp things too much, but have you repeated it several times in a controlled environment? No? What a shame.

If the knife doesn't leave a visible mark, they don't seem to be too fussed about it. So I get to bother you lot about it instead :3<br /><br />

I am back to staring at a list of potential triggers. It's embarrassingly short. But writing one makes the next one easier. Some day they may come naturally. 
</p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Little Joys, Volume 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/16/Little-Joys-Vol-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Little Joys, Volume 1" /><published>2025-06-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-06-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/16/Little-Joys-Vol-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/16/Little-Joys-Vol-1.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
    This is a silly little thing that popped into my head today. I would like to write about the small things that give me far more enjoyment than they should.<br /><br />
    
    Similarly, the act of writing about it would give me a badly needed positivity push. The other thoughts I would put words to were worse; this is preferable for everyone involved.<br /><br />

    ---<br /><br />

    This week I was able to convert a friend-of-a-friend into a friend. Being in newfound proximity to so many cool people is one of my favourite blessings that has ever happened to me.<br /><br />

    Among some trinkets and cool things she brought over were these Danish liquorice sweets - one of them standard, one of them pre-salted. I nabbed the pre-salted ones.<br /><br />

    I haven't had liquorice since I was a kid, didn't particularly like it then, found it too strong. They somehow avoided me for twenty-ish years. So I thought it'd be a neat opportunity to try them out in a new context.<br /><br />

    I made the dire mistake of chewing into the first few I tried - do not do this. Suck for at least 30 seconds. Insert a joke of your choice here.<br /><br />
    
    They are utterly bizarre. Not quite tasting like liquorice that I've ever had before, nor liquorice that's had salt added into it. Another, possibly more horrifying, thing. Still unsure.<br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/gajol-1.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">This has earned its place in the cool gift collection</figcaption>
    </figure>

    Regardless, a cool little thing that I try out every day, and discover a different aspect to it every time.<br /><br />

    (Some research surfaced that the German language version of these treats are not allowed to be given to children, which also made me laugh.)<br /><br />

    ---<br /><br />

    I played Deltarune Chapters 3 and 4 last week and this week. The bar was high, but it was almost certainly always going to be great.<br /><br />

    Naturally, Toby served us up another couple of blinders. Chapter 3 is good fun, though not quite hitting the peaks of Chapter 2 - Queen was always going to be unbeatable. Chapter 4 throws us into the proper story of Deltarune, but reserves time to fuck around with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pZNO0FmyZ0U">delightful boss fights</a>.<br /><br />

    Fun new fact - I now hum this theme when enjoying bothering someone :3 <br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/deltarune.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">This happened organically and made me laugh far more than it should have</figcaption>
    </figure>

    ---<br /><br />

    I'm enjoying and appreciating physical contact with people for the first time in my life. Very new and very heartfelt.<br /><br /> 

    ---<br /><br />

    Muffin had his first birthday last week. I still want to do a huge page on this site for him, and another for Sandy. The little bastards deserve them :3<br /><br />

    ---<br /><br />

    <a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/03/09/Say-Hi-To-Takumi-The-Toyota-GT86.html">Takumi</a> gets a great audience from some kids I pass on the street.<br /><br />

    Passing some kids just leaving school, one of them belts out a "REV IT!!!!!" and I'm obliged to give Takumi maximum beans. Seeing him cheer in my rear view mirror made me laugh for a good week.<br /><br />

    Another kid walked past my driveway as I was letting Takumi idle on high, and I see him run over to his dad, then back to me, giving me a little hand signal to rev it. How could I not?<br /><br />

<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>

</p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a silly little thing that popped into my head today. I would like to write about the small things that give me far more enjoyment than they should. Similarly, the act of writing about it would give me a badly needed positivity push. The other thoughts I would put words to were worse; this is preferable for everyone involved.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Touch</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/01/Touch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Touch" /><published>2025-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/01/Touch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/01/Touch.html"><![CDATA[<div>
    <p>
        <p class="bolded">Content warning: Abuse</p>
    </p>
    <p>
    I wish I were mute.<br /><br />
    There is no sequence of words that make sense. Something fundamental sits in between me and every other person, something that twists every sentence into something I don't fully understand.<br /> <br />
    You can fight it, of course. Play the words out a hundred times in your head, and watch them change slightly every time. Wait for the perfect moment to say it, only for it to never arrive. Get the thoughts out, and they never land. <br /><br />
    Or, you can sit in silence, and watch the dread grow with every passing minute. It all goes the same way. <br /><br />
    You can lie with words. Most combinations of them will work. Say anything to me, and I'd probably believe it. <br /><br />
    There's plenty of other ways to lie as well. I can't read your expression, or hear your tone. Do things in total opposition to each other, and watch me struggle to tell the difference. <br /><br />
    The only honest sense is touch. Grab me by the leg, throw me to the floor, show me what you think I'm worth. <br /><br />
    The only honest sense is touch. Pin me to the wall, I cannot avoid you now. <br /><br />
    The only honest sense is touch. Stick that knife in my face, see what I can do about it. <br /><br />
    The only honest sense is touch. Show me that you love me, I don't care how. <br /><br />
    I'm enamoured with the thought of a hand for every type of touch. It's not a new wonder, but fresh in the mind once again. There is unavoidable truth in it, painful or joyful as each one might be. <br /><br />
    Hit me, I hit you back. Hold me, I hold you back. Don't touch me, or do. We will finally be even, no matter what. <br /><br />
    I wish I were mute. My only greater wish is that you are, too.  <br /><br />
    </p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Content warning: Abuse I wish I were mute. There is no sequence of words that make sense. Something fundamental sits in between me and every other person, something that twists every sentence into something I don't fully understand. You can fight it, of course. Play the words out a hundred times in your head, and watch them change slightly every time. Wait for the perfect moment to say it, only for it to never arrive. Get the thoughts out, and they never land. Or, you can sit in silence, and watch the dread grow with every passing minute. It all goes the same way. You can lie with words. Most combinations of them will work. Say anything to me, and I'd probably believe it. There's plenty of other ways to lie as well. I can't read your expression, or hear your tone. Do things in total opposition to each other, and watch me struggle to tell the difference. The only honest sense is touch. Grab me by the leg, throw me to the floor, show me what you think I'm worth. The only honest sense is touch. Pin me to the wall, I cannot avoid you now. The only honest sense is touch. Stick that knife in my face, see what I can do about it. The only honest sense is touch. Show me that you love me, I don't care how. I'm enamoured with the thought of a hand for every type of touch. It's not a new wonder, but fresh in the mind once again. There is unavoidable truth in it, painful or joyful as each one might be. Hit me, I hit you back. Hold me, I hold you back. Don't touch me, or do. We will finally be even, no matter what. I wish I were mute. My only greater wish is that you are, too.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What I’m Reading, Volume 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/27/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I’m Reading, Volume 2" /><published>2025-05-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-05-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/27/What-I&apos;m-Reading-Vol-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/27/What-I&apos;m-Reading-Vol-2.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
    This is a little bit close to <a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/05/11/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-1.html">Volume 1</a>, but it's been a shit few weeks and I'm getting worse by the day.
</p>

<p><h1>Serious Reads</h1></p>

<h2>The first prototype of the MingKwai Chinese typewriter has been rediscovered</h2>

Spread across three links below, this is the story of the MingKwai, a revolutionary typewriter that was radically ahead of its time.<br /><br />

<a href="https://news.stanford.edu/stories/2025/05/mingkwai-chinese-typewriter-prototype-stanford-libraries">Here is the article talking about how the first ever prototype model has just been found:</a>

<blockquote>Lin invented a machine that altered the very act of mechanical inscription by transforming inscription into a process of searching,” Mullaney said. “The MingKwai Chinese typewriter combined ‘search’ and ‘writing’ for arguably the first time in history.</blockquote><br />

Next up, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WVPFU3TK9fU">a video of the prototype itself.</a><br /><br />

Third, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yNoWMaOyWHY">an in-depth video explaining how it functions.</a>The machine translation of this video is pretty solid, but even just the video has some useful animations to explain how the typewriter's search mechanics work.<br />

<h2><a href="https://medium.com/@brentcsutoras/the-em-dash-dilemma-how-a-punctuation-mark-became-ais-stubborn-signature-684fbcc9f559">The Em Dash Dilemma: How a Punctuation Mark Became AI’s Stubborn Signature</a></h2>

<blockquote>And now? Humans are ditching em dashes, not because they don’t like them, but because they’re terrified their writing will look fake. One commenter on Hacker News even called it out directly, saying ‘the em dash is now a GPT-ism and is not advisable unless you want people to think your writing is the output of a LLM.</blockquote><br />

Not 100% accurate on the finer details of how LLMs are constructed, but ultimately the ripple effect is real.<br />

<h2><a href="https://oxfordamerican.org/oa-now/the-alabama-landline-that-keeps-ringing">The Alabama Landline That Keeps Ringing</a></h2>

<blockquote>About 13 million people in the US and 2.6 billion people globally don’t use the internet, whether for reasons of availability, desire, cost, or religion. Some may have it but don’t feel confident using it. To their callers, who dial from all over the world, these students are the internet. And lucky for callers, these students are remarkably non-judgmental when it comes to the questions they’re asked.</blockquote>

<p><h1>Light Reads</h1></p>

<h2><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FV36QPB0pew">A bizarre Evangelion Horse Racing advertisement from the 1990s</a></h2>
Neon Genesis Evangelion if it made far more sense.

<h2><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c1ldnedvde9o">Case quacked: Flying duck caught by Swiss speed camera is repeat offender</a></h2>
Partially here for the funny title, and mostly because it's just funny.<br /><br />

And finally, because it makes me laugh every single time I think about it. Every time you wonder if you're just pretending, that you're not enough, that you don't deserve success, just remember: the Ferrari Formula 1 team continues to pay its radio engineers 6-digit figures.<br /><br />

<video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
<source src="/assets/videos/blog/leclerc.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
</video>
<br /><br />
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a little bit close to Volume 1, but it's been a shit few weeks and I'm getting worse by the day.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Heaven Will be Mine</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/Heaven-Will-Be-Mine.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Heaven Will be Mine" /><published>2025-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/Heaven-Will-Be-Mine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/Heaven-Will-Be-Mine.html"><![CDATA[<p class="bolded">I'm of the opinion that a properly good piece of media, at least one that doesn't rely on "twists", cannot be spoiled in a meaningful way. If you disagree, avoid this post until after you read HWBM. Which you will.</p>
<p><br /></p>

<div>
<blockquote>We love these places anyway. They're becoming more and more like home. All we need are more of us.<br /><br />And they come, descending in waves, trying to take us back. We beat them back every time, and sometimes one or two look around, and decide "I'd rather stay here." And then there's more of us.<br /><br />Sometimes they succeed, and take one of us back home. That's just as fine with us. We should go where we wish, live as we wish, and if our sisters get taken home, they bring a small part of us back to the Earth. That can't go unchanged.</blockquote><br />

My brain has been fundamentally rewired again. It happens on select occasions, when the right piece of media hits me at the right time, and I engage with it in the right mindset.<br /><br />

Heaven Will Be Mine is short and sweet. A full playthough is roughly five hours. Within that time, it packs a narrative of the trans struggle for identity and recognition, the search for meaning in a perpetually hostile world, the never-ending quest of humans' self-discovery and exploration, and of course cool mechs beating each other up.<br /><br />

Gameplay is delivered in the typical visual novel format, with choices along the way deciding your ultimate faction alignment, and what girls you get to make out with. <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1579698535">Here's how to do that by the way.</a><br /><br />

You play across three main characters, each fulfilling various archetypes and personalities. Broadly, I enjoyed all three characters, but felt there was scope to expand and elaborate on their thoughts and feelings. Like the over-arching story itself, much is left up to the reader to decide.<br /><br />

Luna-Terra, the ace pilot, is the most "tired" of the three. Fighting through struggles without the self-respect to meaningfully change anything.<br /><br />

Pluto, a human that's gone beyond humanity. Absurdly powerful in her new form, but rejects the image of overwhelming strength that others assume of her.<br /><br />

And Saturn; unconventional, unpredictable, aggressively flirty. L33t h4xor extraordinaire.<br /><br />

I resonate strongly with Luna-Terra, and am looking respectfully at Saturn. Make of that what you will.<br /><br />

<blockquote> Through gravity, humans are ruled by each other. Anti-matter, anti-gravity, anti-culture; all exists as a resistive force to this gravity. The refusal of humanity to accept these parts of itself cause its own undoing. When we let our children develop in the lightness of space, they chose their bodies, genders, souls, hearts of their own volition. They became human in the ways they wished to become human.</blockquote><br />

The fight against Gravity is relentless. The pull of the Earth is not just measured in F = G(m1m2)/R2. It's measured in the mass of human history, the difficulty in breaking free of "normal", and the violence that follows resistance.<br /><br />

This was one of the most interesting metaphors in the game. In the context of gravity, one could choose stand on the surface of planet Earth, and cease resistance. Alternatively you could orbit the planet, still caught in its field, but with some measure of distance. To truly break free of it, how far would you need to go?<br /><br />

Creation of one's own gravity field, or connecting to a totally different one, can be seen as the liberation that these characters crave. I won't say more here, but the game does broach this in interesting ways.<br /><br />

<blockquote> In time, the shape conforms to the human inside. This in part confirms the specific theory: the human part isn't the ear, but the hole in the lobes for your earrings, lipstick is real, lips are not, and we see humanity defined in its gravitational output.</blockquote><br />

Ship-selves are another crucial aspect to this. They cannot survive on the surface of planet Earth. They are with form, but contort to replicate the user over time. Luna-Terra's is untouchable, Saturn's is bold and brave, Pluto's is warm and all-encompassing.<br /><br />

It is through Ship-selves that the pilots can fight against gravity, fight against each other, fight against the world. They are constructed in such an intricate way that they cannot kill another. There is a joy in it that cannot be found or replicated anywhere else, lonely as it may be.

<blockquote>No one should die in space. No one should die, period. No one has to die, because Ship-Self combat is shimmering missiles of light, cosmic explosions, electricity that sears through the soul. Blade sciences impossible for a human to produce! Dances of combat without end!<br />A fight against ideas with toys. Humans would never show that sort of compassion to each other.</blockquote>

The true capabilities of the Ship-selves are very ambiguous, more created as a tool of interpretation, as opposed to acting as the centrepiece of the VN.<br />

<p><blockquote>&gt;I worry about what we would be like if that hadn't happened. For me or for you. [...] Would it have taken us even longer? I already feel like I became a person too old. Would we spend our lives without ever-<br /><br />&gt;We'd have found another way. Somehow. In Earth or space, no one is ever born whole. We got there eventually, didn't we?<br /><br />&gt;Ha, I think so too. So I would like to believe that no matter what, we could live and be happy?<br />&gt;Even in mortal bodies, on our boring, awful home.<br />&gt;I mean, they can't undo what we have done.<br />&gt;When they take us back, they will have to make us a part of them.</blockquote></p>

There is pain and reassurance in seeing these thoughts said out loud. Just living can often be sufficient - both as an individual and in the cultures that we create.<br /><br />

You can interpret a relentless sadness from any of the situations put forward in HWBM. To live free of Earth's gravity means losing and sacrificing aspects of us, not because they are necessarily incompatible with us, but because the rest of humanity refuses to allow it to exist.<br /><br />

Yet there is joy in fighting for ourselves and each other, and this persists beyond the endless struggle.<br /><br />

---<br /><br />

Heaven Will Be Mine: <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/836450/Heaven_Will_Be_Mine/">Steam</a> | <a href="https://pillowfight.itch.io/heaven-will-be-mine">Itch</a><br /><br />

<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>

<div>
</div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm of the opinion that a properly good piece of media, at least one that doesn't rely on "twists", cannot be spoiled in a meaningful way. If you disagree, avoid this post until after you read HWBM. Which you will.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chili</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/25/Chili.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chili" /><published>2025-05-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-05-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/25/Chili</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/25/Chili.html"><![CDATA[<div>
    <p>
        Today would have been my cat Chili's second birthday.
    </p>
    <p>
        She was found by a then-partner of mine, miles out of the city, barely able to walk. Her mother was nearby, but seemingly wasn't able to help her.
    </p>
    <p>
        <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/chili-1.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
        <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">First pic ever taken of Chili</figcaption>
        </figure>
    </p>
    <p>
        She had multiple infections, most predominantly in the eyes. It took weeks of treatment before she was able to see properly, and I suspect they never fully healed.
    </p>
    <p>
        She was a wild cat since birth, and acted like it. She was troublesome but clingy at the same time. Litter training her was the most difficult of any cat, as it was tough to dissuade her from going whenever she needed.
    </p>
    <p>
        Interestingly, the vet who performed her surgeries described her as "borderline intersex". During development, the positioning of body parts suggested it was anticipating male organs, but she got female ones instead. The vet described this using very helpful diagrams.
    </p>
    <p>
        Once she cleared the first few weeks, I introduced her to Sandy, my other idiot, who was roughly 1 year old at the time. They bonded faster than any other cats I've seen.
    </p>
    <p>
        <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/chili-2.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
        <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">They would do this wihout any intervention needed, every single day</figcaption>
        </figure>
    </p>
    <p>
        Having two cats was a huge motivator for me to get a more stable roof over my head. The thought of letting down them was more worrying than the thought of disappointing myself.
    </p>
    <p>
        With the typical delays in buying and moving house, Chili was a year old by the time we finally moved. Outside of visits to the family home, she never had any real opportunity of exploring the outdoors in a safe way.
    </p>
    <p>
        <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/chili-3.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
        <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">The only living things to enjoy this couch</figcaption>
        </figure>
    </p>
    <p>
        One of my fondest memories of her is the day of moving - October 30th 2023. The two cats didn't know what to make of everything. The house smelled something bizarre, and they were totally unused to any new environment that wasn't friendly to them. Yet they ran their Sniffy Inspection Squad through every single room to keep me safe :3
    </p>
    <p>
        Currently testing these video players in a live environment, don't mind me :&gt;
    </p>
    <p>
        <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
        <source src="/assets/videos/blog/chili-1.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
        <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
            <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Sniffy Inspection Squad, in your neighbourhood</figcaption>
        </figure>
        </video>
        
    <p>
        The house move was super difficult for many reasons. I was sleeping on a mattress on the floor, that I shifted between the two liveable rooms in the house, whenever I needed to work on the other. Chili would join me every night for the first few weeks.
    </p>
    <p>
        She also took time out to look after Sandy, who wasn't finding the move very enjoyable. On the first night, Sandy saw the miserable-looking mattress that I was hopping on top of, realised he wasn't going back to the flat, and did the closest thing to crying I've ever seen a cat do. Chili was on the case. 
    </p>

    <p>
        <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
        <source src="/assets/videos/blog/chili-2.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
        <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
        <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">:3</figcaption>
        </figure>
        </video>
    <p>
        She loved the outdoors, and took to the area like a natural. The back garden is removed from the local roads, and the area cats have no need to put themselves in danger unless they feel like it. Chili didn't wander much, but she loved the big pine tree my neighbour has.
    </p>
    <p>
        <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/chili-4.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
        <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">They never did forgive me for cutting down the overgrown garden.</figcaption>
        </figure>
    </p>
    <p>
        Chili thoroughly enjoyed her new lifestyle for the next 6 months. It was the ideal setup, two cats that looked after each other, barely fought, and gave each other space when needed.
    </p>
    <p>
        Chili didn't return home one random night. I set up the usual for her: both dry and wet food indoors and outdoors, fresh water bowls, and put some used clothes in the garden to mark her home.
    </p>
    <p>
        She returned the following day, but something was off about her. Despite no visible injuries, she seemed unnerved, shook, or maybe just super curious about something I didn't understand. She ate food happily, but after that was bursting to leave again. She suddenly had no interest in the safe indoors, and only had eyes for whatever was on her mind outside.
    </p>
    <p>
        <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/chili-5.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
        <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">The last photo of Chili</figcaption>
        </figure>
    </p>
    <p>
        I kept her inside for three days, but it fixed nothing. Every time I even glanced at a window or door, she was there by my feet.
    </p>
    <p>
        Eventually she did slip between my feet and escape. She was never a catchable cat, but I decided to trust her anyways. Whatever had caught her attention, I hoped that she'd take care of it and come back. Of course, she didn't.
    </p>
    <p>
        We never did find her. I still hope to this day that she popped into someone else's home, preferred the couch, and decided to stay. No other explanation makes sense or gives hope.
    </p>
    <p>
        So, happy birthday Chili. Your cat yoghurt is waiting for you in the fridge, same as last year.
    </p>
    <script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</p></p></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today would have been my cat Chili's second birthday. She was found by a then-partner of mine, miles out of the city, barely able to walk. Her mother was nearby, but seemingly wasn't able to help her. First pic ever taken of Chili She had multiple infections, most predominantly in the eyes. It took weeks of treatment before she was able to see properly, and I suspect they never fully healed. She was a wild cat since birth, and acted like it. She was troublesome but clingy at the same time. Litter training her was the most difficult of any cat, as it was tough to dissuade her from going whenever she needed. Interestingly, the vet who performed her surgeries described her as "borderline intersex". During development, the positioning of body parts suggested it was anticipating male organs, but she got female ones instead. The vet described this using very helpful diagrams. Once she cleared the first few weeks, I introduced her to Sandy, my other idiot, who was roughly 1 year old at the time. They bonded faster than any other cats I've seen. They would do this wihout any intervention needed, every single day Having two cats was a huge motivator for me to get a more stable roof over my head. The thought of letting down them was more worrying than the thought of disappointing myself. With the typical delays in buying and moving house, Chili was a year old by the time we finally moved. Outside of visits to the family home, she never had any real opportunity of exploring the outdoors in a safe way. The only living things to enjoy this couch One of my fondest memories of her is the day of moving - October 30th 2023. The two cats didn't know what to make of everything. The house smelled something bizarre, and they were totally unused to any new environment that wasn't friendly to them. Yet they ran their Sniffy Inspection Squad through every single room to keep me safe :3 Currently testing these video players in a live environment, don't mind me :&gt; Sniffy Inspection Squad, in your neighbourhood The house move was super difficult for many reasons. I was sleeping on a mattress on the floor, that I shifted between the two liveable rooms in the house, whenever I needed to work on the other. Chili would join me every night for the first few weeks. She also took time out to look after Sandy, who wasn't finding the move very enjoyable. On the first night, Sandy saw the miserable-looking mattress that I was hopping on top of, realised he wasn't going back to the flat, and did the closest thing to crying I've ever seen a cat do. Chili was on the case.]]></summary></entry></feed>