<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-07-09T00:24:34+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/atom.xml</id><title type="html">Sandy’s Palace</title><subtitle>Rosa&apos;s gay little website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A Halfway Halfassed Review of Signalis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/08/A-Halfway-Review-of-Signalis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Halfway Halfassed Review of Signalis" /><published>2025-07-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-07-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/08/A-Halfway-Review-of-Signalis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/08/A-Halfway-Review-of-Signalis.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
    Signalis is stupendously well-reviewed. I'm less convinced, and am writing halfway thoughts on the knowledge there's a 50% chance I won't see the finish.<br /><br />

    Aesthetically born from the era of CRT televisions, analogue error codes, and fifth-generation video game consoles. Narratively created via H.P. Lovecraft, Stanley Kubrick, David Lynch, and plenty more I didn't pick up on.<br /><br />
    
    Visually you will feel very at home here if you're familiar with analogue horror. PS1-era graphics and icons help this along, to the extent that you can see the direct inspiration from specific games - Metal Gear Solid comes to mind for some of the more subtle instances.<br /><br />

    Sound design is quite neat. I'm a big fan of the subtle touch, and there's enough audio cues to nudge the player into uncertainty without coming off as in-your-face.<br /><br />

    Mechanics is where the game falls down quite hard. It pulls far too enthusiastically from the old Resident Evil games - you get a key that forces you to backtack two levels, which lets you unlock a safe that gives you a key, which makes you traverse one floor in order to open a door leading to a desk that contains a key, which opens a lift on a different floor that leads to... another key. Utterly obnoxious.<br /><br />

    Heavily limiting the player's inventory would be fine, except for the occasional room contiaining 2-3 key items, forcing you to backtrack multiple floors to the single storage point available to you.<br /><br />

    Puzzles are fine, combat is fine, but the above drags the game to a state where I simply don't care to carry on. The plot is working towards something interesting, but the interest simply isn't there any more. There's nothing wrong with a slightly shorter game.
</p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Signalis is stupendously well-reviewed. I'm less convinced, and am writing halfway thoughts on the knowledge there's a 50% chance I won't see the finish.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blood on the Clocktower</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/08/Blood-On-The-Clocktower.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blood on the Clocktower" /><published>2025-07-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-07-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/08/Blood-On-The-Clocktower</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/08/Blood-On-The-Clocktower.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
    An instant community in a box! How could I say no?<br /><br />
    
    <a href="https://bloodontheclocktower.com/">Blood on the Clocktower</a> is a social deducation game best played in the shaded section of a comfy bar that runs board game nights. I was already suffering from the heat of the upstairs section and the timing was impeccable.<br /><br />

    We had a party of 18, which seemed unmanageable but for the excellent gamemaster who somehow kept on top of every piece of intrigue, truth, lie, and shittalk that was happening. 14 townsfolk, 4 outsiders. I chose outsider due to its handy ability of not tying the player to the game for its entire duration - very handy for someone who likes to step out dramatically and without warning.<br /><br />

    Dennis talked me into playing the Gunslinger. A chaotic role that allowed me to rooty tooty point and shooty one person per night, as long as they voted to execute another player. My strategy for this role revolved around a few core thoughts:<br /><br />
    <ul>
        <li>I had no idea how the intricacies of the game would function</li>
        <li>Chaos is funny when done right</li>
        <li>I could sit back and observe other players, rather than jump straight into accusations that I didn't fully understand</li>
        <li>"???"</li>
        <li>I was sitting at the corner of the circle and can't comprehend shit in large spaces</li>
    </ul>
    Day 1, and another player zooms up to me as soon as the day phase began. He begged me to shoot him, claiming to be the Angel that absolutely should not be executed on pain of instant team failure. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4f7Gh-EABf0">My mind may have been elsewhere during this very interesting conundrum.</a><br /><br />

    I shot him in the face on Night 1 or 2, can't remember which. Either way, he wasn't playing me, and I wouldn't have known otherwise if he was. Good start.<br /><br />

    Days 2 and 3 are where my masterplan come to fruition. At this point I have little clue what the fuck is going on, Matteo is devising a prosecution statement as long as the entire script of Fate/Stay Night, and there's growing confusion as to who has what roles. Unveiling my grand strategy of Shut The Fuck Up, I refuse to shoot anyone for two nights in a row. This has several key benefits:
    <ul>
        <li>Opting not to shoot someone suspected of being Good, AND someone suspected of being Evil, casts me out of this argument by confusing everyone involved</li>
        <li>Enhances my pretty and mysterious demeanour sitting in the corner teeheeheeing because I have no poker face</li>
        <li>Less is more (a good life strategy in general)</li>
    </ul>
    
    Day 4 proceeds, and the gamemaster nudges us along to speed things up. It's been about 90 minutes, and half the townsfolk are still alive. The discussion that night was lively, plenty of votes put forward on all sides, and there was a growing likelihood that our numbers will be thinned significantly by the next morning.<br /><br />

    Naturally, I take out my gun for the first time in over an hour, and shoot the demon in the face on first attempt. Ending the game in the silliest possible way, and a first according to the gamemaster in his 2-3 years of running it.<br /><br />

    This wouldn't be half as funny except for the fact that, out of the three players I was suspecting, I was wrong about all but one of them. And I picked my target randomly.<br /><br />
    
    Don't tell the other players though. I'm sure they won't find out.<br /><br />

    9/10 great game ye should try it
</p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An instant community in a box! How could I say no? Blood on the Clocktower is a social deducation game best played in the shaded section of a comfy bar that runs board game nights. I was already suffering from the heat of the upstairs section and the timing was impeccable.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What I’m Reading, Volume 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/02/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I’m Reading, Volume 3" /><published>2025-07-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/02/What-I&apos;m-Reading-Vol-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/02/What-I&apos;m-Reading-Vol-3.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
    Previous iterations:<br /><br />
    <ul>
        <li><a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/05/11/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-1.html">Volume 1</a></li>
        <li><a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/05/27/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-2.html">Volume 2</a></li>
    </ul>

<p><h1>Serious Reads</h1></p>

<h2><a href="https://defector.com/seven-days-at-the-bin-store">Seven Days At The Bin Store</a></h2>
<blockquote>Baltimore Avenue runs from the University of Pennsylvania campus in the east, west through a neighborhood that’s a mixture of million-dollar houses, squats-turned-group-houses, and some of the city’s most persistent poverty. For the six-ish years I’ve lived here, I’ve watched a handful of bougie businesses open and quickly fold, leaving behind empty storefronts. Housing prices just go up and up, but the retail strip suggests an uneven gentrification. Those fluctuating fortunes are mirrored in starkly divergent views of whether Amazing Binz is an “amazing store with amazing stuff and amazing prices” (their first Google review) or “a place that sells crap” (a post on West Willy).</blockquote>
A rather American take on the mesmerisingly vast world of fast commerce.<br /><br />

<h2><a href="https://www.comradegallery.com/journal/photo-essay-the-unworldly-photos-of-industrial-waste-pollution-landscapes-in-russia-environmental-policy">The Surreal Landscapes of Industrial Waste in Russia</a></h2>
<blockquote>Photographer Alexander Sukharev set out to document these hidden hazards. As a co-founder of the Kosmaj Project, he spent months traveling across the country, from Moscow to Vladivostok, using a drone to capture the scale of the damage. What began as a planned visit to a few sites soon became an obsession, leading him to seek out these polluted landscapes in nearly every city he passed.</blockquote>
More pictures than words, but still fascinating.<br /><br />

<h2><a href="https://www.danvk.org/2025/04/23/boggle-solved.html">After 20 Years, the Globally Optimal Boggle Board</a></h2>
<blockquote>Using a 192-core c4 on Google Cloud, it took about 5 days to check around 1 million 4x4 board classes (~23,000 CPU hours). This is about $1,200 of compute. That’s a lot, but it’s not a crazy amount. (Fortunately I had a friend in BigTech with CPUs to spare.)<br /><br />

The result was a list of all the Boggle boards (up to symmetry) that score 3500+ points using the ENABLE2K word list. There were 32 of them. Here are the top five:<br />
<ul>
    <li>plsteaiertnrsges (3625 points)</li>
    <li>splseaiertnrsges (3603 points)</li>
    <li>gntseaieplrdsees (3593 points)</li>
    <li>dresenilstapares (3591 points)</li>
    <li>dplcseainrtngies (3591 points)</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

Also I learned a few weeks ago that my family have been using house rules for Boggle for 20 years and I never knew. We were running a restriction of much longer character requirements per word, but the letters didn't need to be in adjacency to each other. Frankly I prefer this because I beat everyone in this variant :3<br /><br />

<h2><a href="https://www.latimes.com/science/story/2025-06-15/l-a-seeks-help-for-a-patient-with-no-name">Strangers in the middle of a city: The John and Jane Does of L.A. General Medical Center</a></h2>
<blockquote>One man hit by a car on Santa Monica Boulevard in January 2017 lived for nearly two years with a traumatic brain injury before dying unidentified in the hospital. As of late 2024, a few Does had been there for more than a year.<br /><br />
If a patient has no identity, L.A. General can’t figure out who insures them. And in the U.S. healthcare system, not having a guarantee of payment is almost worse than not having a name.</blockquote>
I thought a lot about people with dementia who could so easily fall prey to this.<br /><br />

<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/google/2025/05/zero-click-searches-googles-ai-tools-are-the-culmination-of-its-hubris/"> Zero-click searches: Google’s AI tools are the culmination of its hubris </a></h2>
<blockquote>But Google's intentions don't end with AI Overviews. Last week, the company started an expanded public test of so-called "AI Mode," right from the front page. AI Mode doesn't even bother with those blue links. It's a chatbot experience that, at present, tries to answer your query without clearly citing sources inline. (On some occasions, it will mention Reddit or Wikipedia.) On the right side of the screen, Google provides a little box with three sites linked, which you can expand to see more options. To the end user, it's utterly unclear if those are "sources," "recommendations," or "partner deals."<br /><br />

Perhaps more surprisingly, in our testing, not a single AI Mode "sites box" listed a site that ranked on the first page for the same query on a regular search. That is, the links in AI Mode for "best foods to eat for a cold" don't overlap at all with the SERP for the same query in Google Search. In fairness, AI Mode is very new, and its behavior will undoubtedly change. But the direction the company is headed seems clear.</blockquote>
Even DuckDuckGo is not safe, but it's better than whatever the fuck this is.<br /><br />

<h2><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2025/03/27/1113782/scam-compound-meta-facebook-pig-butchering-wechat/">Inside a romance scam compound—and how people get tricked into being there</a></h2>
<blockquote>Compounding all the challenges, however, is the integration of cheap and easy-to-use artificial intelligence into scamming operations. The trafficked individuals we spoke to, who had mostly left the compounds before the widespread adoption of generative AI, said that if targets suggested a video call they would deflect or, as a last resort, play prerecorded video clips. Only one described the use of AI by his company; he says he was paid to record himself saying various sentences in ways that reflected different emotions, for the purposes of feeding the audio into an AI model. Recently, reports have emerged of scammers who have used AI-powered “face swap” and voice-altering products so that they can impersonate their characters more convincingly. “Malicious actors can exploit these models, especially open-source models, to produce content at an unprecedented scale,” says Gabrielle Tran, senior analyst for technology and society at IST. “These models are purposefully being fine-tuned … to serve as convincing humans.” </blockquote>


<p><h1>Light Reads</h1></p>

<h2><a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?direction=prev&amp;oldid=383935943">If on a winter's night a traveler</a></h2>
A timely reminder if you're reading Wikipedia articles at 2am.<br /><br />

<h2><a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/Appendix:Protologisms/Long_words/Titin">Titin</a></h2>
Another light Wikipedia read before bed.<br /><br />

<h2><a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-17/potato-point-emu-population-east-coast-beach/105185358">Shipment of emus that swam to mainland New South Wales now thriving at Potato Point</a></h2>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L2m3aDCmjwo">It's a fuckin emu ya daft cunt</a><br /><br />

<h2><a href="https://uquiz.com/quiz/jyoHiC/which-early-christian-heresy-are-you">Which Early Christian Heresy Are You?</a></h2>
Absolute banger of a quiz that was sent onto me recently. I am Pelagianism apparently!<br /><br />

<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</p></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Previous iterations: Volume 1 Volume 2]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Muffin</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/01/Muffin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Muffin" /><published>2025-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/01/Muffin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/01/Muffin.html"><![CDATA[<div>
  <p>
    Muffin is a stupid little bastard boy with nothing in between his ears but chaos. He is dearly beloved and I will raze towns to the ground for his entertainment.<br /><br />

    Like Sandy, he's a rescue cat from North Kerry. We suspect they're cousins: their family tree more closely resembles a hedge. He was rescued along with his brother Nova, who happily subjugated Muffin during their weeks together.<br /><br />

    Until 8 weeks old he stayed with my friends who rescued him, fawned over by 2-3 dogs, attacked on the regular by 2 cats, and ignored by the other cat. A well-balanced upbringing to ensure that he'd want to burn everything to the ground in the future.<br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/muffin-1.jpeg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Nova (top) and Muffin (bottom) in their natural state</figcaption>
    </figure>

    To give him credit, he was an incredibly fun kitty who was full of beans 100% of the time, as he should be. Permanently wide-eyed and attacked everything on sight. Especially feet. <br /><br />
    
    Sandy never took to him as well as Chili though. The lack of playfighting really was telling. Even now, he's never really bonded with him particularly well. They do hang out and look after each other a bit though which is nice.<br /><br />

    One of his best qualities is his responsiveness. He will adapt to everything you say and do, and he's super clear on what he's feeling (hint: there's two brain cells and only one isn't thinking about food). His tail is basically a mobile exclamation mark. <br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/muffin-2.jpeg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">&gt;:3</figcaption>
    </figure>

    Around 6 months old, the energy wasn't abating in the slightest. At this point we realised we had a problem on our hands. Muffin was a 24/7 terminator, eternally aiming to kill flies, toes, bits of dust in the air, his own tail, any type of reflection, swaying grass, still shadows, dry food, sparks that came out of the fireplace...<br /><br />

    This all came to a head when he was around 9 months old. He was at his holiday home (ie. my parents') in Kerry for a weekend. We're all chilling in the sitting room, when he comes thundering in using only three legs. He put absolutely no weight on it, and would launch away from us if we approached. The last time this happened, a kitty x-ray revealed it was only a sprain, but this time it looked far worse.<br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/muffin-4.jpeg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Consequences of being Muffie</figcaption>
    </figure>

    A week later, the vet had confirmed that Stupid Bastard Idiot Boy had broken his tibia in three places. Most likely from jumping from too high a height, a sin he had committed before and learned nothing from.<br /><br />

    After a few days in the vets and a small fee of ONE THOUSAND FIVE HUNDRED EURO YOU FLUFFY DIPSHIT, Muffin returned to us with an array of splints on his leg, much less fur than before, and a shame cone he refused to wear for more than two seconds. The vet condemned him to four weeks in a cage, with a further two weeks indoors, before he could go outside again. Hell ensued.<br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/muffin-5.jpeg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">:/</figcaption>
    </figure>

    Muffin may have returned to the outdoors a little sooner than 6 weeks. I may have murdered him otherwise.<br /><br />

    After his recovery, he's become even more of a demon tyrant. He has found and executed a local resistance band of mice/voles, and has since turned his attention to the murder of fat birds. The line had been overstepped when he caught and released a garden bird into the house, then proceeded to de-feather the poor bastard. He's more of an indoor boy now.<br /><br />

    Muffin had his first birthday very recently. I have no idea how many more he'll live at this rate, but he finds a way of thriving even when everyone is desperate to stop him. Frankly it makes him worse :3

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/muffin-6.jpeg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Zonked by gay beams every day of his life, he never stood a chance</figcaption>
    </figure>
  </p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Muffin is a stupid little bastard boy with nothing in between his ears but chaos. He is dearly beloved and I will raze towns to the ground for his entertainment.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sandy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/01/Sandy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sandy" /><published>2025-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/01/Sandy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/01/Sandy.html"><![CDATA[<div>
  <p>
    Sandy is the oldest soul in a fluffy young vessel, living a life that I could only dream of. Also a bit of a weirdo. My weirdo.<br /><br />

    He was rescued in North Kerry, his mother having been run over by a car and 4 of his siblings being lost in the days following. Extracted at only 1-2 weeks old, he was nyoomed alongside his brother Astra to Cork, where he's been thrown straight into a life of being fawned over ever since.<br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/sandy-1.jpeg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Big Sandy doesn't want you to know this, but</figcaption>
    </figure>

    In hindsight, he was split up from Astra too early, at 6-8 weeks old. His rescuer had decided I badly needed some company in my then-current state, and he was probably right.<br /><br />

    Sandy spent his first 6 months with me in a tiny flat, plus a tiny concrete square about 1m² being the closest thing either of us had to a garden. He would spend about 16 hours a day napping on a little window bed I had mounted to some glass facing the main road, then when he couldn't take any more naps, he'd thump down to the ground and trot up to me squawking for attention. It was a nice little routine no matter how small it was.<br /><br />

    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/sandy-2.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">First few days in our flat together</figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video><br /><br />

    There's a picture of me that will never see the light of day. I'm in bed looking like absolute shit, to the extent that I'm almost unrecognisable to myself now. Sandy is lying on my chest, face smushed up against my chin, paw wrapped around my shoulder. He did that every morning when I couldn't get out of bed. I think about it a lot. If I ever got the chance to ask him about it, he'd probably just brush it off and claim he had nothing better to do, but I know the truth :3<br /><br />

    I would attempt to bring him on little car drives for enrichment, and some ill-advised walks on a lead around business parks at night where I almost lost him. It was enough to keep him reasonably entertained for a while, but he needed more.<br /><br />

    When I was dating my then-partner, I would occasionally try to bring Sandy over to meet her kitties on a cat date of sorts. He hated them beyond belief.<br /><br />

    We went on frequent weekend trips to my family, and he hated the cage so much that I let him wrap around my neck in the driver's seat. Would not recommend, but it was very funny for the year that I did it.<br /><br />

    I got my second cat<a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/05/25/Chili.html">Chili</a> as a treat for Sandy, and also some extra motivation for me to keep pushing and get them a better home. The two of them adored each other, and quickly outgrew that tiny place. He's never been the same after she left.<br /><br />

    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/sandy-3.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Sniffy Inspection Squad having a chill day in their new pre-renovation garden... which they significantly preferred</figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>

    I moved into my new home for them first and foremost. I didn't really need a garden otherwise. Thankfully they loved it, and even forgave me for the stress of moving... in time.<br /><br />

    Sandy has been, with no exeption on any day, a fluffy little delight. Very strange though. He's easily spooked, and seems constantly low-key stressed. He strikes me as the type of cat we could lose to the silliest little thing, even as cautious as he normally is.<br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/sandy-4.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">His signature comfy trademark</figcaption>
    </figure>

    What's great is his very clear preferences: the precise positioning of his food bowl, the need for a constant supply of dry food and special top-ups of wet, a constant desire for two Chilling Spots that he can move between at will, and his loving of antisocial loafing. Extremely autistic even as cats go.<br /><br />

    He will be three years old this summer, and he already acts like he's thirty. Fluffy bastard took one look at me in 2022 and decided on an early retirement &lt;3<br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/sandy-5.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">&lt;3&gt;</figcaption>
    </figure>
  </p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sandy is the oldest soul in a fluffy young vessel, living a life that I could only dream of. Also a bit of a weirdo. My weirdo.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quiet Places</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/30/Quiet-Places.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quiet Places" /><published>2025-06-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-06-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/30/Quiet-Places</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/30/Quiet-Places.html"><![CDATA[<div>
  <p>
    Step out of Tottenham Court Road Tube station, south exit. Above you is an atrociously out-of-place oversized apartment block, all around you is the chaotic intersection of Charing Cross Road, Oxford Street, Tottenham Court Road, and the A40. Hundreds of people individually raised for decades to serve the noble purpose of launching themselves in front of you with every step you take.<br /><br />

    Look left and slip through the southeast street into a newly purpose-built plaza that cost millions and serves nobody. Ignore the soulless food spots and attempt to cross the A40 - at least three buses will attempt to mow you down here.<br /><br />

    When the queue for Kanada-Ya appears in the distance, look right and there's a tiny entranceway to an alley you'd never otherwise notice.<br /><br />

    Keep going, and in 10 seconds all of the above becomes meaningless.<br /><br />

    I'm enamoured by hidden spots in city centres that totally nullify the chaos around them. The above example is St Giles in the Fields, a 900+ year-old Anglican church and garden that has preserved its sanity amongst the chaos in every direction around it. Outside of 6am when the campanologists go wild, there's no noise, no advertisements, absolutely nothing to suggest you're in a concrete jungle that becomes more hostile with every passing year.<br /><br />

    Plus, if you've truly made it in life, you can rent out the <a href="https://www.thevestryhouse.org/_files/ugd/fe99f5_145162aa150842e7a620cb4907a1c025.pdf">Vestry House</a> for the fanciest-looking dinner of your life with up to 11 other cool people. I will report back on this when I can.<br /><br />

    In Dublin, the best one I've found is the Garden of Remembrance. A cute spot that nobody knows about, just 2 minutes' walk north of O'Connell Street, possibly the shittiest main street of any city I've ever witnessed. The Garden is nice though. Pads the noise beautifully.<br /><br />

    In New York, it's at the end of Greenwich Avenue, the diagonal street that everyone mistakes on a map for Broadway. You buy all your cool stuff at Greenwich Village, then go northwest to Jackson Square to escape it all. Unfortunately this is where I found out via a homeless man that Donald Trump was just elected for the second time, so it loses a point for this.<br /><br />

    Where I currently live though? I'm less sure. The only public park in the city centre is under reconstruction, and will emerge with more concrete and less grass than ever before.<br /><br /> 
    
    There's a park 10 minutes away from the centre with a Hebrew-inspired name, ducking away from a local intersection designed and built by lunatics, but has little else going for it.<br /><br />

    I don't know where I'm going with this. Short of some overdue corporate terrorism, I don't know how we can create a convenient block of green space in our city. But I would dearly like to try.<br /><br />
  </p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Step out of Tottenham Court Road Tube station, south exit. Above you is an atrociously out-of-place oversized apartment block, all around you is the chaotic intersection of Charing Cross Road, Oxford Street, Tottenham Court Road, and the A40. Hundreds of people individually raised for decades to serve the noble purpose of launching themselves in front of you with every step you take.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Comments!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/25/Comments!.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Comments!" /><published>2025-06-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-06-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/25/Comments!</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/25/Comments!.html"><![CDATA[<div>
  <p>
    I'm pleased to announce that this gay little website has a comment section now!<br /><br />

    Big thanks to Caoimhe (no not me the other one, not Other Caoimhe I mean the original one) for hosting a <a href="https://comentario.app/">Commentario</a> instance that could handle adding Sandy's Palace as well.<br /><br />

    I'd looked into comment sections before, but couldn't get my existing servers to share a seedbox domain and a website/comments domain consistently - which is why I outsourced the website portion of things to GitHub Pages.<br /><br />

    Comments will be enabled for most pages apart from when they're not 👍<br /><br />

    Also my profile name is 'Caoimhe M' as I was not the first person to hold this mantle. This may get more complicated once I convince Caoimhe B to join the shitposting fray, we shall see...
  </p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm pleased to announce that this gay little website has a comment section now!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Test Recovery Please Ignore</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/23/Test-Recovery-Please-Ignore.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test Recovery Please Ignore" /><published>2025-06-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/23/Test-Recovery-Please-Ignore</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/23/Test-Recovery-Please-Ignore.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>

<b>Content warning: Abuse, PTSD &amp; Physiological effects of PTSD</b><br /><br />

A friend asked me recently to outline potential triggers for me. She was thinking of visual, auditory, or tactile stimuli. Anything that might cause a flashback or panic response. <br /><br />

Even after responding I know my words were lacking and took too long. The thoughts still only exist in a incomprehensible format, squashed into the back of my brain in the hopes that they'd rot.<br /><br />

--- <br /><br />

I was reading We Know The Devil recently. After Heaven Will Be Mine, I knew I'd be in for a good time; a short and sweet VN that would leave a lot resting on the mind. Of course, it did. <br /><br />

Each of the three main characters runs the risk of being isolated as the story takes hold. Each time you choose two of the three to interact, the third gets left behind. Saving a scenario where you tactically keep all three in equal contact, one of them is left exposed to their fears made manifest.<br /><br />

Second playthrough, I see Jupiter covered in blood, seeped into her hair and body. One of her myriad hands is gently cupping her chin. Another grips her from behind. Another holds a separate hand, reaching from impossible angles. It's only given a sparse few lines of text. I read through it all without a second thought.<br /><br />

Lying in bed afterwards, the imagery doesn't let go. I grab my Steam Deck and speed through through the entire thing again. This time I stare at it until my eyes hurt. Then stare at it until my face hurts, then my limbs, then my thoughts, then my thoughts, then my thoughts.<br /><br />

Jupiter's history is never quite said out loud. There might be an association, a hint that something has made her what she is, but you will never receive confirmation or closure. She tries, and fails, to create a combination of words that make sense. <br /><br />

There are no perfect descriptors, no perfect metaphors, but this one worked for me. WKTD achieved in 30 seconds what I failed to do for years. I didn't sleep for days after that. <br /><br />

---<br /><br />

In the medical world, there is this fundamental disconnect between practitioner and patient. The latter is always fighting to reach through to the former, to convince them that their experiences are real and worthy of more than brief, cursory attention. I've never once bridged this gap in a way that matters. <br /><br />

My mother and I used to look into the root cause of my seizures. The trail went cold after MRIs turned up ok - the desire to investigate them further disappeared once they couldn't tie back to symptoms identifiable in a book. When asked whether they could be brought on by other stresses, the neurologist folder her arms and stared at me in silence until I left.<br /><br />

It's so brushed aside that a consistent term still doesn't exist. The most modern version - functional seizures - drifts in between a mental and neurological space. To the extent that most medical professionals simply refer you back to the other category rather than think about it too hard.<br /><br />

Functional seizures can trigger based on a variety of stressors that I don't fully understand. Though I can identify the cascade of effects: from when the senses become overloaded, to when the body gives up, to when I'm on 5% of brainpower, fighting to ignore the tsunami of sensory signals from every direction, and just faintly aware that my tongue is stuck in my throat.<br /><br />

Tellingly, they most frequently happen when I'm on my own.<br /><br />

From a sensory perspective, the only thing that makes sense is that it doesn't make sense. All you can see is black but not quite black, yet the brightest thing you've ever seen. All you can hear is an advertisement for tinnitus. You'll taste something metallic and inorganic. You can feel the nerves in your limbs but not what they touch. <br /><br />

They were much easier to suppress when I didn't think about things very hard. Unfortunately I now care about my life, and my hormonal balance lets me actually feel emotion. Which has once again exposed this stupid bastard of a thing. <br /><br />

Things are better though. I can identify the slide towards a seizure, the 2-second warning before I hit the floor, and post-collapse recuperation. Two out of these three primarily involve Lucozade Sport, but if it works it works. <br /><br />

---<br /><br />

The wonders of modern medicine have left me to work on this myself. What seems like the biggest disconnect is a lack of easily-treatable symptoms. Sure you passed out from thinking about sharp things too much, but have you repeated it several times in a controlled environment? No? What a shame.

If the knife doesn't leave a visible mark, they don't seem to be too fussed about it. So I get to bother you lot about it instead :3<br /><br />

I am back to staring at a list of potential triggers. It's embarrassingly short. But writing one makes the next one easier. Some day they may come naturally. 
</p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Little Joys, Volume 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/16/Little-Joys-Vol-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Little Joys, Volume 1" /><published>2025-06-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-06-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/16/Little-Joys-Vol-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/16/Little-Joys-Vol-1.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
    This is a silly little thing that popped into my head today. I would like to write about the small things that give me far more enjoyment than they should.<br /><br />
    
    Similarly, the act of writing about it would give me a badly needed positivity push. The other thoughts I would put words to were worse; this is preferable for everyone involved.<br /><br />

    ---<br /><br />

    This week I was able to convert a friend-of-a-friend into a friend. Being in newfound proximity to so many cool people is one of my favourite blessings that has ever happened to me.<br /><br />

    Among some trinkets and cool things she brought over were these Danish liquorice sweets - one of them standard, one of them pre-salted. I nabbed the pre-salted ones.<br /><br />

    I haven't had liquorice since I was a kid, didn't particularly like it then, found it too strong. They somehow avoided me for twenty-ish years. So I thought it'd be a neat opportunity to try them out in a new context.<br /><br />

    I made the dire mistake of chewing into the first few I tried - do not do this. Suck for at least 30 seconds. Insert a joke of your choice here.<br /><br />
    
    They are utterly bizarre. Not quite tasting like liquorice that I've ever had before, nor liquorice that's had salt added into it. Another, possibly more horrifying, thing. Still unsure.<br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/gajol-1.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">This has earned its place in the cool gift collection</figcaption>
    </figure>

    Regardless, a cool little thing that I try out every day, and discover a different aspect to it every time.<br /><br />

    (Some research surfaced that the German language version of these treats are not allowed to be given to children, which also made me laugh.)<br /><br />

    ---<br /><br />

    I played Deltarune Chapters 3 and 4 last week and this week. The bar was high, but it was almost certainly always going to be great.<br /><br />

    Naturally, Toby served us up another couple of blinders. Chapter 3 is good fun, though not quite hitting the peaks of Chapter 2 - Queen was always going to be unbeatable. Chapter 4 throws us into the proper story of Deltarune, but reserves time to fuck around with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pZNO0FmyZ0U">delightful boss fights</a>.<br /><br />

    Fun new fact - I now hum this theme when enjoying bothering someone :3 <br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/deltarune.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">This happened organically and made me laugh far more than it should have</figcaption>
    </figure>

    ---<br /><br />

    I'm enjoying and appreciating physical contact with people for the first time in my life. Very new and very heartfelt.<br /><br /> 

    ---<br /><br />

    Muffin had his first birthday last week. I still want to do a huge page on this site for him, and another for Sandy. The little bastards deserve them :3<br /><br />

    ---<br /><br />

    <a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/03/09/Say-Hi-To-Takumi-The-Toyota-GT86.html">Takumi</a> gets a great audience from some kids I pass on the street.<br /><br />

    Passing some kids just leaving school, one of them belts out a "REV IT!!!!!" and I'm obliged to give Takumi maximum beans. Seeing him cheer in my rear view mirror made me laugh for a good week.<br /><br />

    Another kid walked past my driveway as I was letting Takumi idle on high, and I see him run over to his dad, then back to me, giving me a little hand signal to rev it. How could I not?<br /><br />

<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>

</p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a silly little thing that popped into my head today. I would like to write about the small things that give me far more enjoyment than they should. Similarly, the act of writing about it would give me a badly needed positivity push. The other thoughts I would put words to were worse; this is preferable for everyone involved.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Touch</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/01/Touch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Touch" /><published>2025-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/01/Touch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/01/Touch.html"><![CDATA[<div>
    <p>
        <p class="bolded">Content warning: Abuse</p>
    </p>
    <p>
    I wish I were mute.<br /><br />
    There is no sequence of words that make sense. Something fundamental sits in between me and every other person, something that twists every sentence into something I don't fully understand.<br /> <br />
    You can fight it, of course. Play the words out a hundred times in your head, and watch them change slightly every time. Wait for the perfect moment to say it, only for it to never arrive. Get the thoughts out, and they never land. <br /><br />
    Or, you can sit in silence, and watch the dread grow with every passing minute. It all goes the same way. <br /><br />
    You can lie with words. Most combinations of them will work. Say anything to me, and I'd probably believe it. <br /><br />
    There's plenty of other ways to lie as well. I can't read your expression, or hear your tone. Do things in total opposition to each other, and watch me struggle to tell the difference. <br /><br />
    The only honest sense is touch. Grab me by the leg, throw me to the floor, show me what you think I'm worth. <br /><br />
    The only honest sense is touch. Pin me to the wall, I cannot avoid you now. <br /><br />
    The only honest sense is touch. Stick that knife in my face, see what I can do about it. <br /><br />
    The only honest sense is touch. Show me that you love me, I don't care how. <br /><br />
    I'm enamoured with the thought of a hand for every type of touch. It's not a new wonder, but fresh in the mind once again. There is unavoidable truth in it, painful or joyful as each one might be. <br /><br />
    Hit me, I hit you back. Hold me, I hold you back. Don't touch me, or do. We will finally be even, no matter what. <br /><br />
    I wish I were mute. My only greater wish is that you are, too.  <br /><br />
    </p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Content warning: Abuse I wish I were mute. There is no sequence of words that make sense. Something fundamental sits in between me and every other person, something that twists every sentence into something I don't fully understand. You can fight it, of course. Play the words out a hundred times in your head, and watch them change slightly every time. Wait for the perfect moment to say it, only for it to never arrive. Get the thoughts out, and they never land. Or, you can sit in silence, and watch the dread grow with every passing minute. It all goes the same way. You can lie with words. Most combinations of them will work. Say anything to me, and I'd probably believe it. There's plenty of other ways to lie as well. I can't read your expression, or hear your tone. Do things in total opposition to each other, and watch me struggle to tell the difference. The only honest sense is touch. Grab me by the leg, throw me to the floor, show me what you think I'm worth. The only honest sense is touch. Pin me to the wall, I cannot avoid you now. The only honest sense is touch. Stick that knife in my face, see what I can do about it. The only honest sense is touch. Show me that you love me, I don't care how. I'm enamoured with the thought of a hand for every type of touch. It's not a new wonder, but fresh in the mind once again. There is unavoidable truth in it, painful or joyful as each one might be. Hit me, I hit you back. Hold me, I hold you back. Don't touch me, or do. We will finally be even, no matter what. I wish I were mute. My only greater wish is that you are, too.]]></summary></entry></feed>