<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-12-05T13:01:24+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/atom.xml</id><title type="html">Sandy’s Palace</title><subtitle>Caoimhe&apos;s gay little website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Outlive The Bastards</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/12/05/Outlive-The-Bastards.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Outlive The Bastards" /><published>2025-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/12/05/Outlive-The-Bastards</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/12/05/Outlive-The-Bastards.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
<blockquote>“One final paragraph of advice: do not burn yourselves out. Be as I am - a reluctant enthusiast....a part-time crusader, a half-hearted fanatic. Save the other half of yourselves and your lives for pleasure and adventure. It is not enough to fight for the land; it is even more important to enjoy it. While you can. While it’s still here. So get out there and hunt and fish and mess around with your friends, ramble out yonder and explore the forests, climb the mountains, bag the peaks, run the rivers, breathe deep of that yet sweet and lucid air, sit quietly for a while and contemplate the precious stillness, the lovely, mysterious, and awesome space. Enjoy yourselves, keep your brain in your head and your head firmly attached to the body, the body active and alive, and I promise you this much; I promise you this one sweet victory over our enemies, over those desk-bound men and women with their hearts in a safe deposit box, and their eyes hypnotized by desk calculators. I promise you this; You will outlive the bastards.”</blockquote>

I have never engaged with Edward Abbey's work before. This quote burrowed through to me years ago, probably through Tumblr, and came to mind recently at a very specific moment.<br /><br />

I - and we - exist under relentless attack. Our access to healthcare is political football for headline-chasers and professional imbeciles. Our ability to walk down the street, how we piss, how we access the same basic resources as anyone else is open game for endless bile and hatred. Journalists and grifters squash our existence while simultaneously screaming how they're silenced, their voices echoing loudly through every piece of media every day of the week. How I wish their last day on this planet was lived in our shoes.<br /><br />

To be told the best act of resistance is love isn't enough. I do not love these scum. By design, they will never understand, and will never make the effort to. Why would they? Our lives are too ripe for exploitation. I already give them far more respect than they deserve. No, resistance is a dogged act.<br /><br />

Stop the quivering performance. You will go on as you always do. We will simply do the same.<br /><br />

There's been several eye-opening moments for me in the past few years. Realisations that we can simply <i>do</i> things never before imagined. These rolling revelations haven't stopped. I can live and love in ways I was never able to before, and nothing can stop this.<br /><br />

So we live. But only in a way that works for us. We dictate how we breathe, how we act, how we medicate, how we live and how we die. How long did I spend dancing to other peoples' tunes, hoping and begging to be given basic respect, only to be thrown aside? Never again.<br /><br />

I wonder how Edward would consider my interpretation of his speech. I'm a reluctant enthusiast by trade, doing things that I dearly wish weren't necessary, but we stay alive regardless. A part-time crusader when the anger boils over and I push myself out of my lover's embrace and into the cold outside. A half-hearted fanatic when I defend my existence.<br /><br />

Do I fight for the land? I love it, sure, but strongly suspect my actions don't go far enough. I am knee-deep in the urban desecration that he so despised. The nature around my house is human-designed and maintained, nothing allowed to grow out of proportion for fear of offending the land "owners". It's not true nature.<br /><br />

My interpretation of Edward's passion is where he strikes the balance between preserving our sanity and maximising our days on this planet. I do it with friends and loved ones every day, and I will never let go of it. Even if I'm more attached to screens than I would like. I am not entranced by the lull of numbers going up, of preserving capital, of hiding myself in a glass box until my pension plan activates. No, I live now.<br /><br />

So I have embraced this quote and tethered it to my values<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>. I think of it when being a reluctant enthusiast, a part-time crusader, and a half-hearted fanatic. When I'm full of love and when I'm boiling over with anger and bitterness. I would like it to be associated with my life. If at the end of it all, it fits appropriately, I will be very pleased.<br /><br />

After all, I am nothing if not a petty bitch :3


<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>Is it obvious that this is a thing I've been working on with a therapist? I'm not sure which answer is funnier.<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>


</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“One final paragraph of advice: do not burn yourselves out. Be as I am - a reluctant enthusiast....a part-time crusader, a half-hearted fanatic. Save the other half of yourselves and your lives for pleasure and adventure. It is not enough to fight for the land; it is even more important to enjoy it. While you can. While it’s still here. So get out there and hunt and fish and mess around with your friends, ramble out yonder and explore the forests, climb the mountains, bag the peaks, run the rivers, breathe deep of that yet sweet and lucid air, sit quietly for a while and contemplate the precious stillness, the lovely, mysterious, and awesome space. Enjoy yourselves, keep your brain in your head and your head firmly attached to the body, the body active and alive, and I promise you this much; I promise you this one sweet victory over our enemies, over those desk-bound men and women with their hearts in a safe deposit box, and their eyes hypnotized by desk calculators. I promise you this; You will outlive the bastards.”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Realities of Being Nice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/11/19/The-Realities-of-Being-Nice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Realities of Being Nice" /><published>2025-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/11/19/The-Realities-of-Being-Nice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/11/19/The-Realities-of-Being-Nice.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>---<br /><br />
<b>Content warning: I go into considerable detail talking about partner and domestic abuse. This post does attempt to take on a nicer tone in the final segment.</b><br /><br />---<br /><br />

I've been reliably told that I fawn over people. This is not a compliment.<br /><br />

Generally we have one of four responses to threats: Fight, flight, freeze, and fawn. Each fucks you up in a lovely and unique way. For someone who fawns, it means you appease the entity in front of you at all costs.<br /><br />

Your boss can be as much of a dickhead as they like, and you'll be nice to them, enabling them to keep doing it. You get yapped over at every opportunity, then you sit back and listen to everyone with a big wide-eyed smile on your face. Your partner jabs a knife in your face while you're up against a wall, and you don't even think too much about it. They're saying something, you should be hearing them out :)<br /><br />

Assisted with a psychotherapist who doesn't actively try to put me in danger<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>, picking this theory apart has been an interesting experience. It leads back - as it always does - to childhood, and what events there may have instilled such a reaction. You could spend years doing this. Eventually it'll lead to the events that brought you to needing therapy in the first place. <br /><br />

The time of year is February 2020. You're moving into a flat with your partner for the first time. For the past few years, you did your best to make the most out of every situation and the time you had together. Even if you got talked over a lot, it was fine because they were very eager to say things! Even if they had unpredictable meltdowns, you threw yourself at trying to resolve them, if only to mitigate the stress on their side. Don't think too hard about whether you actually want this or not. Nobody else has ever wanted you, and you have nowhere else to go. There is no alternative.<br /><br />

The first day in the flat is still fresh on the mind. The partner - who I'm calling E for the rest of this post - is having a meltdown because they're convinced the flat is going to be overflowing with belongings. Naturally this leads to a vividly explained train of thought where you're going to get evicted, made homeless, then killed. This is getting screamed at you while you have a black bag of clothes in your hand, dragging it to the wardrobe. Where you put clothes.<br /><br />

This continues for the rest of the day. E continues berating you while sitting on the couch doing fuck all to help. After all, you're moving their stuff for them. Looking back, I was right in my initial assessment of it being the worst and most regretful day of my life.<br /><br />

The flat did not overfill with belongings. E was simply worried that they wouldn't have space to put up their anime figurines. The meltdown is never brought up again.<br /><br />

I was bitter and angry, of course. But I had to be nice. Because I told myself that I had to be nice. The thought of being any other way led me back to memories of being dogpiled on for standing up or speaking out. People were/are far too accustomed to walking over me without consequence, that any pushback felt like oppression to them. Or so I told myself.<br /><br />

Plus, any dreams of autonomy in my head were about to be wiped out. Within a month, the whole country was put into the first of a wave of lockdowns. We did not reliably escape them for over two years. I have very irrational views on this<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[2]</a></sup>.<br /><br />

Life goals morph into surviving just this one day, solely to enable moving onto the next. This used to be a passive approach, being stuck in miserable low-pay jobs, but now it was an active one. A successful day was one where you got screamed at as little as possible, and you would do anything to facilitate this.<br /><br />

I have very few memories around this time. There are vague thoughts of scrolling news headlines to see the daily death and hospitalisation counts, and begging for speculation on when we might be allowed go outside freely again. Looking through the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Timeline_of_the_COVID-19_pandemic_in_the_Republic_of_Ireland_(2020)">timeline of events</a> doesn't feel real at all.<br /><br />

There are recollections of specific E meltdowns. They're not easy to retrieve, and mostly invade the mind when a related stressor sets them off. If I rake my head with my fingernails, I think of being barricaded in the tiniest room in the house, getting shouted by E because they had a difficult day in work. If I scratch my face, I think of moments where I'm filled with fear and anger, and the rare free space in which I allowed myself to feel it. If I bite my finger, I taste blood.<br /><br />

I still remember the steps of the flat's staircase and how they sounded under my shoes. They're tied into thoughts of being shouted at through several walls before I even get the front door open. Sometimes I would sit on the steps and wait it out. It didn't help.<br /><br />

In 2021 I recall moving jobs in January, and getting a vaccine at some point in the second half. That's it.<br /><br />

Chronic sleep deprivation became, well, chronic. My side of the bed was rammed up against the wall so E could have more space to move around in the mornings. I was kept up at night by the sounds of teeth grinding, getting kicked, the quilt being ripped off me so E could wrap themselves up like a cinnamon roll, and random shouting episodes when E was woken up by hearing something on the street. Aggravated, they would shake me awake shouting about how inconsiderate <i>someone else</i> was. I never once opened my mouth to point out the obvious.<br /><br />

E had severe problems. I put up with them because I thought that's what you're supposed to do. Raised on Catholic Ireland doctrine of not questioning what you've been served, and the embedded mantra that partners should unquestionably be there for each other. So I was.<br /><br />

By 2022, E was functional to the point where you might decide to trust them with pulling some of the weight around the house. They would cook 1-2 dinners a week. Being 2 metres away from E while they prepped food was unsatisfactory to E, because supposedly they couldn't hear you. So they invite you to move into the kitchen while they worked. Once you're there and leaned against a wall, they would spin around and jab a 12-inch knife in your face. They shout words in your face.<br /><br />

Not one thought of resistance came into my head. I counted my breaths. When the threat quietened, I slid along the wall and left the room. E looks bemused, already throwing away the recording of what just happened. I don't even escape the flat, I just slink away, quietly continuing attempts at a conversation. Anything to keep E distracted.<br /><br />

The dissonance in E's head was truly a scientific wonder. On the rare occasions where I confronted E in the moment of a conflict, they would throw away the threat in a heartbeat and pretend it never existed. No I never held a knife in your face? No I didn't just say that?? No I'm not barricading you right this instant???<br /><br />

The fawn response always wins over. You never push an argument too far, because that puts yourself in harm's way again. Just defuse this current threat, and don't think about the next one. Don't think ahead.<br /><br />

I have trains of thoughts from 2022. The pent-up fear and anger was boiling over, and being taken out on myself. I still couldn't even articulate the events that were happening to me. But there was a growing sense that something was badly wrong, and that I couldn't do this forever. This was not a straightforward escape process.<br /><br />

Extracing myself from this relationship was blocked by the barriers of: COVID lockdowns, the housing crisis, and the relentless urge to fawn over E and placate them rather than cause drama. The first of these dissipated throughout 2022. The second is a permanent issue in Irish society, and I had to let this fuck me over in order to survive. The third was incredibly messy.<br /><br />

The long-term desire to leave was always overridden by the short-term need of staying safe. Raising accusations of abusive behaviour was out of the question. I sometimes raised dissatisfactions, but warped them in a way that solely or predominantly blamed me. After all, there had to be something wrong with <i>me</i>.<br /><br />

I used to wonder about how E felt about these conversations beginning to emerge. As incomprehensible as it might sound, I feel they genuinely did not understand the acts they were doing. Looking back on specific events, they seemed to have no comprehension of other people having other perspectives. What went on in their own head totally dominated their worldview, and they demanded aggressively that everyone and everything follow that. There was no knife.<br /><br />

I would make a limp attempt at a breakup, only to be barricaded in the bedroom again, being screamed at to tell E that I loved them. So I said that.<br /><br />

I have no idea what the final catalyst for the breakup actually was. Far more vivid is the memory of the next few days, brain activity dulled to a pathetic murmur, no idea what to do with myself with nothing to fawn over. I crashed very hard. The recovery period was even worse than most of the scenario in which I was escaping from.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[3]</a></sup><br /><br />

<i>Skipping ahead - there is a period of a few months here which deserves to be its own reminiscence, far further away in the future. Most of my hatred of people in power stems from this time.</i><br /><br />

I often credit <a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/07/01/Sandy.html">Sandy</a> with keeping me alive at this point. Having a fluffly little dude to fawn over was great. It carried zero downside. It was unheard of. Most of my life choices following his adoption circle around ensuring that he's happy and comfortable, which keeps me happy and comfortable :3<br /><br />

The next few months of memories do exist, but mostly revolve around cats and some upheaval in work. Which was excellent as focusing on myself still would have been too much.<br /><br />

Building a new personality post-escape has been unequivocally fun. My social circle is 95% different from even three years ago, which allowed me to take a mostly fresh approach when interacting with people. Core parts of our brain aren't so easily rewired, but what was managed was more than enough. I love many many people now.<br /><br />

Most progress in 2023 and 2024 involved stumbling from one wildly new situation to the next, learning an absurd amount and doing my genuine best for both me and others. I still feel like I'm in a honeymoon period of sorts.<br /><br /> 

I still fawn over people too much. People fuck me over, and I let them in the moment, only getting angry afterwards. This isn't healthy for a multitude of reasons. But there is consciousness of it, which wasn't there before. And I can actually talk to some people about it. Again, unheard of until now.<br /><br />

Analysing how I handle interacting with people has been very challenging. Being forced to tackle the realisation that you bend over for other people in conflicts leaves a hard taste once you realise how often it's happened. The upside is that I'm attempting to skew my fawning over people into a positive thing. I'm in a much healthier and safer position in life, and better able to provide for people around me whom I love very much. Once my own needs are still met, it feels a lot better.<br /><br />

The bitter thoughts do not leave me. But there are things to fight for now. It's more than enough..

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>I will never miss any excuse to say how much the HSE and every suit in it needs to be burned to the ground.<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
        <p>Keeping this train of thought separate. My life was thrown aside and disregarded to save others. I had no say in the matter. I don't care how many people lived because of these decisions made, I will always resent them and the reticence from society and the media in discussing them.<a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
        <p>I'm still not able to articulate this period. And the change in tone after this paragraph is deliberate.<a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>


</p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[--- Content warning: I go into considerable detail talking about partner and domestic abuse. This post does attempt to take on a nicer tone in the final segment.---]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Turboautismo</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/11/11/Turboautismo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Turboautismo" /><published>2025-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/11/11/Turboautismo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/11/11/Turboautismo.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
Hey check out the abridged results of a psychological assessment I got done recently 

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/cdm.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;"></figcaption>
</figure>

CAMPEÃO DO MUNDO 💯💯💯 🔥🔥🔥 🇧🇷

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey check out the abridged results of a psychological assessment I got done recently]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You’re In The Know, Right?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/11/05/You're-In-The-Know-Right.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You’re In The Know, Right?" /><published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/11/05/You&apos;re-In-The-Know-Right</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/11/05/You&apos;re-In-The-Know-Right.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
Bloodborne is one of my favourite games of all time, and always will be. It's as close to perfection as a FromSoft title is ever going to be. Shame about the PS4 exclusivity though.<br /><br />

Director Hidataka Miyazaki, skipping development of Dark Souls 2 and leaving that game in the unproven hands of Tomohiro Shibuya and Yui Tanimura, was planning Bloodborne before Dark Souls 1's DLC was even released. <a href="https://darksouls.wiki.fextralife.com/Marvelous+Chester">Marvelous Chester</a> was a systems check, having a unique character rigging model versus every other model in DS1. This, plus his unusual clothing and bizarre moveset, was Miyazaki testing the waters to see if the Havok engine could handle the new ideas.<br /><br />

Three years of development later, Bloodborne did far better than that. Combat was now fast and increasingly ruthless. Immediately upon arrival in Central Yharnam, you are delivered a stark reminder that this is not a Souls title. Poise as a stat had been eliminated - if you got hit even once, your rhythm was shattered. Shields were thoroughly discouraged, with the base game only having one flimsy model, and it was intended as a mocking joke. The game played fast and expected you to keep up.<br /><br />

Less openly communicated was the game's surprisingly lenient levels of forgiveness. I-frames provided via dodging were significantly higher, and parrying had an enormous activation window. Naturally, being Bloodborne, parrying now involved shooting your opponent in the face. This also worked with the cannon. Big fan of that.<br /><br />

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/43oKzqPpJNQ?si=0kcgUzLJ5m0CodS_" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe><br /><br />

Thematically, this game was magnificent. Opaque as usual, but the depth of the worldbuilding was unparalleled. Moving from a moderately-understandable Victorian horror, to the final third of the game descending into Lovecraftian madness, was outstandingly well executed. Every area is dripping with layers of history and meaning, most of it sailing over the heads of new players. On subsequent playthroughs, you see far more - figuratively and literally.<br /><br />

The Insight mechanic may have been unusual, but uncovering its implications in the world was stunning. At low or zero levels of Insight, your character simply can't observe and operate on the level that Yharnam exists on, with the hidden bonus of taking less damage from the more horrifying enemy effects. High levels of Insight put you at risk, but the world reveals enemies and entities that were there all along, ignoring you until you became a threat.<br /><br />

The world of Yharnam quite literally exists on various levels and planes. The Old Hunters DLC explores and reveals this more, in the most complete piece of work FromSoft has ever pulled off. Physical and cognitive realities are separated from the beginning, and over time your character moves between them - sometimes willingly, sometimes extremely unwillingly.<br /><br />

Beings on higher planes can be killed, but seem not to die in a way that makes linear sense. Most still exist, on a level that is incomprehensible and unreachable to you. And sometimes you can bring them back and they get rather mad about it<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>.<br /><br />

Everything from the soundtrack, to the architecture, to the hidden meanings behind actions and words spoken, paints the best story in almost any video game I've played. Revelations aren't delivered to you on a platter, you must discover them by yourself. Look at the above video again - for a few frames, you can see the hunter's riposting hand stretch into a beast claw, hinting at the peculiar Yharnam madness being unavoidable to everyone sucked into it. Absolutely nobody in the game will tell you that you're not injecting yourself with <i>regular</i> blood, you piece together the information yourself and then scream internally for a week<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[2]</a></sup>.<br /><br />

Bosses were overall pretty tough, and perhaps demanded a more narrow combat style than the broader approach of Souls games, but were almost always gripping experiences. And the soundtrack was lethal.<br /><br />

If there is a downside to Bloodborne, it's that the PvP was poorly thought out. Using bells to signal co-operations or invasions took away player agency, as without password matching (which few knew about) you had no clue were there other players online at the same time and in the same area as you. Plus, the mechanic of rivalling factions could turn an expectant co-operator into an adversary, with no player choice allowed. Perhaps a cool idea, but very ill-executed.<br /><br />

I've rarely been as engrossed in a game world. There is nothing else like it, and we likely won't see another similarly radical title via FromSoftware ever again.

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/bb-1.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Bloodborne didn't have one dominant message meme like most Souls games did. The title of this article was an often-spammed message aiming to be deliberately vague and silly. Also "Time for thrust attacks" next to choice NPCs.</figcaption>
</figure>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>That's what Annalise gets for telling me to kneel.<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
        <p>Spoiler: It's menstrual blood. Only women were producing the recovery vials, and the organisation seeking to commune with the gods was called Mensis. Plus whatever the fuck Imposter Iosefka was cooking up.<a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>


</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bloodborne is one of my favourite games of all time, and always will be. It's as close to perfection as a FromSoft title is ever going to be. Shame about the PS4 exclusivity though.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Don’t Give Up, Skeleton!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/11/03/Don't-Give-Up-Skeleton.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Don’t Give Up, Skeleton!" /><published>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/11/03/Don&apos;t-Give-Up-Skeleton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/11/03/Don&apos;t-Give-Up-Skeleton.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
"Dark Souls 2 is underrated" is overrated. Do not argue with me on this.<br /><br />

Released in 2014, the initial reception was negative on several fronts. Seasoned Souls fans disliked the sequel's adoption of themes and motifs from the original without fully understanding why they were there in the first place. New players came face to face with the now heavily-marketed "prepare to die" tagline that was baked into the game design. And games journalists were, as expected, unbearably annoying for all the wrong reasons.<br /><br />

More concerning was the drift in area design, enemy placement, and player animations, all crafted to put the player in compromising positions without intuitive explanation. Stepping forward in most areas provoked divebombs and ambushes to an exhausting amount. Hiding i-frames behind the Adaptability stat was unforgiveable and deserves its own article that I couldn't be arsed doing.<br /><br />

Boss design was, for the most part, uninspired and unrewarding. Dude With Sword fights began with Dark Souls 2, and we've never recovered from it since. The soundtrack for these fights was noticeably poorer as well. Diehard DS2 fans - please tell me what the Flexile Sentry battle theme sounds like. I'll wait.<br /><br />

The plot, for the most part, simply didn't exist. You have traveled to Drangleic to undo your curse, sure. But why are you following Shanalotte's suggestion to topple the king and become the new monarch? It's never elaborated on. The opening cinematic suggests that your character stumbles into this train of events "without really knowing why". Well I sure would fucking like to.<br /><br />

NPC plotlines are even worse. "Why did I come to this place? Ehhhghhhghghghghgh..... sure you know yourself." There you go, saved you some time, no need to watch VaatiVidya<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>.<br /><br />

The pre-release demo of the game promised lighting and shadows that the PS3 and Xbox360 couldn't handle. So the downgrade for the release version was catastrophic. Entire areas had copy-paste brightened textures on the walls, and areas that relied on dark lighting to provoke a challenge, simply didn't.<br /><br />

So: why does it have the highest amount of play hours of any EldenShadowSoulsBorne title I own?<br /><br />

The three DLCs, panned before release for pushing the Souls franchise into the Season Pass craze, were broadly very good. Significantly better boss fights, thoroughly designed areas, and a story arcing across all three entries that expanded and improved on the original game's attempts.<br /><br />  

As time passed, the issue with the original game's directorship became clear. Tomohiro Shibuya and Yui Tanimura were both listed as directors for development of the base game. It's unknown whether one held authority over the other, but it's known that the game stumbled through development, up to its release window, with nothing resembling a level of solid fundamental structure, never mind polish. Absolutely dire design like the Shrine of Winter's knee-high roadblock were symptoms of catastrophic miscommunication and disjointed level design.

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/ds2-3.jpeg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">To pass through the Shrine of Winter, the player is expected to fell four mighty bosses, or acquire one million souls. Because they can't hop over these rocks right next to the Shrine.</figcaption>
</figure>

What's most interesting is that, after release, Shibuya was turfed out, never to be seen again as a director at FromSoftware or any other company. Tanimura stayed on, and was tasked with directing the three well-received DLCs. His later work on Dark Souls 3, and Elden Ring+DLC, neither of which was planned before 2's release, strongly suggests that Shibuya was the problem.<br /><br />

The slightly-more-polished version of DS2 (Scholar of the First Sin), melded the base game into the DLCs, and attempted to correct some of the rot. Some aspects, like the disjointed level design, was unfixable without producing an entirely new game. But, with the execption of Iron Keep<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[2]</a></sup>, areas and mechanics were tidied up and made more intuitive. This version of Dark Souls 2 is considered the quintissential version, and nobody dares touch the release-version base game apart from ironic YouTube videos.<br /><br />

There is wonderful variety in weapons and armour. While the game has cycled through questionable balance patches<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[3]</a></sup>, the diversity of player choice in playstyle is commendable. There's some poor weapons, and joke weapons, but you can take an absurd amount of weapon classes and make them work. Powerstancing weapons - wielding two same-class weapons simultaneously with a heftier stat requirement - was a wild approach and broadly loved by fans. PvP was very healthy and lasted for many years.<br /><br />

I think this is the main reason why I keep coming back. It's stupendously easy to pick up this game and try something stupid with it. Plus it's the best Souls games in terms of game-breaking exploits that are comparatively easy to pull off. I always enjoy <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kXEy4bx90sM">parrywalking</a> in front of the unenlightened.<br /><br />

I will always enjoy complaining about this game. While playing it, mostly.

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/ds2-1.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">The title of this article comes from the most popular message left by players, always positioned humourously next to extremely dead corpses.</figcaption>
</figure>

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/ds2-2.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">And also other funny things.</figcaption>
</figure>




<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>King Yappertron of the Conjecture Brigade.<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
        <p>I cannot stress heavily enough how they took a flawed area and made it apocalyptic dogshit.<a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
        <p>Not an issue unique to 2, and I don't judge it as harshly as I might.<a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>


</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA["Dark Souls 2 is underrated" is overrated. Do not argue with me on this.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SuperValu Car Park Simulator 2025</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/28/SuperValu-Car-Park-Simulator-2025.md.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SuperValu Car Park Simulator 2025" /><published>2025-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/10/28/SuperValu-Car-Park-Simulator-2025.md</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/28/SuperValu-Car-Park-Simulator-2025.md.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
I did my first track day in two years! And also brought Takumi for the first time! How exciting!<br /><br />

This is where the enthusiasm ends. For the money spent, I might as well have bought and raced an ice cream truck.<br /><br />

Mondello is a good track - plenty of technical challenging corners, decent amount of undulation, and unpredictable weather. It can be attacked with anything up to the speed of a Formula 3 car, and tests plenty of aspects of car performance and driver skill. Unfortunately it is populated by clowns.<br /><br />

The rules of motorsport are there for a reason. "Overtake on the left on the straights only" and "Get the fuck out of faster people's way" are pretty basic ones. There's huge variation in car performance, and the straights are the safest way of sorting cars out. This understanding got thrown out the window within the first hour, as I got divebombed going into a 100kph corner:<br /><br />

<p>
    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/td-1.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mS41bHNw1WI">TU TU DU DU</a></figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>
<p>

Red flag ends the current session, as there's marshals, recovery vehicles, and sometimes ambulances on track. You'd have to be some cretin to overtake needlessly when we're going into the garage-

<p>
    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/td-2.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">If you're wondering why I'm mad, it's the fifth red flag of the day after 90 minutes of running</figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>
<p>

We had eight red flags throughout the day from imbeciles spinning into the gravel, more than one crash, and zero intelligence applied in changeable conditions.<br /><br />

The quantity of cars on track was unmanageable. The track day was fully booked out; either this is too high an amount, or the marshals needed to limit the amount of cars on track at any given time.

<p>
    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/td-3.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">WHY</figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>
<p>

<p>
    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/td-4.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">THE</figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>
<p>

<p>
    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/td-5.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">FUCK</figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>
<p>

<p>
    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/td-6.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">ARE</figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>
<p>

<p>
    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/td-7.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">YOU</figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>
<p>

<p>
    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/td-8.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">HERE (also watch this guy own himself lol)</figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>
<p>

I didn't get a single uninterrupted lap all day, despite the track having 6 hours of availability. Every single time without fail, the red flag would come out, or some clown would park themselves in the middle of the track and refuse to move, or someone would spin directly in front of me. I completely maintain that god is real, she fucking hates me, and I did something as a previous reincarnation that earned me some kind of Sisyphean punishment where imbeciles are bred and raised for decades for the sole purpose of being dropped in front of me while I try to do things and go places.<br /><br />

The morning session was mostly dry, with light rain starting to fall around midday. My best lap time was 2:14, but I only got to spend 2/3rds of the lap actually pushing. Maybe 2:05 or 2:00 is doable with Takumi, but I'll never find out.<br /><br />

The afternoon session was wet from start to finish, with particularly heavy rain around 3-4pm. This was a lot more challenging, as rather than just chasing lower laptimes, pushing the car to its limits in super tricky conditions was far more interesting. I was hoping to turn off Traction Control at some point, but it became clear I'd be upside-down if I did. Fastest lap in the wet was 2:34, but again heavily interrupted by god's finest soldiers. Maybe sub-2:30 was doable in another universe better than this one.<br /><br />

I did have some degree of entertainment. Someone turned up with a Subaru BRZ<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>, and I had fun keeping up with that driver in the afternoon session to see where our differences lay. Takumi was much better under braking, although that could just have been me being more confident. Accelerating out of corners was a key issue for me all day, and I was struggling to match the BRZ here. Otherwise we were pretty evenly-matched and gave each other plenty of room to have fun, which was nice.<br /><br />

I was hoping to borrow a GoPro for the day, but frankly I don't think I missed out on much. Moving my dashcam around the car worked sufficiently for the ragebait it outputted<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[2]</a></sup>.

I am praying the British motorsport scene is better behaved. I want to go to Anglesey soon, and will put up with the insane ferry cost to actually enjoy a track day.

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/td-1.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">My boy deserves it :3</figcaption>
</figure>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>Exact same underlying car as the Toyota GT86, but with a different badge<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
        <p>Also the clock is wrong by an hour on those videos because Daylight Savings Time is stupid<a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>


</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I did my first track day in two years! And also brought Takumi for the first time! How exciting!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Amazing Chest Ahead</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/10/Amazing-Chest-Ahead.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Amazing Chest Ahead" /><published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/10/10/Amazing-Chest-Ahead</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/10/Amazing-Chest-Ahead.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
After a brief rant about <a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/10/09/THE-LEGEND-NEVER-DIES.html">Giantdad</a> I'm in a Dark Souls 1 mood again. I've played it through enough, and this time am more thinking fondly of the nuts online community, the bizarre memes that followed, and the utter broken nonsense that was a delight to tear apart and exploit.<br /><br />

The year is, once again, 2012. Dark Souls 1 has just released on PC, and due to the hype being steadily built from its console release a year prior, the screeching about artificial difficulty has hit record highs<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>. Yours truly is blasting through a second playthrough on New Game Plus, picking up all of the little hints that passed me by the first time, and owning myself in the PvP scene with glee.<br /><br />

Building on Demon's Souls' charm of being innovative without a final touch of polish, there is <i>so</i> much to exploit. The Endurance stat is absurdly overpowered. The Resistance stat is useless. Darkroot Forest is an absolute clusterfuck of gank squads and tryhard bullshit.<br /><br />

The <a href="https://darksouls.wiki.fextralife.com/Ring+of+Fog">Ring of Fog</a> completely prevented enemy players from locking onto you. <a href="https://darksouls.wiki.fextralife.com/Miracle+Synergy">Resonance signs</a> were invisible and you had no idea when they were active - this mechanic took over two years of testing for the community to understand properly. Proper understanding of <a href="http://darksouls.wikidot.com/vagrant">Vagrant</a> appearances took even longer.<br /><br />

Yet the niche mechanics of the game were a hidden joy in itself. Kindling a bonfire would send a single charge of Estus Flask healing to a random other player's world. This was a beautiful little trick that saved many people's boss runs in the most poetic of circumstances.<br /><br />

However, outrageously broken stuff is far funnier. Until Patch 1.06, souls obtained from enemies/bosses was <i>less than half</i> of what it currently is. So beating the Taurus Demon would net you a cool 1,000 souls, which could buy you fuck all. Good job scrub.<br /><br />

Remember <a href="https://darksouls.wiki.fextralife.com/Basilisk">Basilisks</a>, whose mist can inflict the <a href="https://darksouls.wiki.fextralife.com/curse">Curse mechanic</a>, halving your HP if you died to it? IT. COULD. STACK.<br /><br />

Roll-swapping weapons and movesets was totally viable, meaning you could meld the Tranquil Walk of Peace and Darkmoon Blade spells into some <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZMz8lB_AvP0">ungodly AoE murder machine with no consequences</a>. And nobody ever realised how good <a href="https://darksouls.wiki.fextralife.com/Strong+Magic+Shield">Strong Magic Shield</a> was.<br /><br />

Abusing this to grief others was easy<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[2]</a></sup>. Making use of these mechanics in increasingly silly ways was far more challenging and rewarding. Unkillable when two-handing a greatshield? Just <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oXp8Th41rBs">hold up a certain infamous choke point</a> and make people lose their minds. Even <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WqacyIaq27o">maximising usage out of silly character animations</a> was its own trend.<br /><br />

None of this died overnight with future game releases. But the development cycle became tighter, the community were laser-focused on analysing game files on Day 1, and PvP arenas demanded narrower and narrower builds to stand any chance of victory. I do miss the blind scrambling to figure out the depths to which game mechanics worked, the yolo approach to surviving in Lordran, the total lack of orthodoxy to how the community behaved<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[3]</a></sup>. Elden Ring releasing to a barrage of NEW BROKEN META screeching nonsense does not fill me with anywhere near the same level of love.<br /><br />

Also - no other EldenShadowSoulsBorne game had the <a href="/assets/images/blog/ds1.gif">greatest gesture of all time</a>. Case closed.<br /><br />

Final note: The blog post title is a reference to the time-honoured tradition of abusing the message system for silly nonsense:

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/ds1.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">This will be a trend for my inevitable Dark Souls 2/3/Bloodborne rambles</figcaption>
</figure>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>A peak that would be surprassed many, many times.<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
        <p>For example, modifying the Giantdad built to operate at Level 11 and terrorise new players in Undead Burg. Teehee.<a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
        <p>Not a wholly positive scene of behaviour, but an amusingly entertaining one, even if only in hindsight.<a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>


</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a brief rant about Giantdad I'm in a Dark Souls 1 mood again. I've played it through enough, and this time am more thinking fondly of the nuts online community, the bizarre memes that followed, and the utter broken nonsense that was a delight to tear apart and exploit.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What I’m Reading, Volume 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/10/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I’m Reading, Volume 5" /><published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/10/10/What-I&apos;m-Reading-Vol-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/10/What-I&apos;m-Reading-Vol-5.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
    Previous iterations:<br /><br />
    <ul>
        <li><a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/05/11/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-1.html">Volume 1</a></li>
        <li><a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/05/27/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-2.html">Volume 2</a></li>
        <li><a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/07/02/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-3.html">Volume 3</a></li>
        <li><a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/09/02/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-4.html">Volume 4</a></li>
    </ul>

I probably could have added more Light Reads, but I'm on holidays for a week and wanted to wrap this up! 

<p><h1>Serious Reads</h1></p>

<h2><a href="https://www.wired.com/story/mike-lynch-sinking-disaster/">The Superyacht, the Billionaire, and a Wildly Improbable Disaster at Sea</a></h2>
<b>Note: Wired has a limited amount of free articles for non-subscribers. If you have any issues with the above link, use a link like <a href="https://www.removepaywall.com/search?url=https://www.wired.com/story/mike-lynch-sinking-disaster/">Remove Paywall</a>.</b>
<blockquote>What has emerged through the various investigations, and through press accounts, is a critical flaw in the Bayesian’s design. The single-mast configuration that gave the yacht her elegant lines—unique among the boat designer’s sought-after series of similar vessels—also dangerously affected her center of gravity. The MAIB analysis, conducted by the Wolfson Unit at Southampton, found that with the keel raised and no sails set, the yacht became vulnerable to capsizing in winds exceeding 60 knots—a threshold crossed in seconds when the downburst struck. The other yachts in the same series as the Bayesian had two masts, not one. This problem might have been noticed earlier except for one other factor: Elite luxury yachts don’t have to comply with the same robust safety rules as commercial ones. The International Safety Management Code is voluntary for boats registered for private use.</blockquote>
I may have skipped some of the sections about corporate bag-slinging. The yacht disaster is interesting though.

<h2><a href="https://www.noemamag.com/the-last-days-of-social-media/">The Last Days Of Social Media</a></h2>
<blockquote>Social media’s current logic is designed to reduce friction, to give users infinite content for instant gratification, or at the very least, the anticipation of such. The antidote to this compulsive, numbing overload will be found in deliberative friction, design patterns that introduce pause and reflection into digital interaction, or platforms and algorithms that create space for intention.</blockquote>
It hasn't gone unnoticed that I could consume the ever-swelling number of articles on this subject for far too long. And the perceived benefit of reading and recirculating them remains questionable.<br /><br />

This article does go into some interesting depth as to a possible new future of decentralised web development. And it also reminded me to check back up on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solid_(web_decentralization_project)">Solid project</a> led by a certain Tim Berners-Lee.

<h2><a href="https://english.elpais.com/international/2025-09-14/the-gentrification-of-mexican-wrestling.html">The gentrification of Mexican wrestling</a></h2>
<blockquote>Seven years ago, the Mexican Wrestling Council (CMLL) managed to have its sport declared an intangible cultural heritage of Mexico City, which turned it into a tourist attraction. Ernesto Ocampo, editor-in-chief of the specialized portal Superluchas, explains that lucha libre emerged as entertainment for the lower classes in neighborhoods where there were no cinemas or theaters, but that today it is recognized as a national symbol “on a par with mariachi or tequila.”</blockquote>
Lucha Libre is enormously encoded in Mexican culture, in a way that isn't reflected in its presentation to international audiences. The incorporation of the (Lucha Libre) AAA brand into (USA) WWE this year has already resulted in a watering-down and ironing-out of the sport's core. This is also seen somewhat in the collaboration between (Lucha Libre) CMLL and (USA) AEW.<br /><br />

WWE and AEW stars will make appearances in Lucha Libre events<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>, and the style of wrestling will shape itself to show off the skill of the visiting star. CMLL and AAA stars will also attend USA-based events, but their finesse is muted.<br /><br />

The larger entity inevitably consumes the smaller one, forcing it to fit within its mould. Many such cases.

<h2><a href="https://english.elpais.com/technology/2025-09-13/never-steal-a-hackers-girlfriends-phone-how-an-expert-exposed-a-global-network-of-thieves.html">Never steal a hacker’s girlfriend’s phone: How an expert exposed a global network of thieves</a></h2>
<blockquote>But there are cities in China where that IMEI can be changed, says Vigo. “It’s the hardest part, when it arrives in China and they change certain components and the IMEI. It requires a certain level of sophistication: opening the phone, changing the chip... you have to know what you’re doing because Apple detects if there are non-original components.” The goal is to be able to resell the stolen phone with a different IMEI so that it can’t be traced.</blockquote>
Interesting evidence here to show that the security on modern phones is rather impressive, when criminals often go to these lengths.<br /><br />

It also exposes, once again, that the end user remains the most vulnerable area of an attack surface.

<h2><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/future/article/20250911-the-people-who-hunt-down-old-tvs">'You just can't recreate that glow': The people who hunt old TVs</a></h2>
<blockquote>Byron McDanold is one of the moderators for a Facebook group called The CRT Collective, which at the time of writing has more than 240,000 members. McDanold says that CRT technology has appealing quirks that are impossible to replicate with other technology. "You push the button on the front and it makes that zap, pop noise as it turns on," he says. He argues that many CRT hunters are on an epic quest to recreate specific memories or feelings from their childhoods – they end up obsessing over picture quality in their pursuit of the past.</blockquote>


<h2><a href="https://erysdren.me/blog/2025-08-16/">If you love it, download it</a></h2>
<blockquote>I have written a few short guides and notes about ways you can help contribute to media preservation by doing it your damn self. Most of the guides lean very technical, but I try to give appropriate explanations and links to the tools and documentation where I can.<br /><br /></blockquote>
Despite reassurances from other sites that I have almost certainly seen this somewhere before, I had not in fact seen this somewhere before. Neat little guide for preserving various forms of media. 

<h2><a href="https://daniel.lawrence.lu/blog/y2025m09d21/#s1">Line scan camera image processing</a></h2>
<blockquote>Line scan cameras are very suitable for capturing trains, since I can capture the full length of the train with minimal perspective distortion. This is super nice for train nerds who want to make models of the trains. Also, as you keep the camera running, you can get incredibly high resolution photos that span over 100,000 pixels wide.<br /><br /></blockquote>
A fascinating look at how line scan cameras operate and how they're utilised. Some of the technical aspects did go over my head though.


<h2><a href="https://wordsmith.social/elilla/deep-in-mordor-where-the-shadows-lie-dystopian-stories-of-my-time-as-a-googler">Deep in Mordor where the shadows lie: Dystopian tales of that time when I sold out to Google</a></h2>
<blockquote>I will be honest and say that most of my fellow programmers ate that shit up, we had all been gold-star kids and here was the hottest company in the world constantly massaging our egos, telling us we were better than everyone for being geniuses. I would have loved to feel the same, I tried to feel the same, but I came from poverty and I could not stop noticing the precariat: temps, part-timers, and contractors, an entire layer of the company who did the brunt of work without being Googlers. No toy budget for kitchen staff.<br /><br />

It's the little things that bugged me, how people would eat the free candy or have a bowl of cereal and just leave trash and dirty dishes everywhere for the cleaning ladies (contractors) to deal with; more than that the way nobody looked at them or said “thank you”. We Brazilians have a social class for that, a social code underlying that studied invisibility, I knew what this was: these were maids. Servants. The women in my family, my friends at school. The “campus” was pretty open and my then-wife visited it a few times; it creeped the Fuck out of her, the distinction between people and non-people.<br /><br /></blockquote>
I've visited Big Tech main headquarters a few times. In the shadow of the Olympic-sized swimming pool, the cleaning staff never spoke.<br /><br />

Otherwise this article offers another interesting view on life within Big Tech, with a perspective of someone from the "Global South". The perk-slinging days of the 2010s must have stung even harder with the author's background.


<p><h1>Light Reads</h1></p>

<h2><a href="https://hard-drive.net/hd/video-games/every-pikmin-type-ranked-by-how-much-i-had-to-pay-an-exterminator-to-get-them-out-of-my-kitchen/">Every Pikmin Type Ranked by How Much I Had to Pay an Exterminator to Get Them Out of My Kitchen</a></h2>
I have never played a Pikmin game, but enjoy the thought of oppressing these silly little dudes.

<h2><a href="https://bogdanthegeek.github.io/blog/projects/vapeserver/">Hosting a WebSite on a Disposable Vape</a></h2>
<blockquote>Over the past year I have collected quite a few of these PY32 based vapes, all of them from different models of vape from the same manufacturer. It’s not my place to do free advertising for big tobacco, so I won’t mention the brand I got it from, but if anyone who worked on designing them reads this, thanks for labeling the debug pins!</blockquote>
<a href="http://ewaste.fka.wtf/">Here</a> is the direct link to the vape-hosted site. Took about 20 seconds to load for me. Pretty neat!

<h2><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Unusual_articles">Wikipedia: Unusual Articles</a></h2>
I think it'd be cheating if I posted one of these articles on every single What I'm Reading post. So here you go.

<h2><a href="https://www.presentandcorrect.com/blogs/blog/david-walkers-paper-clip-collection">David Walker's Paper Clip Collection</a></h2>
It's exactly what you think it is.


<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>Or Lucha Libre-styled events, and there is a significant difference.<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>

    </ol>
</div>

<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</p></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Previous iterations: Volume 1 Volume 2 Volume 3 Volume 4]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An Infinite Set of Lines Going Up</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/09/An-Infinite-Set-of-Lines-Going-Up(2).html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Infinite Set of Lines Going Up" /><published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/10/09/An-Infinite-Set-of-Lines-Going-Up(2)</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/09/An-Infinite-Set-of-Lines-Going-Up(2).html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
There is no clear threshold for when we've gone too far. It varies per person, per entity, per company, per nation. The consequences are never clear and understandable. Yet we are already in the middle of them after so little time, and I strongly fear it will get worse.<br /><br />

I refuse to call any product or technology "AI". It is neither artificial nor intelligent. What you see, and maybe interact with, is little more than a token prediction model. Rather good ones, mind you. The libraries of data they pull from are immense - and, of course, stolen. Not that it will ever be proven.<br /><br />

No leap forward in efficiency for these programs has fundamentally altered the notion that they simply predict the most likely token to appear next in a sequence. You can see this with ChatGPT or Gemini replying to your query. It starts a sentence with no idea how to end it. I can think of people in real life who also act like this, and they're barely preferable.<br /><br />

But can you avoid it? The ability decreases on the daily. You might be able to avoid direct use of it, avoiding outsourcing your own thought processes to a machine, but what about when decisions are made for you? When you argue with a "chatbot" on your medical provider's shitty app, sending you in endless loops with no intention of giving you what you need, do you have a choice any more? When your work demands it be embedded in every process, what else can you do?<br /><br />

I have seen the inside of one of the Large Language Models that increasingly powers website backends, servers, chatbots, and far more serious things. It is held together with spit and prayers. And the amount of people who truly understand how it works is pitiful. I am not one of them. But I do understand that our future of living is being outsourced to an opaque incomprehensible entity, completely without consent.

<h2>On "Intelligence"</h2>
Sure I can say that "AI" isn't very artificial nor intelligent. But why? The output is often very verbose and detailed.<br /><br />

The chatbots you might know of - ChatGPT, Gemini, CoPilot, Claude - are all Large Language Models at heart. They draw from an absurdly large reservoir of data to answer every query that comes into it. They are tailored to read and speak in natural language terms: the user types a question as they might to a friend, and the LLM responds in a clear, understandable format. This has been fundamental to the surge in popularity of LLMs. The average user does not know what prompt engineering is, never mind have any desire to utilise it. They want an answer with minimal effort. LLMs are perfectly poised to deliver this.<br /><br />

For example, you ask ChatGPT to draft an email for you. The LLM will analyse your query, identify important words that correspond with keywords in its data banks, then search those data banks for correlated words and phrases. It then assembles these correlated words and phrases into a readable format, and spits it back to the user.<br /><br />

This is a ludicrously simple breakdown. Every single stage of the LLM is fiendishly complex, and it grows in difficulty the more fundamentally simple the question is. Mathematical equations that span the length of a country are easier to answer than a single philosophical question<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>.<br /><br /> 

One of my favourite examples of phrasing this is: You can get a machine to analyse 10,000 pictures, and pick out ones based on colours fairly easily. A digital picture is comprised of code, so the machine can look at the data and pick out similarities within a certain range. But then you ask the machine to "identify all pictures with a bird in them". <b>How do you teach a machine what a bird is?</b><br /><br />

The only viable solution as of 2025 is to feed that machine thousands, millions, billions of pictures and descriptions of birds. An utterly overwhelming amount of examples to drill it home into that silicon shell. So when you give the machine a picture of a bird, there's enough pixel patterns that match with its data banks that makes the machine decide that it's a reasonably accurate match. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decision_tree">decision tree</a> for LLMs to determine this is on an astronomical scale, one that no individual could ever pick apart.<br /><br />

How similar is this to the human brain? We have no idea. There could be chemical reaction in our synapses that moves in an inate way we simply can't comprehend. Or maybe the billions of neurons work in a concerningly similar manner to a decision tree. "AI" manufacturers are banking on the latter.<br /><br />

Anything that is inherently created in binary data, like mathematics or programming, stands to gain the most from LLMs. Their existence is not affected by being fed into one. To convert anything else into data, you implicitly lose an aspect of it. A text message does not convey all of the emotion behind it. A picture does not fully represent the wonderful experience leading to it. These are our attempts to snapshot and hold onto our fundamental thoughts and being, understandable only to us. When you feed these into an LLM, it does not understand, and the output always reflects this.<br /><br />

Programming genuises built LLMs on top of decades of work in neurobiology, neural networks, and deep learning. They should be lauded for their work, as it is fundamentally incredible. But we must draw a line between the definition of these creations, and the wholly separate world of human thinking.<br /><br /> 

I am blunt in my opinion that use of LLMs is little more than outsourcing your thinking. You can use it like a calculator, and it may not fundamentally differ too much from a physical one. When you ask it to create a shopping list, create recipe ideas, think of birthday present ideas, write a letter, you are sacrificing a part of yourself. To an entity that does not think like you do. Because it does not think.

<h2>The Future is Here (TBC)</h2>
A tool is nothing without hands to hold it. As powerful as a LLM might be, what it's applied to is of far greater concern than how it currently functions.<br /><br />

My hypothetical workplace is an interesting example of this. If I were to ever work in such a company, I might describe it as a gargantuan entity, reaching its growing tendrils into every facet of human life with every passing day. An entity that has amassed such power that it has totally thrown away the pretence of not doing evil, happy to stand with every vile being you could imagine, for the right price. A googolplex of malice.<br /><br />

Such a company would be built on decades of experience, talent, and hard work. Despite its best efforts, not all is smooth in a trillion-dollar beast: chains of command are inefficient and cumbersome, data is often siloed, unclear, and contradictory, and the vast quantity of moving parts makes it difficult to figure out what direction it's headed in. Nevertheless you might respect how it grew to its current position.<br /><br />

Imagine a presentation is sent around to the entire company one day. Copious slides of information, singing the praises of <a href="https://x.com/karpathy/status/1886192184808149383">"vibe coding"</a>. Look at how many uses it has in our daily work, the presentation proclaims!<br /><br />

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/ai-1.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Death 🙏</figcaption>
</figure>

Don't review the code changes, just feed it into the LLM and see what it says! Ask the LLM to review that document! Get AI to generate code, and push that shit into prod! Fix it later! With the LLM!<br /><br />

The LLM would be pushed deep into every service and product, both internal and external. Your widget has to have an LLM element now. Also why isn't it internally running on the LLM? Why did you make your own code for this?<br /><br />

This would give rise to the worst breed of imbecile. Someone who's probably intelligent in other ways, I'm sure, but you just wouldn't see it. This person's job is to "drive things forward". They must speak first on the call, wrap up proceedings on their schedule, and provide their opinion on every single matter. LLMs have turbocharged this brand of yappertron.<br /><br />

Imagine you are drafting a hundred lines of code for a future task. Before it's even completed, the yappertron, who's job has no relation to this, sends around an LLM-created summary of what your code does, including your managers, and provides their opinions on said LLM summary. They might also ask you to "check" the LLM summary for them<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[2]</a></sup>.<br /><br />

A leaderboard would be set up to see who submitted the most code involving "vibe coding". Security and best practice would go out the window. Envision a meeting where you are flat-out told that we can expedite a project timeline by foisting work on LLMs, submit the completed metrics to management, then "correct" them later if there's any issues. Whatever the LLM prescribes, implement that in prod. Don't worry about the LLM having no concept of data security, or data retention policies, or data privacy. Or local laws and regulations. That's not pertinent to the task at hand.<br /><br />

The classic phrase to describe this might be "move fast and break things". Large technology companies have often utilised this, it's not a new concept. LLMs simply provide a new unrivaled speed at which to do this.<br /><br />

I have no doubt where the future of such a workplace leads. Unconstrained LLMs will not make your work easier - they will set the new speed at which your work will be demanded, of which there will always be more. Plus the additional work of fixing stuff that the LLM inadvertently broke. Whatever skills you used to bring are now firmly secondary.<br /><br />

I was once brought aside in my totally separate workplace, and told that our executives had decided on a target of 30% growth rate. On every department, on every core metric (revenue, profit, user growth, etc), every year. How they reached that figure was never explained. It was simply decided, then it was so. Here is the result.

<h2>Disconnection</h2>

It's hard to maintain a level of knowledge to stay aware of this nonsense, and also stay sane. Similar to relentless negativity in the media, you can only detach yourself so much when you're living in the middle of it.<br /><br />

The pervasion of technology into our lives has been relentless. I'm strongly confident that it has broached the point of usefulness, and now actively impedes us. What do you stand to gain from another app on your phone?<br /><br />

As our lives grow ever-busier without purpose, the demand on technology to invent a solution grows stronger. I've seen friends on chatbot apps, slightly-more-raunchy chatbot apps, very-raunchy chatbot apps. Funny as it was in the first few days, the dawning realisation that their socialising was ever-increasingly dependent upon a machine was horrifying.<br /><br />

The ability to step back from this void grows increasingly difficult. My parents would often remind me that they would socialise via heading into the city centre, to the "old reliable spots", and running into whoever they ran into. How many of us are accessible this way now?<br /><br />

Being in the circles I'm in, even moreso than my distrust of technology, has been the catalyst for me to rebase my life centred around local communities. Yet the organisation of this still hinges on technology to hold it all together. The more you try to poke it, prod it, shift away from it, the more fragile it appears. 80% of my social life is dependent on Discord servers staying online.<br /><br />

When these services lean into LLMs with every update, it's tougher and tougher just to cling on.

<h2>The Secret Agenda</h2>
The truth is often stranger than fiction. But to wrap up this tirade, I don't have a grand conclusion. Sometimes the truth is drab and miserable.<br /><br />

There's money to be made here. Imagine a company forced to move at such breakneck speeds, complete so many Important Tasks every day, that the entire entity needed to be built and maintained with LLMs in mind. Imagine a solicitor who now doesn't have enough time to read through every page of a legal document, now that there's so much more to do. Imagine a doctor who, rather than providing their insight, relies increasingly on LLM output to reach a decision.<br /><br />

A company that provides such LLM services would have a wonderful stranglehold on the flow of information. The business competitive advantage would be immense - how could a fresh startup possibly hope to rival your LLM, when you've spent the last decade scraping and collating the entire Internet to use as a reference?<br /><br />

Venture capital investment throws itself at the nearest and loudest thing. Max risk, max reward is the name of the game. The Return on Investment is a fickle being, and must be sated with every offering at our feet. Imagine a game of bronze-ranked Rocket League where 6 cars blindly chase the ball without thought. It's not too dissimilar to that.<br /><br />

The capital demands a return. "AI" grabs headlines, attention, investment. Companies try to push boundaries to grow faster than their perceived rivals. All things you already knew.<br /><br />

In trying to find a solution to all this, my only finding was that there is no solution. To quote Abba Eban, men and nations behave wisely once they have exhausted all other alternatives.<br /><br />

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>Just like in real life.<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
        <p>The hypothetical recipient of this may be very tempted to get an LLM to review that summary and send it back.<a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>


</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is no clear threshold for when we've gone too far. It varies per person, per entity, per company, per nation. The consequences are never clear and understandable. Yet we are already in the middle of them after so little time, and I strongly fear it will get worse.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">THE LEGEND NEVER DIES</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/09/THE-LEGEND-NEVER-DIES.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="THE LEGEND NEVER DIES" /><published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/10/09/THE-LEGEND-NEVER-DIES</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/09/THE-LEGEND-NEVER-DIES.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
The year is 2012. Social media remains scattered. Youtube exists, but with massive restrictions on file size, length, and quality. Information is not centralised, and crucial information takes days or weeks to disseminate to a wider audience.<br /><br />

Gaming culture is, as it always has been, utter dogshit. Hatemail on Xbox Live remains at near-peak levels, and off in the recesses of Dark Souls 1 PvP, Games for Windows Live hosts an absolute shitshow of a community. Much like everywhere else.<br /><br />

Dark Souls, in its initial guise and still after the first few patches, horrendously unbalanced. Even up to 1.05, you could wear the heaviest tankiest armour in the game (<a href="https://darksouls.wiki.fextralife.com/Havel's+Set">Havel's Set</a>), yet still balance your stats to have a weight ratio of less than 50%, and therefore be able to ninjaflip (more invulnerability frames) with the <a href="https://darksouls.wiki.fextralife.com/Dark+wood+Grain+ring">Dark Wood Grain Ring</a>. This resulted in nigh-invincible rock men backflipping around until they stabbed you in the back with Darkmoon daggers for absurd damage. Because of the unpatched <a href="https://darksouls.wiki.fextralife.com/Hornet+Ring">Hornet Ring</a> of course. Nightmare material.<br /><br />

Patch 1.06 annihilated this meta, and with good reason. What still remained was the flavour of tryhard MLG bullshit that came in the form of hilariously bad hatemail, kill montages on youtube complete with awful music, and brain-dead herd mentality to follow the "meta".<br /><br />

The setting was perfect for OnlyAfro to unleash a weapon of absolute destruction on the Dark Souls and wider community. This <s>guy</s> <s>femboy</s> thing uploaded a parody of that style of tryhard dudebro nonsense, only to unleash an even more titanic wave of MLG terror:<br /><br />

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oyA8odjCzZ4?si=IwiTdSZUrItzyFUY" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe><br /><br />

It feels ridiculous to describe the impact this 180 second shitpost had. Those kinds of MLG-style montages turned into parodies overnight. /r/montageparodies owes most of its existence to this movement. Homodexuality remained a meme until Elden Ring released in 2022. Giantdad, not even a canonical character, is one of the most recognisable faces of Souls games. Half of the stylised words of this video materialised itself into the Souls community for years.<br /><br />

The slurs being patched out of the above video is strangely unfortunate. They're there as a parody, but there's little room for that level of irony on any level of the popular internet. Until Big Tech fully stops pretending to care of course.<br /><br />

Far funnier is the way little facts got rewritten over time. Giantdad was perceived as a "meta", but had no such impact outside of memes. Reading the swing of a Zweihander was mandatory to survive pre-1.06 patch, and didn't become any more difficult here. If you did get stunlocked, you could just toggle escape<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>.<br /><br />

Being a filthy tryhard at the time, I utilised the Giantdad build to wreck havoc in lower-level areas. By tweaking the build to operate at Level 11 instead of Level 99, I could swing the Bass Cannon at full power in the beginner areas, with the only downside being that I couldn't mid-roll. Not that you needed to, going up against someone thirty minutes into the game wielding a toothpick. This exploit took waves of attempts to fix - first in Dark Souls 2 using the dire <a href="https://darksouls.fandom.com/wiki/Soul_Memory">Soul Memory</a> mechanic, and later in Dark Souls 3 with the contentious <a href="https://darksouls3.wiki.fextralife.com/Summon+Range+Calculator">Weapon-Based Matchmaking</a>.<br /><br />

PvP was never the same after Dark Souls 1. It couldn't survive staying that way, mind you. But the outrageously unbalanced setup gave the community the tools to build weapons of mass destruction that ruined gaming for years (affectionate).<br /><br />

This post is an elaborate reminder for me to set up my shrine to Giantdad. Your understanding is appreciated.<br /><br />

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>Not that many knew this.<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>


</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The year is 2012. Social media remains scattered. Youtube exists, but with massive restrictions on file size, length, and quality. Information is not centralised, and crucial information takes days or weeks to disseminate to a wider audience.]]></summary></entry></feed>