<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-08-13T01:20:01+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/atom.xml</id><title type="html">Sandy’s Palace</title><subtitle>Caoimhe&apos;s gay little website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">6 Month Thoughts on Takumi</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/12/6-Month-Thoughts-on-Takumi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="6 Month Thoughts on Takumi" /><published>2025-08-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/12/6-Month-Thoughts-on-Takumi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/12/6-Month-Thoughts-on-Takumi.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
<a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/03/09/Say-Hi-To-Takumi-The-Toyota-GT86.html">Takumi</a> was bought 6 months ago, integrated into Ireland with wallet-annihilating speed, and has been enjoying his new life (hopefully).<br /><br />

He grabs loads of attention still. The car scene in Ireland is dire. It's not just that nice cars are expensive - <i>everything</i> is expensive. So a modded GT86 is more of a head-turner than it has any right to be. This wouldn't even be worthy of a sniff in Britain.<br /><br />

The previous owner - a delight of a woman from everything I've heard - has covered most of the basics of modding. Aero kit is in good shape, Invidia N1 exhaust looks like the correct call, and the decals are cool without being over the top. With the engine at 100,000 miles, I don't want to strain it more than necessary, and probably won't try to push more power out of it. A supercharger sounds fun, as long as I could keep it switched off 95% of the time. And where's the fun in that?<br /><br />

The ride leans on the stiff side. Which is to be expected, but roads in Cork are an incredibly accurate simulation of the moon after cluster bomb strikes. So this is my main area of focus. Fully adjustable suspension, in particular being able to adjust spring stiffness, would be amazing. This is a €1,000+ job though. Gotta sort out other life stuff before this.<br /><br />

Tyres are good, as Michelin Pilot Sport 5's would be, apart from the bit where Sandy uses them to sharpen his claws. No I don't plan on doing anything about this.<br /><br />

I've scratched the wheels a few times which is frustrating, especially as the base paint underneath is orange and looks terrible when exposed. Parallel parking is very prominent where I live, so this may continue to be an issue.<br /><br />

Fuel consumption is pretty poor in-town, which annoyingly is where most of my driving is located. I haven't let Takumi stretch his legs as much as he'd like. Even when good roads do exist, they're populated by tractors, campervans, and old people who got their license in 1968 down the bottom of a cereal box. I may end up just taking a ferry to Wales. Or France maybe. Particularly if I learn how to solo camp...<br /><br />

Getting the approval of bikers is my big thing. I got some revs of approval from a Kawasaki rider a few weeks back and am still glowing from that. Also got an earful of throttle from a modded Audi RS6, which considering that thing is a nuclear power plant on wheels, is a nice motivator! Plus the kids who ask me to rev it are still great.<br /><br />

Unsure will I take it to Mondello Park, as I've already been there twice and might enjoy learning a new track this time. Anglesey in Wales is right next to Holyhead and looks gorgeous, so that's the next goal!<br /><br />

Edit: what the fuck do you mean the ferry is more expensive than the entire track day

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Takumi was bought 6 months ago, integrated into Ireland with wallet-annihilating speed, and has been enjoying his new life (hopefully).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Virtuous Mechsploitation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/12/Virtuous-Mechsploitation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Virtuous Mechsploitation" /><published>2025-08-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/12/Virtuous-Mechsploitation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/12/Virtuous-Mechsploitation.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
If you recognise the title and are currently in a cold sweat, don't worry I won't go all out. Yet.<br /><br />

---<br /><br />

Armored Core 6 arrived at an interesting time. Fans of a gritty corporate-war mech series found themselves rubbing shoulders with lesbians freshly giddy from watching Gundam: The Witch From Mercury. The partnership between these two factions has been... interesting.<br /><br />

In hindsight, the first trailer containing the words <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SlSfr6Wa5sc">"wake the dog up"</a> was an obvious flag. Then 621 getting ordered around by "Handler" Walter, with a gruff voice born of gravel getting run through a blender, set people off like nothing else before it. Later in the game, it leans directly into mind control plot lines. I wonder if the writers knew how it would all be received. Or maybe they were finally let loose.<br /><br />

What's followed since AC6 melded all this together is a fresh fanfic genre of a lovely diverse range of people getting hurled into scenarios of control (physical and mental), brainwashing, petplay, delightfully unhealthy relationships, containing lots of trans girlies. All enshrouded by the cold heartless shell of a mech they've been forced into. <a href="https://archiveofourown.org/tags/Mechsploitation">Fascinating stuff, really.</a><br /><br />

Unfortunately the unhealthy relationship stuff doesn't sit well with me. So I've been thinking instead about the coolness of mechs, the appeal of having one's humanity augmented and/or stripped away, and how this interacts with other people.<br /><br />

I adore technology at its hardware heart: cold metal that simply does what it does, and nothing more. You know why a mechanical watch moves, how an engine performs, how a lightbulb glows. They know their place, and I love them for it<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>.<br /><br />

Technology should not think, that's what we're here for. The second metal thinks it knows better than you, intentionally or not, is where it all falls apart. Whether it's software designed for a different purpose than what you want, malicious code, or just plain bad design, the roles begin to shift. Metal is power, not control - that's your job.<br /><br />

This clashes badly with most mech fiction. Normally the mech is a tool of control via another entity - a human controller or corporation maybe. But what if it's a symbol of individual power? I like how <a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/05/26/Heaven-Will-Be-Mine.html">Heaven Will Be Mine</a> captures this. The Ship-Selves are first and foremost an extension of their pilots, beyond even their physical forms. They live and fight on a tier of existence that humans could only dream of. They merely exist in ways never before possible.<br /><br />

The human element must reign supreme and free. Even when enshrouded in metal, even with orders being barked into their ear, even with the elements trying to wipe them out.<br /><br />

"I bet you're thinking of an F1 clip-" you're damn right I am. Behold the final five laps of the 2021 Russian Grand Prix from Max Verstappen's perspective. If you're expecting something dramatic, it doesn't happen. Max's engineer, Gianpiero Lambiase, is on top of every event before it's in front of his pilot's eyes. He makes the perfectly-timed call to switch to wet weather tyres on a track that's half dry, half soaked, and getting more volatile every lap. Gianpiero, with the crispest of voices, gives Max every bit of information he needs, and not a thing more, knowing with full confidence that Max can sweep aside everything in his way.<br /><br />

(The below embed likely won't work without watching it on youtube, still trying to figure out fixes to this)<br /><br />

<iframe title="Max Verstappen's Final Five Laps in Sochi | 2021 Russian Grand Prix" width="660" height="371" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/m0eASI6N6vE?si=mraCk8F7FVWDYa1G" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe><br /><br />

Max makes it look easy, and carves up other elite pilots for breakfast. What powers it all is the confidence in every word said between them: no second-guessing, no doubt as to the thought put into them. The human element is simultaneously drowned out by mechanical whines, and the most powerful thing there is.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup><br /><br />

Outside of still-niche VNs, this concept doesn't seem to have much sway with the masses. Yet the concept of trust and love conquering all is a huge undeniable trope, I'm just applying it to massive hunks of metal that can crush your enemies. Y'know, normal kink stuff.

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>Yes this is hot to me<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>
</p>

<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you recognise the title and are currently in a cold sweat, don't worry I won't go all out. Yet.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WPlace Shitposting General</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/11/WPlace-Shitposting-General.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WPlace Shitposting General" /><published>2025-08-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/11/WPlace-Shitposting-General</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/11/WPlace-Shitposting-General.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
If you're not familiar, <a href="https://wplace.live/">WPlace</a> is a collaborative pixel art canvas of sorts, utilising OpenStreetMap and MapLibre for a rather joyful 2025 internet experience. Alternatively, it's the hottest place to shitpost right now.<br /><br />

The servers work approx. 4% of the time, which is charming for now. This will tire out a lot of the freshly enthusiastic crowd that have joined recently, but I'm sure scaling up the servers would be stupidly expensive for such a silly little (affectionate) site.<br /><br />

It is reminiscent of many more delightful websites that no longer exist. Existing not for profit, just for fun. Seeing your home city lit up with flags, artwork, and love is quite touching.<br /><br />

I've been painting, cleaning, and maintaining pride flags in my home city, helping a friend paint her cool custom Pokemon trainer sprite, creating a big sign that tells everyone where my cats live, and planting a little surprise for my online friend in her hometown (Hi Brigid &lt;3).<br /><br />

Though it does expose the fact that art and creativity have never been my strong suit. For every living second in school, my mind would lock up when given any open-plan "write/draw whatever you like" task, then I'd inevitably get shouted at for it. This builds up into me clutching to certainty and security a little bit too much. An open canvas is still scary in a sense.<br /><br />

As much as I like painting big trans-coloured love hearts where my friends might find them, something a bit more individual might be neat. I briefly toyed with sprite creators and assist tools before hitting another creative wall that I've never figured out how to break through. This also ties into creativitiy issues when it comes to this site, and my life and hobbies in general.<br /><br />

Much like relearning Irish, some kind of fundamental restart is needed. 

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/wplace-1.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Rio di Janeiro</figcaption>
</figure>

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/wplace-2.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">[Drone Strike]</figcaption>
</figure>

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're not familiar, WPlace is a collaborative pixel art canvas of sorts, utilising OpenStreetMap and MapLibre for a rather joyful 2025 internet experience. Alternatively, it's the hottest place to shitpost right now.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Small Site Updates</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/10/Small-Site-Updates.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Small Site Updates" /><published>2025-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/10/Small-Site-Updates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/10/Small-Site-Updates.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
<ul>
    <li>A quick check showed that Sandy's Palace was consuming 404kB of data transfer on page load. This is shocking, unacceptable, and appalling. To avoid being cubed by the Javascript-hating mob I foolishly created in my head, this needs to go down. I've culled it to below 300kB with some easy changes, unfortunately <a href="https://sneil.neocities.org/">Nora's</a> very cute 88x31 gif now takes up a third of the page size. This will be tolerated :3</li>
    <li>Made the first new additions to the Cool Site buttons this year. Very much enjoyed looking through these sites. Plenty more to come.</li>
    <li>Considered updating my 88x31, then decided against it. It's funnier the more basic it is. Unless I can figure out how to animate 88x31 gifs, then I'm unstoppable (someone please show me how to do this)</li>
    <li>Deliberated randomising the Cool Site button order, then decided to keep it mostly ordered in terms of people I know first. Also couldn't be arsed engineering that one without using Javascript. Don't know that many people IRL with blogs, gotta work on that</li>
</ul>
Still considering should I post about projects that are identifiable to me IRL. Will err on the side of caution, though it'd be nice to have more links on the home page. 
</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A quick check showed that Sandy's Palace was consuming 404kB of data transfer on page load. This is shocking, unacceptable, and appalling. To avoid being cubed by the Javascript-hating mob I foolishly created in my head, this needs to go down. I've culled it to below 300kB with some easy changes, unfortunately Nora's very cute 88x31 gif now takes up a third of the page size. This will be tolerated :3 Made the first new additions to the Cool Site buttons this year. Very much enjoyed looking through these sites. Plenty more to come. Considered updating my 88x31, then decided against it. It's funnier the more basic it is. Unless I can figure out how to animate 88x31 gifs, then I'm unstoppable (someone please show me how to do this) Deliberated randomising the Cool Site button order, then decided to keep it mostly ordered in terms of people I know first. Also couldn't be arsed engineering that one without using Javascript. Don't know that many people IRL with blogs, gotta work on that Still considering should I post about projects that are identifiable to me IRL. Will err on the side of caution, though it'd be nice to have more links on the home page.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Do I Webring</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/09/How-Do-I-Webring.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Do I Webring" /><published>2025-08-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/09/How-Do-I-Webring</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/09/How-Do-I-Webring.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
I'm finally moving beyond repetitive thoughts on improving Sandy's Palace's homepage.<br /><br />

Fundamentally it's fine - I like straightforward. And it stays true to my goal of minimal bullshit, and only things that I want. Some silly one-liners, blog summary, links to RSS, links to cool stuff, all working ok.<br /><br />

The list of other cool sites isn't great. I populated it once when building the site in late-2024, added two buttons for people I found via another friend's site, then one from a friend I knew IRL, then just kinda stopped. Not that I don't enjoy travsering people's silly little blogs, but mentally the energy wasn't there.<br /><br />

So I am making a concerted push to trawl through more blogs - primarily for entertainment, and secondarily to add more cool things to my webring. I think that'd be more sustainable. Maybe hardcap myself at 5 blogs per session, and actually delve into them, rather than surface-level aesthetic comparison.<br /><br />

I'm familiar with the <a href="https://cohost-highway.neocities.org/webring">Cohost Highway</a>, a continuation of the wonderful spirit of Cohost that I was tantalisingly close to but never fully committed to. But I would love to discover other curated webrings and build up my enthusiasm again.<br /><br />

I was gonna wrap up this post with a joke, then noticed that one of my friends changed their name and I'm too excited about this to think straight ok bye

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm finally moving beyond repetitive thoughts on improving Sandy's Palace's homepage.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Babygirl Moments Unlimited</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/08/Babygirl-Moments-Unlimited.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Babygirl Moments Unlimited" /><published>2025-08-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/08/Babygirl-Moments-Unlimited</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/08/Babygirl-Moments-Unlimited.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
I enjoy giggling and teeheeheeing a normal amount. It gets far funnier the more egregious the context is.<br /><br />

I also enjoy Formula 1 a normal amount, and of the many things that have accumulated in my mind is the enjoymemt of elite sportspeople being delightfully silly. Fernando Alonso is the definition of this, bending the rules and outright breaking them for twenty-plus years, with the most babygirl expression on his face as he pretends he had no idea about the plan to stage a deliberate crash.<br /><br /> 

One of my favourite moments comes from 1999. British American Tobacco had poured millions into their new child, complete with a star-studded driver lineup, engineers purchased from across the world, and swathes of flashy sponsors. Unfortunately they didn't account for their two drivers engaging in a bet to see who could tackle a steep 250kph+ corner at full throttle.

<p>
    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/teehee-1.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;"></figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>
<p>

Millions of dollars ruined, a race weekend thrown out the window, and all but egos unharmed. I think Jock Clear at the end summarises the mood best.<br /><br />

Moving on to a man who has defined F1 rulebooks to the extent that they've had to invent multiple new ones just to stop his bullshit. Michael Schumacher, in the middle of a furiously competitive qualifying session at Monaco, had a bright idea mid-lap as to how to ruin his opponent's final attempt to dethrone him. The most enjoyable bit is observing how bad he is at acting bad. The Italian hand gestures, and stalling despite his left hand clearly on the brake bias dial rather than the clutch, is icing on the cake.<br /><br />

<p>
    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/teehee-2.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;"></figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>
<p>

The driver impeded at the end of the clip? Fernando Alonso. Wonder where he got it from later in life.<br /><br />

Anyways this shit makes me giggle and I am committing to submerging you all in inane content until I'm satisfied :3

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</p></p></p></p></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I enjoy giggling and teeheeheeing a normal amount. It gets far funnier the more egregious the context is.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My-Dream-Supermarket-V2FINAL.txt</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/08/My-Dream-Supermarket-V2FINAL.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My-Dream-Supermarket-V2FINAL.txt" /><published>2025-08-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/08/My-Dream-Supermarket-V2FINAL</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/08/My-Dream-Supermarket-V2FINAL.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
I am afflicted with a deadly illness that has ruined my life. It's called Walking At A Normal Fucking Speed and cripples my ability to function in society.<br /><br />

I claim to minimise my time in public spaces because of loud noise, overstimulation, overheating, and health concerns. Truthfully it's because me getting stuck behind a three-child pram for more than a microsecond results in authoritarian thoughts of cubing everyone who stands in my way.<br /><br /> 

People who sprint across the road just to screech to a halt in front of me and stare at their phone deserve nothing more than forced labour camps. Able-bodied people who move at the pace of tectonic plates shall be given exoskeletons that I remotely control to forcibly speed them up on footpaths.<br /><br />

(This is all far funnier when you consider I'm 5ft 6" and my left leg is two inches shorter than my right)<br /><br />

Supermarkets are the worst for all of these combined. Why I haven't moved to online deliveries and click-and-collect ranges from excuses such as "I want an excuse to drive Takumi" to "Tesco gave me the wrong type of tomato and now I'm considering domestic terrorism."<br /><br />

Dunnes is hell on earth. It has everything in stock, meaning the large food shops are done here, meaning the bills are often €200+, then the arguing over vouchers is excruciating. Dante Alighieri did not envision a middle-aged mother forcing the entire queue to shuffle out of her way three separate times for her to stare at chocolate bars to push her bill up to a certain amount such that her vouchers covered more, only to realise she miscalculated the amounts, proceeding to argue with the cashier over price labels, then finding half her vouchers were different to what she thought, THEN loading her shopping into the trolley for the subsequent five minutes. But if he did, Inferno would have ten circles.<br /><br />

SuperValu is a nursing home. I am not attuned to John-and-Mary culture at the best of times, but visiting here could be a documentary. Also the car park is a war zone fought by tortoises.<br /><br />

Tesco operates one human-staffed till, and five morbillion self-checkouts visited entirely by cataconic dudebros. Also I refuse on principle to get a Clubcard to get the actual prices.<br /><br />

Aldi and moreso Lidl should be more to my taste. I meet the cashier's eye, they challenge me to a duel, then proceed to sling my shopping at lightning speeds through the register while I make a mediocre attempt to keep up. A brief sniff of victory is all they display. Which is great fun, but neither of them have good fish. Or vegetables. Or snacks. Or spices.<br /><br />

And here rests my problem. I desire a supermarket designed from scratch for people who know what they're getting, get the thing, pay for the thing, then evaporate into mist. With aisles curated for the actual separation of food types, not forcing the essential stuff into alternating corners of the warehouse. Alas no overpaid executive sees my vision.<br /><br /> 

In completely unrelated news, I scored full marks on an autism assessment for the first time in that psychiatrist's career. Please clap.

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am afflicted with a deadly illness that has ruined my life. It's called Walking At A Normal Fucking Speed and cripples my ability to function in society.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">K_____</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/07/K_____.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="K_____" /><published>2025-08-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/07/K_____</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/07/K_____.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
I am a huge fan of characters that don't speak very much or at all. This may not come as a huge surprise.<br /><br />

Even better when they can hold their own, without any compromises to their character or what they're trying to achieve. There is motivation here for me that outstrips pretty much anything else a piece of media could say.<br /><br />

Kimiko from the TV show The Boys has been a treat to watch. There is clear reason in her silence, which adds to her character rather than detracts or constrains it. Also she's cute when she rips people's heads off :3 <br /><br />

Moving to, as my friend has ungenerously put it before, a show for babies: Miraculous Ladybug has Kagami whom I attune with a very normal amount. She does talk, but only when necessary and saying only what's needed. Plenty of examples of this in media, I just stumbled upon this one and quite enjoy it.<br /><br />

This is where the trend ends for fictional characters whose names begin with K and are 6 characters long. I am very interested in continuing this mind you.<br /><br />

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/kimiko-1.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">:33333333</figcaption>
</figure>

Something about Komi from Komi-san Can't Communicate didn't click with me. It felt permanently like an attempt to be adorable to the ogling reader, before any point it tried to deliver.<br /><br />

Shōko Nishimiya	from Koe no Katachi wrecked me when I first watched it almost a decade ago. It's been too long to remember the subtleties, but it hits too close to home for me to call it my favourite rendition of this thought. Good film though.<br /><br />

A search online for mute characters pulled up Shizune Hakamichi, who comes from a time where I was shitposting on corners of the internet that I would rather erase. So that one's a bit cursed still. Also her route was SHIT<br /><br />

Chell, Doomguy, and Gordon Freeman all fit the bill, but I don't feel it as much with video game protagonists. Maybe there's this expectation that they don't <i>have</i> to speak in that type of media. I can't immediately think of nonverbal NPCs, though this would likely appeal to me far more.<br /><br />

Most words I speak are weighed down with unease, and the sense that I'm always a step behind what I'm <i>supposed</i> to say feels inescapable. The more casual the talk, the worse it becomes. I don't understand how anyone can reach deep into their decades of knowledge, pull out the exact silly media fact or quip required, and belt it out all in a microsecond. By the time I've stewed over a sentence long enough to trust it, we're talking about anarchist communes or some shit.<br /><br />

The thought of dropping it all feels nice. Even with the knowledge that I'd lose that necessary connection to people that's (mostly) required to get closer to them.<br /><br />

It remains unrealistic. I'd have to drop too much from my life to be able to continue with stability. So I watch these fictional little characters and squee with glee and envy.
</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am a huge fan of characters that don't speak very much or at all. This may not come as a huge surprise.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tachanka</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/02/Tachanka.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tachanka" /><published>2025-08-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/02/Tachanka</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/02/Tachanka.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
In 2015 I spent €120 on a laptop with the physical properties of a battering ram. Tachanka has served me for 10 glorious years, and he has finally been allowed to rest after much faithful service.<br /><br />

Tachanka the Thinkpad T410 has no outrageous tech specs to speak of. i5-520M, 2GB RAM, 250GB HDD, TFT LCD screen. Where he becomes outstanding is the way it's all put together. Everything is socketed, not soldered, into place. Virtually every component is hot-swappable, and a surprising proportion of them can be done while the machine is still running. A full magnesium shell shrouds the heart, still indestructible despite my best efforts.<br /><br />

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/tachanka-1.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">You wish your laptop was also a landline phone so bad it makes you look stupid</figcaption>
</figure>

Almost everything got upgraded, bar the CPU. Several years and some lost screws later, Tachanka was rocking 8GB RAM, 1TB of SSD storage, doubled battery capacity, and a lightweight Linux distro that gave zero fucks about raw processing power.<br /><br />

His drawback - massive weight - was also his party piece, as you could drop him on a table with zero disregard for the subsequent earthquake. Glass tables were for weaklings anyway.<br /><br />

The foolish masses never understood. Tachanka was the equivalent of a Mercedes Grosser, delightfully overengineered. Unfortunately my D&amp;D group did not appreciate my ability to reload the spare SATA slot like an AK-47:<br /><br />

<p>
    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/tachanka-1.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">This reload could have been done in 5 seconds if I wasn't frothing with rage</figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>
<p>

I used him as a daily driver far beyond his usual shelf life, having been manufactured in 2010 and running happily until 2023. However the troubles eventually began to pile up.<br /><br />

The keyboard had to be removed every time you needed to access the front of the motherboard, and the clips had loosened and weakened the corners. The screen's ability to rotate 180 degrees had worn out the hinges. The ability to charge him became inconsistent, and it dropped power on rare occasions.<br /><br />

The charging issue became so troublesome, I had to perform a few operations. The first, a full disassembly, attempted to find any loose wires or other easy fixes. No such luck of course. The second operation was an attempt to replace some core cables, strip the machine to its bare insides (hot), and try jump-starting it under various conditions.<br /><br />

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/tachanka-2.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">About halfway through the operation</figcaption>
</figure>

When it became clear that no accessory was causing problems, I resorted to changing the charging port and some electrical sections. No luck. Either I'd missed something, or the issue was on a main board that was discontinued over a decade ago.<br /><br />

With Tachanka already in a million pieces, I made the brave decision to keep the core components and scrap the rest. No modern machine uses a magnesium shell anyways.<br /><br />

I have no idea what to do with a BGA1288-socketed CPU. But if I thought of something cool, it might keep Tachanka still kicking in a sense. I have a drawer full of CPUs, maybe some weird art piece could work.

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</p></p></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2015 I spent €120 on a laptop with the physical properties of a battering ram. Tachanka has served me for 10 glorious years, and he has finally been allowed to rest after much faithful service.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">McIntyre Monday</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/30/McIntyre-Monday.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="McIntyre Monday" /><published>2025-07-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-07-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/30/McIntyre-Monday</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/30/McIntyre-Monday.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
April 7th, 2024. Wrestlemania 40, the opening act of Night 2. A 6ft buff Scotsman struts down the catwalk to the ring, through a saber arch with bagpipes blasting. I turn to my friend and remark that this is the dumbest shit I've ever seen, with a big smile on my face.<br /><br />

His opponent, another 6ft buff lad, continues his tradition of dressing himself by running through his wife's curtains. They kind of dropped this gimmick in 2025, unfortunately. I miss Mardi Gras Seth Rollins.<br /><br />

They pretend to kick the shit out of each other for 10 minutes, mostly by actually throwing each other around in increasingly wacky scenarios, with the Scotsman taking a brief break to send a tweet mid-match. <a href="https://x.com/dmcintyrewwe/status/1777114915678937236">Not a joke</a>.<br /><br />

Scotsman wins, before becoming the definition of hubris by mocking another rival in the commentary box to the extent that he gets beaten up for shits and giggles, before the Money In The Bank holder (winner of a silly match that gives the holder an instant no-questions-asked world championship match on demand) sprints into the ring, performs the world's quickest ass-kicking, steals the title off him and leaves. This proceeds to set off the biggest feud of 2024, containing several months of the most idiot babygirl promos, and three banger matches. It's funnier the less I explain.<br /><br />

This, and many other idiotic storylines, has confirmed to me the theory that professional wrestling is advanced drag. The wrestlers are playing complete caricatures, love to show off skin, are supremely talented in ways that aren't immediately obvious, and have extremely tacky soundtracks following them around. Prove me wrong.<br /><br />

The more indie you go, the sillier it gets. Turn to AEW for blood matches, storylines that revolve around being bald, and the single greatest kayfabe actor of all time (MJF). Turn to the national indies (in my case, OTT) for shouting "you fat bastard" at a ripped British dude while a big schmeaty Irish lad is doing a striptease to rapturous applause. We love and support Big Damo around here. Also there's a lad who's main gimmick is vaping in the middle of matches.<br /><br />

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/joshi-1.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Joshi wrestling is also delightfully stupid</figcaption>
</figure>

You can't force yourself to enjoy it, it's just utter nonsense that one day may or may not make sense. And it makes you look like a lunatic if you try to explain it. Hi btw &lt;3 <br /><br />

For almost a full year I carried the tradition of McIntyre Monday, a weekly celebration of why you the worshipper were so much better than everyone else. Drew was in the middle of his heel run and it just made sense. It made for strangely satisfying motivation. Also Drew (real name Andrew) is a real-life babygirl who goes to cat cafes and looks after all the women wrestlers when travelling and on nights out. Great dude to support.<br /><br />

The interest has dropped off a bit recently - WWE is having a poor run, and is politically rancid. AEW is picking itself up after a weak few months. OTT is only up in Dublin even if I'd like to go up maybe once a year. But it's still delightfully stupid and makes me laugh.<br /><br />

Happy McIntyre Monday bitches. No I don't care if it's Wednesday it's a state of mind you fool

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/drew-1.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">I'm not explaining shit.</figcaption>
</figure>


</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[April 7th, 2024. Wrestlemania 40, the opening act of Night 2. A 6ft buff Scotsman struts down the catwalk to the ring, through a saber arch with bagpipes blasting. I turn to my friend and remark that this is the dumbest shit I've ever seen, with a big smile on my face.]]></summary></entry></feed>