<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-09-01T11:26:23+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/atom.xml</id><title type="html">Sandy’s Palace</title><subtitle>Caoimhe&apos;s gay little website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Sandy Lane</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/01/Sandy-Lane.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sandy Lane" /><published>2025-09-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-09-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/09/01/Sandy-Lane</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/01/Sandy-Lane.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
It's been almost two years since I moved into my house. This used to be an area of severe insecurity for me, and the feeling never really leaves. So I'm quite pleased with how it turned out.<br /><br />

The house is named after Sandy<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>, naturally. I thought getting a place without a garden would upset him. So I turned down a tiny red-brick house closer to town<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[2]</a></sup>, and a terraced city-centre hideaway around the corner from my old flat<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[2]</a></sup>.<br /><br />

Instead I chose a "maturing" neighbourhood. In non-estate-agent terms, a former council housing estate that's less rough than even a decade ago. The upsides being that the garden's huge<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[3]</a></sup>, the price was manageable, and it has a driveway: an increasing rarity in modern builds. And I like Takumi too much :3 <br /><br />

The downside was that the previous owner left the place like shit. Even in the eight months between the viewing and moving in, the garden had become totally overgrown, interior was not cleaned once, and there were horrors perfectly within my comprehension buried in the back garden. Fuck you [REDACTED].<br /><br />

It's taken a stupid amount of time, effort, and money to get it fixed up to the extent where I can host people. But after the final big project, I think we're finally there.<br />

<h2>Kitchen</h2>

<div class="gallery-with-caption">
  <div class="image-gallery">
    <div class="expandable-image" id="sl-1">
      <a href="#sl-1">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-1.jpg" alt="Kitchen Before" />
      </a>
      <div class="expanded-view">
        <a href="#" class="close-button"></a>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-1.jpg" alt="Kitchen Before" />
        <div class="navigation">
          <a href="#sl-2" class="next-prev-button">Next Image</a>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="expandable-image" id="sl-2">
      <a href="#sl-2">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-2.jpg" alt="Kitchen After" />
      </a>
      <div class="expanded-view">
        <a href="#" class="close-button"></a>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-2.jpg" alt="Kitchen After" />
        <div class="navigation">
          <a href="#sl-1" class="next-prev-button">Previous Image</a>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>

  <p class="image-caption">
    Hey look I can make images expand on a click now! <sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[4]</a></sup>
  </p>
</div>

The kitchen was the first room I looked into when I opened the front door for the first time. The floor was coated in layers of dirt, mostly carried from outside, via the previous owner's moving crew who deposited half the garden soil around the house.<br /><br />

Pictures do not convey the level of dirt on everything: the cupboard doors, handles, inside of the oven, <b>everything</b>.

I ripped this bitch to shreds only last month, via the following steps:<br />
<ul>
  <li>Pulling the wall tiles off - this required re-plastering of the wall in certain areas. Not fully completed as the right-hand side of this room will have new tiles put on. Left side is to be scraped and painted.</li>
  <li>Tearing out the original ceiling, fully replastering it, with integrated lighting</li>
  <li>Annihilate the old appliances and furniture from existence, and install new Ikea furnishings. Ikea quality is fine, perfectly befitting of a small room that will hopefully be extended and retrofitted in another decade or two.</li>
  <li>Entirely new appliances across the board. Mostly Bosch apart from the fridge freezer cos that shit's pricey. Magnetic induction hob is a treat and I love it</li>
</ul>

There's also some strip lighting for the countertop which was a neat addition. Pretty sure I didn't request it but Ikea added it anyways. Decent spend of €100.

<h2>Bathroom</h2>

<div class="gallery-with-caption">
  <div class="image-gallery">
    <div class="expandable-image" id="sl-5">
      <a href="#sl-5">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-5.jpg" alt="Bathroom Before" />
      </a>
      <div class="expanded-view">
        <a href="#" class="close-button"></a>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-5.jpg" alt="Bathroom Before" />
        <div class="navigation">
          <a href="#sl-6" class="next-prev-button">Next Image</a>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="expandable-image" id="sl-6">
      <a href="#sl-6">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-6.jpg" alt="Bathroom After" />
      </a>
      <div class="expanded-view">
        <a href="#" class="close-button"></a>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-6.jpg" alt="Bathroom After" />
        <div class="navigation">
          <a href="#sl-5" class="next-prev-button">Previous Image</a>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
<p class="image-caption">Pretty sure no plumber will ever work with me again after I handed this project to them</p>
</div>

This was absolute hell to work on from start to finish. When there were contractors in to help with the floorboards, one of them later confessed to me "I nearly burst into tears".<br /><br />

The existing floor was comprised of destroyed lino, secured via chipboard that was glued directly onto the floorboards. Every single one of these elements was in dire condition. You might be able to pull the lino off the chipboard, but hammers, chisels, and power tools couldn't pull most of the chipboard off.<br /><br />

You may notice the wall tiles don't reach the floor. This is because some of the pipes were added afterwards, and the previous owner decided to just shove them into a section that wouldn't fit them. Also see the top corner where they inserted a pipe through the ceiling with the help of a cluster grenade.<br /><br />

Also the shower was falling apart and leaking directly onto the floor and through the floorboards.<br /><br />

Every single item in this room had to be brand new. There's some cheaper items (toilet and radiator are on the budget side) but everything else was pretty nice. The tiles ended up working out really well - big cream ones on the floor are easy to clean, and the blue for the shower was a bit of a gamble but worked out ok.<br /><br />

Even the walls are new. There's waterproof membrane installed behind the tiles, which does make the room ultimately smaller, but eliminates moisture issues.<br /><br />

The light has day/night functions that I never use, but I appreciate the thought.<br /><br />

Also I may have put a lot of the budget into a good shower. Teehee.

<h2>Rear Bedroom</h2>

<div class="gallery-with-caption">
  <div class="image-gallery">
    <div class="expandable-image" id="sl-7">
      <a href="#sl-7">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-7.jpg" alt="Rear Bedroom Before" />
      </a>
      <div class="expanded-view">
        <a href="#" class="close-button"></a>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-7.jpg" alt="Rear Bedroom Before" />
        <div class="navigation">
          <a href="#sl-8" class="next-prev-button">Next Image</a>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="expandable-image" id="sl-8">
      <a href="#sl-8">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-8.jpg" alt="Rear Bedroom After" />
      </a>
      <div class="expanded-view">
        <a href="#" class="close-button"></a>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-8.jpg" alt="Rear Bedroom After" />
        <div class="navigation">
          <a href="#sl-7" class="next-prev-button">Previous Image</a>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
<p class="image-caption">You're not seeing the final result because I never put the sliding door on the wardrobe :3 <sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[5]</a></sup></p>
</div>

"The Orange Room", as my then-partner put it. Originally I tried a forest green on the walls, and found it dimmed the brightness too much. So we went with an ochre red that was initially trialled in the guest bedroom.<br /><br /> 

Also I did paint that final wall in ochre red, after a few weeks of doing nothing about it. Brighter than it looks.<br /><br />

Most of the dirt in the carpet comes from a fireplace in the corner. Why a fireplace was being ignited in a room containing only a tumble dryer and a treadmill, I do not know. Cream carpets were used for all of the upstairs bedrooms, and work pretty well.<br /><br />

One feature of this brand of council house is that the gas boiler is situated in a small sub-room within the rear-facing bedroom. Which the plumbers all find quite amusing.<br /><br />

That bedframe was my one treat for myself in this room. A stupidly-good-quality mattress is up next.<br /><br />

Plenty of wall decorations later went up - mostly artwork from local artists. I also got some art prints from the Crawford Art Gallery that I still need to put up.<br /><br />

<h2>Guest bedroom</h2>
<div class="gallery-with-caption">
  <div class="image-gallery">
    <div class="expandable-image" id="sl-3">
      <a href="#sl-3">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-3.jpg" alt="Guest Bedroom Before" />
      </a>
      <div class="expanded-view">
        <a href="#" class="close-button"></a>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-3.jpg" alt="Guest Bedroom Before" />
        <div class="navigation">
          <a href="#sl-4" class="next-prev-button">Next Image</a>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="expandable-image" id="sl-4">
      <a href="#sl-4">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-4.jpg" alt="Guest Bedroom After" />
      </a>
      <div class="expanded-view">
        <a href="#" class="close-button"></a>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-4.jpg" alt="Guest Bedroom After" />
        <div class="navigation">
          <a href="#sl-3" class="next-prev-button">Previous Image</a>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
<p class="image-caption">The bed kinda takes up 70% of the room. Don't worry about it</p>
</div>

Probably the easiest room to improve. Floorboards needed no modification to fit carpets on top, two layers of paint did the walls, and triple-glazed windows (not pictured) were sufficient.<br /><br />

Another council house oddity - that storage on the left links directly to a ventilation hole in the exterior wall. So this took some amateur DIY to plug up and stop everything from freezing in winter. Bizarre architectural choice.

<h2>Other Works</h2>
<ul>
  <li>The front bedroom isn't pictured here because the current occupier moved their stuff in before I could get a good pic</li>
  <li>This house had the worst possible energy efficiency rating when I moved in. Triple-glazed windows at the front (rear already had double-glazed) and new exterior doors is my progress to-date. Next step would be exterior wall insulation, which is prohibitively expensive. Like €15,000 expensive.</li>
  <li>Living room didn't need much work apart from new couches and armchairs</li>
  <li>Garden work is still ongoing. Maybe to be finished this winter. Maybe.</li>
</ul>

I have a spreadsheet tracking the total spend on this house, and it's reached a horrifying number. But it's all been good investments so far. However, as the essential projects all get ticked off, my mind drifts towards catios at the back and flamethrower defences at the front. Teehee.<br /><br /> 


<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>Informally. If you search this house name online, you'll surely find others, but not this one<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
        <p>Correctly, in hindsight<a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
        <p>A deliberate design choice. This would have been soon after World War 2 and The Emergency, and allowing families some semblance of agricultural self-sufficiency was a local government priority. Imagine that being pitched these days. <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4">
        <p>No you cannot move between pictures via keyboard presses. Or click to escape. That is Javascript heresy.<a href="#fnref:4" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:5">
        <p>I don't have a landscape picture of the original, no portrait picture of the new, and couldn't be arsed changing the code to make this bit look good<a href="#fnref:5" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>



<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</p></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been almost two years since I moved into my house. This used to be an area of severe insecurity for me, and the feeling never really leaves. So I'm quite pleased with how it turned out.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Degustation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/30/Degustation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Degustation" /><published>2025-08-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/30/Degustation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/30/Degustation.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
<blockquote>Eleven times you take the boat out here, where we introduce every dish, every single time. We tell you exactly what we are feeding you. We create elaborate stories. We make it fun. We even give you a copy of the menu to take home. Please tell me one dish you ate the last time you were here. Or the time before. One. Please.</blockquote>

At this section of watching <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt9764362/">The Menu</a>, I was stumped for a minute. I had previously dined in Ichigo Ichie twice<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>, back when it ran a thirteen-course menu and carried a prestigious Michelin star. And in this moment, I could only think of a single dish I fully remembered.<br /><br />

No disrespect to the restaurant of course. Both times I waddled out of there very pleased with myself. But the egg dashi broth, dish twelve out of thirteen, was the only one that's survived in the mind. The rest is a collection of accessories - crisp interior design, beautiful plates to compliment the foods, slick staff that operated to the highest degree. And a hefty price tag.<br /><br />

To twist the knife some more, I also have a framed copy of the menu from one of the visits. It's entirely in Hiragana and Kanji, and I still can't read half of it. Stunning.<br /><br />

Chef Miyazaki repurposed Ichigo Ichie almost two years ago, into a bistro restaurant that carried almost none of the ostentation, a clean and simple menu that still delivered, and the financial barriers to entry torn down. I imagine he's quite happier with this setup.<br /><br />

The level of artistic faff in The Menu is stupendous. Chef Slowik presents the first few courses with the camera framing him as some sort of religious prophet, even as the proceeding courses aim to push the clientele into seeing through the bullshit. His soft voice delivers the most venomous of lines with absolute beauty. He convinces you the viewer with ease that this is all beyond your comprehension, an act of culinary brilliance even as the counter-evidence sits directly in front of you: a pitiful shard of fish sitting atop some jaunty rocks. Or some broken emulsion.<br /><br />

It's put me on notice. Whatever about occasional restaurant visits, my own cooking was going to lean down this path if I didn't stop myself. Not to the same extent maybe, but definitely losing that touch of love that carries everything.<br /><br />

I cooked <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8-9EWcxtPPY">Lu Ruo Fan</a> for some friends that evening. Partly because it was a hearty-ish meal and I love doing that shit in big batches. Partially because it was from one of the cuisines I think I most enjoy<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[2]</a></sup>. And partially cos I thought it would impress people.<br /><br />

Maybe it did, but that should be a secondary thought at best. There's a vague gap between doing something new and cool to have fun exploring cuisines, and doing it to fuel the ego. The latter doesn't last, and it's hard to figure out when you're in the middle of this dance.<br /><br />

I'm certainly not too far gone yet. I think I can cook better than <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s597UDb8qkE">Tyler's Bullshit</a>, and haven't said anything to put myself on Chef Slowik's execution list<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[3]</a></sup>. But maybe I should ease off on watching videos on Michelin-starred New York chefs preparing Korean barbeque.<br /><br />

I had more thoughts on The Menu, but they've slid from the mind since I started typing. Much like the clients, it doesn't entirely hold up to intense scrutiny. But the message is clear: cook for love.<br /><br />

Movie nights are going to be a regular thing at my place now. I'm thinking cheeseburgers next week.<br /><br />

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>Given that Ichigo Ichie means "once in a lifetime", this is additionally funny in hindsight <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
        <p>The others mainly being Cantonese, Shanghai (read: Xiaolongbao), Louisiana Creole, and Italian <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
        <p>Yet<a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink"> ↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eleven times you take the boat out here, where we introduce every dish, every single time. We tell you exactly what we are feeding you. We create elaborate stories. We make it fun. We even give you a copy of the menu to take home. Please tell me one dish you ate the last time you were here. Or the time before. One. Please.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You Won’t BELIEVE This Game Exists! (NOT CLICKBAIT)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/25/You-Wont-Believe-This-Game-Exists.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You Won’t BELIEVE This Game Exists! (NOT CLICKBAIT)" /><published>2025-08-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/25/You-Wont-Believe-This-Game-Exists</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/25/You-Wont-Believe-This-Game-Exists.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
Yu-Gi-Oh: Forbidden Memories is the stupidest most broken appallingly imbalanced piece of shit video game ever created. I love it to bits.<br /><br />

Released in Japan in 1999, and elsewhere in 2002, this game ruined several years of my childhood as I spent countless hours trying to beat it. I never did, and have no desire to try again. Skill will only bring you so far - you require hours of grinding to get top-tier cards, in-depth game exploitation knowledge, and the most absurd run of RNG imagineable.<br /><br />

The gameplay attempts to track the Yu-Gi-Oh card game, with one slight flaw: development of Forbidden Memories began before the card game was released. So the devs had some knowledge of the cards that would come out, basic mechanics in terms of monsters/spells/traps, life points, etc. But everything else, Forbidden Memories just kind of... made up.<br /><br />

<p>
<ul>
    <li>You can only play one card onto the field each turn, and it must be before you interact with the field</li>
    <li>It introduces a monster Star Sign system to create weaknesses/strengths versus other Star Signs, which simply does not exist outside of this game</li>
    <li>Monster effects do not exist</li>
    <li>Most of the game takes place in ancient Egypt rather than with the actual Yu-Gi-Oh cast. I find this quite charming but kid me was not impressed</li> 
    <li>Trap cards will automatically activate at the earliest legal moment, whether you or the opponent wants it or not</li>
    <li> Each monster card - and there are hundreds of them - have individually crafted 3d models, specifically for battle animations that most players will never see because you have to press a different button to see the 3d battle format, and the game never tells you this</li> 
    <li>Ritual cards do exist, however they're disgustingly bad to the point of it being endearing. You have to sacrifice 2-3 specific monsters to obtain the ritual monster, except THE GAME NEVER TELLS YOU WHICH MONSTERS TO SACRIFICE. AND THE MONSTERS HAVE TO BE ON THE FIELD IN ORDER TO BE SACRIFICED, IN A GAME WHERE YOU CAN ONLY PLAY ONE CARD PER TURN WHAT THE FUCK</li>
    <li>The fusion system hahaha holy shit</li><br /><br />
</ul>

Beating an opponent gives you a reward card, which operates off an absurdly opaque system where it judges how aggressive/tactical your gameplay was, and how quickly you ended the battle, then rates you as either "Power" or "Technical" and gives you a grade. The higher the grade, the better the card in that "Power" or "Technical" category. Good luck grinding S-rank Technicals.<br /><br />

Your reward for this, once you clear some huge power spikes, is a final boss gauntlet run of 6 opponents in a row. Each of these opponents has twenty cards in their card, rather than your five. They can see your hand at all times, as well as your face-down cards. Some of them (read: Seto) have cards that are so absurdly powerful that if they play multiple of them, there is absolutely nothing whatsoever you can do. You can board wipe sure, but that leaves you open to another 4500 ATK direct hit the next round. In a game with 8000 life points. And he has three of the stupid bastards.<br /><br />

There is absolutely no strategy that will save you if the game decides to screw you on RNG. Bad hand - dead. Opponent plays multiple Blue-Eyes Ultimate Dragons DIRECTLY FROM THE HAND - dead. Game freezes at a very specific point because of a scratch in the disc - very dead. Last one might have been a me thing.<br /><br />

Did you think I wasn't going to elaborate on the fusion system? Well this is my blog and I do whatever I want, so enjoy:

<ul>
    <li>Cards are fused together in the hand without Polymerization</li>
    <li>The list of allowed fusions is manually coded in, with no tags in the code to specify which fusion material cards are beasts/machines/dark/male/female/whatever. <a href="https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/ps/561010-yu-gi-oh-forbidden-memories/faqs/16613">Here is a quick summary of the fusions. It is insane.</a>
    <li>There are plenty of instances where fusing two monster will make one that is weaker in every single regard</li>
    <li>To copy a specific section I saw via a friend, here is some of the bizarre fusion rules coded in:
        <blockquote>[Female]<br />
        These are monsters that fuse with Stone Ogre Grotto to become Mystical Sand.<br />
        Notes:<br />
        - Performance of Sword, Spirit of the Harp and Spirit of the Winds are not
        female, even though they can be equipped with Cyber Shield and certainly look
        female.<br />
        - Mystical Sand, Empress Judge and Cosmo Queen can be
        considered female, as they can be equipped with Cyber Shield and look female,
        but they don't participate in any fusions as females because their attack level
        is too high.<br />
        - every female and every monster that can be equipped with Cyber Shield can be
        equipped with Electro-whip, but there are dozens of monsters that can be
        equipped with Electro-whip that aren't female and can't be equipped with
        Cyber Shield<br />
        - all females can be equipped with Malevolent Nuzzler<br />
        </blockquote>
    </li>
    <li>Some other funny segments that I found:
        <blockquote>Note: every dragon can be equipped with Dragon Treasure, but there are 36 monsters that can be equipped with Dragon Treasure that are not dragons.</blockquote>
        <blockquote>[Bugrothian]<br />
                    These are monsters with strictly less than 1850 attack points that have primary type Aqua or first guardian star Neptune and that are not Fish with strictly less than 1600 attack points nor Sea Serpents.</blockquote>
    </li>
    <li>You can fuse spell and trap cards together what the fuck</li>

<p>
    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/ygo-1.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">WHY IS THIS ALLOWED</figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>
<p>

Fuck this stupid baka piece of shit. Except I love it because the soundtrack slaps.<br /><br />

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iqp9jzmWhto?si=6MX5VADcgWmYXyrZ" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe><br /><br />

Obviously Konami had to make a sequel. And they continued to be incredibly normal about it :3 <br /><br />

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/ygo-1.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">👍</figcaption>
</figure>

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</p></li></ul></p></p></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yu-Gi-Oh: Forbidden Memories is the stupidest most broken appallingly imbalanced piece of shit video game ever created. I love it to bits.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WPlace Shitposting General 2, Electric Boogaloo</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/18/WPlace-Shitposting-General-Part2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WPlace Shitposting General 2, Electric Boogaloo" /><published>2025-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/18/WPlace-Shitposting-General-Part2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/18/WPlace-Shitposting-General-Part2.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
After my <a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/08/11/WPlace-Shitposting-General.html">part 1 post</a> having initial fun with <a href="https://wplace.live/">WPlace</a>, I've been trying to branch out a bit more from painting and maintaining some existing pride flags.<br /><br />

I still keep an eye on the pride flags though. They get defaced pretty frequently, and there's a concerted push to paint pedophile flags on/around pride flags in an attempt to smear them. Much like real life, our existence is a constant battle on every front.<br /><br />

My online friend hasn't noticed the gay little message I left in her hometown. Don't wanna tell her outright, but the area is becoming increasingly busy and I don't wanna miss my chance either.<br /><br />

A friend of mine drew her custom Pokemon trainer which I thought was super cool. It was modelled off Kris and the Youngster from Pokemon Crystal, and comes off really well in WPlace. A lovely combination of cute art and a personal touch. I'm doing similar in that I'm drawing pixel art of my favourite Pokemon, but rather a dream team combination of my 6 favourites, complete with my favourite trainer design - Rosa, unsurprisingly. Really pleased with how this turned out.<br /><br />

I'm probably a bit burnt out after that one. I'll probably wind down my activities, as long as my city doesn't fall to 4Chan raids. What year is it, anyway?

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/wplace-3.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">:3</figcaption>
</figure>

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[After my part 1 post having initial fun with WPlace, I've been trying to branch out a bit more from painting and maintaining some existing pride flags.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Virtuous Mechsploitation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/12/Virtuous-Mechsploitation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Virtuous Mechsploitation" /><published>2025-08-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/12/Virtuous-Mechsploitation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/12/Virtuous-Mechsploitation.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
If you recognise the title and are currently in a cold sweat, don't worry I won't go all out. Yet.<br /><br />

---<br /><br />

Armored Core 6 arrived at an interesting time. Fans of a gritty corporate-war mech series found themselves rubbing shoulders with lesbians freshly giddy from watching Gundam: The Witch From Mercury. The partnership between these two factions has been... interesting.<br /><br />

In hindsight, the first trailer containing the words <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SlSfr6Wa5sc">"wake the dog up"</a> was an obvious flag. Then 621 getting ordered around by "Handler" Walter, with a gruff voice born of gravel getting run through a blender, set people off like nothing else before it. Later in the game, it leans directly into mind control plot lines. I wonder if the writers knew how it would all be received. Or maybe they were finally let loose.<br /><br />

What's followed since AC6 melded all this together is a fresh fanfic genre of a lovely diverse range of people getting hurled into scenarios of control (physical and mental), brainwashing, petplay, delightfully unhealthy relationships, containing lots of trans girlies. All enshrouded by the cold heartless shell of a mech they've been forced into. <a href="https://archiveofourown.org/tags/Mechsploitation">Fascinating stuff, really.</a><br /><br />

Unfortunately the unhealthy relationship stuff doesn't sit well with me. So I've been thinking instead about the coolness of mechs, the appeal of having one's humanity augmented and/or stripped away, and how this interacts with other people.<br /><br />

I adore technology at its hardware heart: cold metal that simply does what it does, and nothing more. You know why a mechanical watch moves, how an engine performs, how a lightbulb glows. They know their place, and I love them for it<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>.<br /><br />

Technology should not think, that's what we're here for. The second metal thinks it knows better than you, intentionally or not, is where it all falls apart. Whether it's software designed for a different purpose than what you want, malicious code, or just plain bad design, the roles begin to shift. Metal is power, not control - that's your job.<br /><br />

This clashes badly with most mech fiction. Normally the mech is a tool of control via another entity - a human controller or corporation maybe. But what if it's a symbol of individual power? I like how <a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/05/26/Heaven-Will-Be-Mine.html">Heaven Will Be Mine</a> captures this. The Ship-Selves are first and foremost an extension of their pilots, beyond even their physical forms. They live and fight on a tier of existence that humans could only dream of. They merely exist in ways never before possible.<br /><br />

The human element must reign supreme and free. Even when enshrouded in metal, even with orders being barked into their ear, even with the elements trying to wipe them out.<br /><br />

"I bet you're thinking of an F1 clip-" you're damn right I am. Behold the final five laps of the 2021 Russian Grand Prix from Max Verstappen's perspective. If you're expecting something dramatic, it doesn't happen. Max's engineer, Gianpiero Lambiase, is on top of every event before it's in front of his pilot's eyes. He makes the perfectly-timed call to switch to wet weather tyres on a track that's half dry, half soaked, and getting more volatile every lap. Gianpiero, with the crispest of voices, gives Max every bit of information he needs, and not a thing more, knowing with full confidence that Max can sweep aside everything in his way.<br /><br />

(The below embed likely won't work without watching it on youtube, still trying to figure out fixes to this)<br /><br />

<iframe title="Max Verstappen's Final Five Laps in Sochi | 2021 Russian Grand Prix" width="660" height="371" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/m0eASI6N6vE?si=mraCk8F7FVWDYa1G" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe><br /><br />

Max makes it look easy, and carves up other elite pilots for breakfast. What powers it all is the confidence in every word said between them: no second-guessing, no doubt as to the thought put into them. The human element is simultaneously drowned out by mechanical whines, and the most powerful thing there is.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup><br /><br />

Outside of still-niche VNs, this concept doesn't seem to have much sway with the masses. Yet the concept of trust and love conquering all is a huge undeniable trope, I'm just applying it to massive hunks of metal that can crush your enemies. Y'know, normal kink stuff.

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>Yes this is hot to me<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>
</p>

<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you recognise the title and are currently in a cold sweat, don't worry I won't go all out. Yet.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">6 Month Thoughts on Takumi</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/12/6-Month-Thoughts-on-Takumi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="6 Month Thoughts on Takumi" /><published>2025-08-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/12/6-Month-Thoughts-on-Takumi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/12/6-Month-Thoughts-on-Takumi.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
<a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/03/09/Say-Hi-To-Takumi-The-Toyota-GT86.html">Takumi</a> was bought 6 months ago, integrated into Ireland with wallet-annihilating speed, and has been enjoying his new life (hopefully).<br /><br />

He grabs loads of attention still. The car scene in Ireland is dire. It's not just that nice cars are expensive - <i>everything</i> is expensive. So a modded GT86 is more of a head-turner than it has any right to be. This wouldn't even be worthy of a sniff in Britain.<br /><br />

The previous owner - a delight of a woman from everything I've heard - has covered most of the basics of modding. Aero kit is in good shape, Invidia N1 exhaust looks like the correct call, and the decals are cool without being over the top. With the engine at 100,000 miles, I don't want to strain it more than necessary, and probably won't try to push more power out of it. A supercharger sounds fun, as long as I could keep it switched off 95% of the time. And where's the fun in that?<br /><br />

The ride leans on the stiff side. Which is to be expected, but roads in Cork are an incredibly accurate simulation of the moon after cluster bomb strikes. So this is my main area of focus. Fully adjustable suspension, in particular being able to adjust spring stiffness, would be amazing. This is a €1,000+ job though. Gotta sort out other life stuff before this.<br /><br />

Tyres are good, as Michelin Pilot Sport 5's would be, apart from the bit where Sandy uses them to sharpen his claws. No I don't plan on doing anything about this.<br /><br />

I've scratched the wheels a few times which is frustrating, especially as the base paint underneath is orange and looks terrible when exposed. Parallel parking is very prominent where I live, so this may continue to be an issue.<br /><br />

Fuel consumption is pretty poor in-town, which annoyingly is where most of my driving is located. I haven't let Takumi stretch his legs as much as he'd like. Even when good roads do exist, they're populated by tractors, campervans, and old people who got their license in 1968 down the bottom of a cereal box. I may end up just taking a ferry to Wales. Or France maybe. Particularly if I learn how to solo camp...<br /><br />

Getting the approval of bikers is my big thing. I got some revs of approval from a Kawasaki rider a few weeks back and am still glowing from that. Also got an earful of throttle from a modded Audi RS6, which considering that thing is a nuclear power plant on wheels, is a nice motivator! Plus the kids who ask me to rev it are still great.<br /><br />

Unsure will I take it to Mondello Park, as I've already been there twice and might enjoy learning a new track this time. Anglesey in Wales is right next to Holyhead and looks gorgeous, so that's the next goal!<br /><br />

Edit: what the fuck do you mean the ferry is more expensive than the entire track day

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Takumi was bought 6 months ago, integrated into Ireland with wallet-annihilating speed, and has been enjoying his new life (hopefully).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WPlace Shitposting General</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/11/WPlace-Shitposting-General.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WPlace Shitposting General" /><published>2025-08-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/11/WPlace-Shitposting-General</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/11/WPlace-Shitposting-General.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
If you're not familiar, <a href="https://wplace.live/">WPlace</a> is a collaborative pixel art canvas of sorts, utilising OpenStreetMap and MapLibre for a rather joyful 2025 internet experience. Alternatively, it's the hottest place to shitpost right now.<br /><br />

The servers work approx. 4% of the time, which is charming for now. This will tire out a lot of the freshly enthusiastic crowd that have joined recently, but I'm sure scaling up the servers would be stupidly expensive for such a silly little (affectionate) site.<br /><br />

It is reminiscent of many more delightful websites that no longer exist. Existing not for profit, just for fun. Seeing your home city lit up with flags, artwork, and love is quite touching.<br /><br />

I've been painting, cleaning, and maintaining pride flags in my home city, helping a friend paint her cool custom Pokemon trainer sprite, creating a big sign that tells everyone where my cats live, and planting a little surprise for my online friend in her hometown (Hi Brigid &lt;3).<br /><br />

Though it does expose the fact that art and creativity have never been my strong suit. For every living second in school, my mind would lock up when given any open-plan "write/draw whatever you like" task, then I'd inevitably get shouted at for it. This builds up into me clutching to certainty and security a little bit too much. An open canvas is still scary in a sense.<br /><br />

As much as I like painting big trans-coloured love hearts where my friends might find them, something a bit more individual might be neat. I briefly toyed with sprite creators and assist tools before hitting another creative wall that I've never figured out how to break through. This also ties into creativitiy issues when it comes to this site, and my life and hobbies in general.<br /><br />

Much like relearning Irish, some kind of fundamental restart is needed. 

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/wplace-1.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Rio di Janeiro</figcaption>
</figure>

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/wplace-2.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">[Drone Strike]</figcaption>
</figure>

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're not familiar, WPlace is a collaborative pixel art canvas of sorts, utilising OpenStreetMap and MapLibre for a rather joyful 2025 internet experience. Alternatively, it's the hottest place to shitpost right now.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Small Site Updates</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/10/Small-Site-Updates.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Small Site Updates" /><published>2025-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/10/Small-Site-Updates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/10/Small-Site-Updates.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
<ul>
    <li>A quick check showed that Sandy's Palace was consuming 404kB of data transfer on page load. This is shocking, unacceptable, and appalling. To avoid being cubed by the Javascript-hating mob I foolishly created in my head, this needs to go down. I've culled it to below 300kB with some easy changes, unfortunately <a href="https://sneil.neocities.org/">Nora's</a> very cute 88x31 gif now takes up a third of the page size. This will be tolerated :3</li>
    <li>Made the first new additions to the Cool Site buttons this year. Very much enjoyed looking through these sites. Plenty more to come.</li>
    <li>Considered updating my 88x31, then decided against it. It's funnier the more basic it is. Unless I can figure out how to animate 88x31 gifs, then I'm unstoppable (someone please show me how to do this)</li>
    <li>Deliberated randomising the Cool Site button order, then decided to keep it mostly ordered in terms of people I know first. Also couldn't be arsed engineering that one without using Javascript. Don't know that many people IRL with blogs, gotta work on that</li>
</ul>
Still considering should I post about projects that are identifiable to me IRL. Will err on the side of caution, though it'd be nice to have more links on the home page. 
</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A quick check showed that Sandy's Palace was consuming 404kB of data transfer on page load. This is shocking, unacceptable, and appalling. To avoid being cubed by the Javascript-hating mob I foolishly created in my head, this needs to go down. I've culled it to below 300kB with some easy changes, unfortunately Nora's very cute 88x31 gif now takes up a third of the page size. This will be tolerated :3 Made the first new additions to the Cool Site buttons this year. Very much enjoyed looking through these sites. Plenty more to come. Considered updating my 88x31, then decided against it. It's funnier the more basic it is. Unless I can figure out how to animate 88x31 gifs, then I'm unstoppable (someone please show me how to do this) Deliberated randomising the Cool Site button order, then decided to keep it mostly ordered in terms of people I know first. Also couldn't be arsed engineering that one without using Javascript. Don't know that many people IRL with blogs, gotta work on that Still considering should I post about projects that are identifiable to me IRL. Will err on the side of caution, though it'd be nice to have more links on the home page.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Do I Webring</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/09/How-Do-I-Webring.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Do I Webring" /><published>2025-08-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/09/How-Do-I-Webring</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/09/How-Do-I-Webring.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
I'm finally moving beyond repetitive thoughts on improving Sandy's Palace's homepage.<br /><br />

Fundamentally it's fine - I like straightforward. And it stays true to my goal of minimal bullshit, and only things that I want. Some silly one-liners, blog summary, links to RSS, links to cool stuff, all working ok.<br /><br />

The list of other cool sites isn't great. I populated it once when building the site in late-2024, added two buttons for people I found via another friend's site, then one from a friend I knew IRL, then just kinda stopped. Not that I don't enjoy travsering people's silly little blogs, but mentally the energy wasn't there.<br /><br />

So I am making a concerted push to trawl through more blogs - primarily for entertainment, and secondarily to add more cool things to my webring. I think that'd be more sustainable. Maybe hardcap myself at 5 blogs per session, and actually delve into them, rather than surface-level aesthetic comparison.<br /><br />

I'm familiar with the <a href="https://cohost-highway.neocities.org/webring">Cohost Highway</a>, a continuation of the wonderful spirit of Cohost that I was tantalisingly close to but never fully committed to. But I would love to discover other curated webrings and build up my enthusiasm again.<br /><br />

I was gonna wrap up this post with a joke, then noticed that one of my friends changed their name and I'm too excited about this to think straight ok bye

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm finally moving beyond repetitive thoughts on improving Sandy's Palace's homepage.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My-Dream-Supermarket-V2FINAL.txt</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/08/My-Dream-Supermarket-V2FINAL.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My-Dream-Supermarket-V2FINAL.txt" /><published>2025-08-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/08/My-Dream-Supermarket-V2FINAL</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/08/My-Dream-Supermarket-V2FINAL.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
I am afflicted with a deadly illness that has ruined my life. It's called Walking At A Normal Fucking Speed and cripples my ability to function in society.<br /><br />

I claim to minimise my time in public spaces because of loud noise, overstimulation, overheating, and health concerns. Truthfully it's because me getting stuck behind a three-child pram for more than a microsecond results in authoritarian thoughts of cubing everyone who stands in my way.<br /><br /> 

People who sprint across the road just to screech to a halt in front of me and stare at their phone deserve nothing more than forced labour camps. Able-bodied people who move at the pace of tectonic plates shall be given exoskeletons that I remotely control to forcibly speed them up on footpaths.<br /><br />

(This is all far funnier when you consider I'm 5ft 6" and my left leg is two inches shorter than my right)<br /><br />

Supermarkets are the worst for all of these combined. Why I haven't moved to online deliveries and click-and-collect ranges from excuses such as "I want an excuse to drive Takumi" to "Tesco gave me the wrong type of tomato and now I'm considering domestic terrorism."<br /><br />

Dunnes is hell on earth. It has everything in stock, meaning the large food shops are done here, meaning the bills are often €200+, then the arguing over vouchers is excruciating. Dante Alighieri did not envision a middle-aged mother forcing the entire queue to shuffle out of her way three separate times for her to stare at chocolate bars to push her bill up to a certain amount such that her vouchers covered more, only to realise she miscalculated the amounts, proceeding to argue with the cashier over price labels, then finding half her vouchers were different to what she thought, THEN loading her shopping into the trolley for the subsequent five minutes. But if he did, Inferno would have ten circles.<br /><br />

SuperValu is a nursing home. I am not attuned to John-and-Mary culture at the best of times, but visiting here could be a documentary. Also the car park is a war zone fought by tortoises.<br /><br />

Tesco operates one human-staffed till, and five morbillion self-checkouts visited entirely by cataconic dudebros. Also I refuse on principle to get a Clubcard to get the actual prices.<br /><br />

Aldi and moreso Lidl should be more to my taste. I meet the cashier's eye, they challenge me to a duel, then proceed to sling my shopping at lightning speeds through the register while I make a mediocre attempt to keep up. A brief sniff of victory is all they display. Which is great fun, but neither of them have good fish. Or vegetables. Or snacks. Or spices.<br /><br />

And here rests my problem. I desire a supermarket designed from scratch for people who know what they're getting, get the thing, pay for the thing, then evaporate into mist. With aisles curated for the actual separation of food types, not forcing the essential stuff into alternating corners of the warehouse. Alas no overpaid executive sees my vision.<br /><br /> 

In completely unrelated news, I scored full marks on an autism assessment for the first time in that psychiatrist's career. Please clap.

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am afflicted with a deadly illness that has ruined my life. It's called Walking At A Normal Fucking Speed and cripples my ability to function in society.]]></summary></entry></feed>