<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-10-10T10:07:05+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/atom.xml</id><title type="html">Sandy’s Palace</title><subtitle>Caoimhe&apos;s gay little website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">What I’m Reading, Volume 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/10/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I’m Reading, Volume 5" /><published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/10/10/What-I&apos;m-Reading-Vol-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/10/What-I&apos;m-Reading-Vol-5.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
    Previous iterations:<br /><br />
    <ul>
        <li><a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/05/11/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-1.html">Volume 1</a></li>
        <li><a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/05/27/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-2.html">Volume 2</a></li>
        <li><a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/07/02/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-3.html">Volume 3</a></li>
        <li><a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/09/02/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-4.html">Volume 4</a></li>
    </ul>

I probably could have added more Light Reads, but I'm on holidays for a week and wanted to wrap this up! 

<p><h1>Serious Reads</h1></p>

<h2><a href="Link">The Superyacht, the Billionaire, and a Wildly Improbable Disaster at Sea</a></h2>
<b>Note: Wired has a limited amount of free articles for non-subscribers. If you have any issues with the above link, use a link like <a href="https://www.removepaywall.com/search?url=https://www.wired.com/story/mike-lynch-sinking-disaster/">Remove Paywall</a>.</b>
<blockquote>What has emerged through the various investigations, and through press accounts, is a critical flaw in the Bayesian’s design. The single-mast configuration that gave the yacht her elegant lines—unique among the boat designer’s sought-after series of similar vessels—also dangerously affected her center of gravity. The MAIB analysis, conducted by the Wolfson Unit at Southampton, found that with the keel raised and no sails set, the yacht became vulnerable to capsizing in winds exceeding 60 knots—a threshold crossed in seconds when the downburst struck. The other yachts in the same series as the Bayesian had two masts, not one. This problem might have been noticed earlier except for one other factor: Elite luxury yachts don’t have to comply with the same robust safety rules as commercial ones. The International Safety Management Code is voluntary for boats registered for private use.</blockquote>
I may have skipped some of the sections about corporate bag-slinging. The yacht disaster is interesting though.

<h2><a href="https://www.noemamag.com/the-last-days-of-social-media/">The Last Days Of Social Media</a></h2>
<blockquote>Social media’s current logic is designed to reduce friction, to give users infinite content for instant gratification, or at the very least, the anticipation of such. The antidote to this compulsive, numbing overload will be found in deliberative friction, design patterns that introduce pause and reflection into digital interaction, or platforms and algorithms that create space for intention.</blockquote>
It hasn't gone unnoticed that I could consume the ever-swelling number of articles on this subject for far too long. And the perceived benefit of reading and recirculating them remains questionable.<br /><br />

This article does go into some interesting depth as to a possible new future of decentralised web development. And it also reminded me to check back up on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solid_(web_decentralization_project)">Solid project</a> led by a certain Tim Berners-Lee.

<h2><a href="https://english.elpais.com/international/2025-09-14/the-gentrification-of-mexican-wrestling.html">The gentrification of Mexican wrestling</a></h2>
<blockquote>Seven years ago, the Mexican Wrestling Council (CMLL) managed to have its sport declared an intangible cultural heritage of Mexico City, which turned it into a tourist attraction. Ernesto Ocampo, editor-in-chief of the specialized portal Superluchas, explains that lucha libre emerged as entertainment for the lower classes in neighborhoods where there were no cinemas or theaters, but that today it is recognized as a national symbol “on a par with mariachi or tequila.”</blockquote>
Lucha Libre is enormously encoded in Mexican culture, in a way that isn't reflected in its presentation to international audiences. The incorporation of the (Lucha Libre) AAA brand into (USA) WWE this year has already resulted in a watering-down and ironing-out of the sport's core. This is also seen somewhat in the collaboration between (Lucha Libre) CMLL and (USA) AEW.<br /><br />

WWE and AEW stars will make appearances in Lucha Libre events<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>, and the style of wrestling will shape itself to show off the skill of the visiting star. CMLL and AAA stars will also attend USA-based events, but their finesse is muted.<br /><br />

The larger entity inevitably consumes the smaller one, forcing it to fit within its mould. Many such cases.

<h2><a href="https://english.elpais.com/technology/2025-09-13/never-steal-a-hackers-girlfriends-phone-how-an-expert-exposed-a-global-network-of-thieves.html">Never steal a hacker’s girlfriend’s phone: How an expert exposed a global network of thieves</a></h2>
<blockquote>But there are cities in China where that IMEI can be changed, says Vigo. “It’s the hardest part, when it arrives in China and they change certain components and the IMEI. It requires a certain level of sophistication: opening the phone, changing the chip... you have to know what you’re doing because Apple detects if there are non-original components.” The goal is to be able to resell the stolen phone with a different IMEI so that it can’t be traced.</blockquote>
Interesting evidence here to show that the security on modern phones is rather impressive, when criminals often go to these lengths.<br /><br />

It also exposes, once again, that the end user remains the most vulnerable area of an attack surface.

<h2><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/future/article/20250911-the-people-who-hunt-down-old-tvs">'You just can't recreate that glow': The people who hunt old TVs</a></h2>
<blockquote>Byron McDanold is one of the moderators for a Facebook group called The CRT Collective, which at the time of writing has more than 240,000 members. McDanold says that CRT technology has appealing quirks that are impossible to replicate with other technology. "You push the button on the front and it makes that zap, pop noise as it turns on," he says. He argues that many CRT hunters are on an epic quest to recreate specific memories or feelings from their childhoods – they end up obsessing over picture quality in their pursuit of the past.</blockquote>


<h2><a href="https://erysdren.me/blog/2025-08-16/">If you love it, download it</a></h2>
<blockquote>I have written a few short guides and notes about ways you can help contribute to media preservation by doing it your damn self. Most of the guides lean very technical, but I try to give appropriate explanations and links to the tools and documentation where I can.<br /><br /></blockquote>
Despite reassurances from other sites that I have almost certainly seen this somewhere before, I had not in fact seen this somewhere before. Neat little guide for preserving various forms of media. 

<h2><a href="https://daniel.lawrence.lu/blog/y2025m09d21/#s1">Line scan camera image processing</a></h2>
<blockquote>Line scan cameras are very suitable for capturing trains, since I can capture the full length of the train with minimal perspective distortion. This is super nice for train nerds who want to make models of the trains. Also, as you keep the camera running, you can get incredibly high resolution photos that span over 100,000 pixels wide.<br /><br /></blockquote>
A fascinating look at how line scan cameras operate and how they're utilised. Some of the technical aspects did go over my head though.


<h2><a href="https://wordsmith.social/elilla/deep-in-mordor-where-the-shadows-lie-dystopian-stories-of-my-time-as-a-googler">Deep in Mordor where the shadows lie: Dystopian tales of that time when I sold out to Google</a></h2>
<blockquote>I will be honest and say that most of my fellow programmers ate that shit up, we had all been gold-star kids and here was the hottest company in the world constantly massaging our egos, telling us we were better than everyone for being geniuses. I would have loved to feel the same, I tried to feel the same, but I came from poverty and I could not stop noticing the precariat: temps, part-timers, and contractors, an entire layer of the company who did the brunt of work without being Googlers. No toy budget for kitchen staff.<br /><br />

It's the little things that bugged me, how people would eat the free candy or have a bowl of cereal and just leave trash and dirty dishes everywhere for the cleaning ladies (contractors) to deal with; more than that the way nobody looked at them or said “thank you”. We Brazilians have a social class for that, a social code underlying that studied invisibility, I knew what this was: these were maids. Servants. The women in my family, my friends at school. The “campus” was pretty open and my then-wife visited it a few times; it creeped the Fuck out of her, the distinction between people and non-people.<br /><br /></blockquote>
I've visited Big Tech main headquarters a few times. In the shadow of the Olympic-sized swimming pool, the cleaning staff never spoke.<br /><br />

Otherwise this article offers another interesting view on life within Big Tech, with a perspective of someone from the "Global South". The perk-slinging days of the 2010s must have stung even harder with the author's background.


<p><h1>Light Reads</h1></p>

<h2><a href="https://hard-drive.net/hd/video-games/every-pikmin-type-ranked-by-how-much-i-had-to-pay-an-exterminator-to-get-them-out-of-my-kitchen/">Every Pikmin Type Ranked by How Much I Had to Pay an Exterminator to Get Them Out of My Kitchen</a></h2>
I have never played a Pikmin game, but enjoy the thought of oppressing these silly little dudes.

<h2><a href="https://bogdanthegeek.github.io/blog/projects/vapeserver/">Hosting a WebSite on a Disposable Vape</a></h2>
<blockquote>Over the past year I have collected quite a few of these PY32 based vapes, all of them from different models of vape from the same manufacturer. It’s not my place to do free advertising for big tobacco, so I won’t mention the brand I got it from, but if anyone who worked on designing them reads this, thanks for labeling the debug pins!</blockquote>
<a href="http://ewaste.fka.wtf/">Here</a> is the direct link to the vape-hosted site. Took about 20 seconds to load for me. Pretty neat!

<h2><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Unusual_articles">Wikipedia: Unusual Articles</a></h2>
I think it'd be cheating if I posted one of these articles on every single What I'm Reading post. So here you go.

<h2><a href="https://www.presentandcorrect.com/blogs/blog/david-walkers-paper-clip-collection">David Walker's Paper Clip Collection</a></h2>
It's exactly what you think it is.


<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>Or Lucha Libre-styled events, and there is a significant difference.<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>

    </ol>
</div>

<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</p></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Previous iterations: Volume 1 Volume 2 Volume 3 Volume 4]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An Infinite Set of Lines Going Up</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/09/An-Infinite-Set-of-Lines-Going-Up(2).html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Infinite Set of Lines Going Up" /><published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/10/09/An-Infinite-Set-of-Lines-Going-Up(2)</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/09/An-Infinite-Set-of-Lines-Going-Up(2).html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
There is no clear threshold for when we've gone too far. It varies per person, per entity, per company, per nation. The consequences are never clear and understandable. Yet we are already in the middle of them after so little time, and I strongly fear it will get worse.<br /><br />

I refuse to call any product or technology "AI". It is neither artificial nor intelligent. What you see, and maybe interact with, is little more than a token prediction model. Rather good ones, mind you. The libraries of data they pull from are immense - and, of course, stolen. Not that it will ever be proven.<br /><br />

No leap forward in efficiency for these programs has fundamentally altered the notion that they simply predict the most likely token to appear next in a sequence. You can see this with ChatGPT or Gemini replying to your query. It starts a sentence with no idea how to end it. I can think of people in real life who also act like this, and they're barely preferable.<br /><br />

But can you avoid it? The ability decreases on the daily. You might be able to avoid direct use of it, avoiding outsourcing your own thought processes to a machine, but what about when decisions are made for you? When you argue with a "chatbot" on your medical provider's shitty app, sending you in endless loops with no intention of giving you what you need, do you have a choice any more? When your work demands it be embedded in every process, what else can you do?<br /><br />

I have seen the inside of one of the Large Language Models that increasingly powers website backends, servers, chatbots, and far more serious things. It is held together with spit and prayers. And the amount of people who truly understand how it works is pitiful. I am not one of them. But I do understand that our future of living is being outsourced to an opaque incomprehensible entity, completely without consent.

<h2>On "Intelligence"</h2>
Sure I can say that "AI" isn't very artificial nor intelligent. But why? The output is often very verbose and detailed.<br /><br />

The chatbots you might know of - ChatGPT, Gemini, CoPilot, Claude - are all Large Language Models at heart. They draw from an absurdly large reservoir of data to answer every query that comes into it. They are tailored to read and speak in natural language terms: the user types a question as they might to a friend, and the LLM responds in a clear, understandable format. This has been fundamental to the surge in popularity of LLMs. The average user does not know what prompt engineering is, never mind have any desire to utilise it. They want an answer with minimal effort. LLMs are perfectly poised to deliver this.<br /><br />

For example, you ask ChatGPT to draft an email for you. The LLM will analyse your query, identify important words that correspond with keywords in its data banks, then search those data banks for correlated words and phrases. It then assembles these correlated words and phrases into a readable format, and spits it back to the user.<br /><br />

This is a ludicrously simple breakdown. Every single stage of the LLM is fiendishly complex, and it grows in difficulty the more fundamentally simple the question is. Mathematical equations that span the length of a country are easier to answer than a single philosophical question<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>.<br /><br /> 

One of my favourite examples of phrasing this is: You can get a machine to analyse 10,000 pictures, and pick out ones based on colours fairly easily. A digital picture is comprised of code, so the machine can look at the data and pick out similarities within a certain range. But then you ask the machine to "identify all pictures with a bird in them". <b>How do you teach a machine what a bird is?</b><br /><br />

The only viable solution as of 2025 is to feed that machine thousands, millions, billions of pictures and descriptions of birds. An utterly overwhelming amount of examples to drill it home into that silicon shell. So when you give the machine a picture of a bird, there's enough pixel patterns that match with its data banks that makes the machine decide that it's a reasonably accurate match. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decision_tree">decision tree</a> for LLMs to determine this is on an astronomical scale, one that no individual could ever pick apart.<br /><br />

How similar is this to the human brain? We have no idea. There could be chemical reaction in our synapses that moves in an inate way we simply can't comprehend. Or maybe the billions of neurons work in a concerningly similar manner to a decision tree. "AI" manufacturers are banking on the latter.<br /><br />

Anything that is inherently created in binary data, like mathematics or programming, stands to gain the most from LLMs. Their existence is not affected by being fed into one. To convert anything else into data, you implicitly lose an aspect of it. A text message does not convey all of the emotion behind it. A picture does not fully represent the wonderful experience leading to it. These are our attempts to snapshot and hold onto our fundamental thoughts and being, understandable only to us. When you feed these into an LLM, it does not understand, and the output always reflects this.<br /><br />

Programming genuises built LLMs on top of decades of work in neurobiology, neural networks, and deep learning. They should be lauded for their work, as it is fundamentally incredible. But we must draw a line between the definition of these creations, and the wholly separate world of human thinking.<br /><br /> 

I am blunt in my opinion that use of LLMs is little more than outsourcing your thinking. You can use it like a calculator, and it may not fundamentally differ too much from a physical one. When you ask it to create a shopping list, create recipe ideas, think of birthday present ideas, write a letter, you are sacrificing a part of yourself. To an entity that does not think like you do. Because it does not think.

<h2>The Future is Here (TBC)</h2>
A tool is nothing without hands to hold it. As powerful as a LLM might be, what it's applied to is of far greater concern than how it currently functions.<br /><br />

My hypothetical workplace is an interesting example of this. If I were to ever work in such a company, I might describe it as a gargantuan entity, reaching its growing tendrils into every facet of human life with every passing day. An entity that has amassed such power that it has totally thrown away the pretence of not doing evil, happy to stand with every vile being you could imagine, for the right price. A googolplex of malice.<br /><br />

Such a company would be built on decades of experience, talent, and hard work. Despite its best efforts, not all is smooth in a trillion-dollar beast: chains of command are inefficient and cumbersome, data is often siloed, unclear, and contradictory, and the vast quantity of moving parts makes it difficult to figure out what direction it's headed in. Nevertheless you might respect how it grew to its current position.<br /><br />

Imagine a presentation is sent around to the entire company one day. Copious slides of information, singing the praises of <a href="https://x.com/karpathy/status/1886192184808149383">"vibe coding"</a>. Look at how many uses it has in our daily work, the presentation proclaims!<br /><br />

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/ai-1.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Death 🙏</figcaption>
</figure>

Don't review the code changes, just feed it into the LLM and see what it says! Ask the LLM to review that document! Get AI to generate code, and push that shit into prod! Fix it later! With the LLM!<br /><br />

The LLM would be pushed deep into every service and product, both internal and external. Your widget has to have an LLM element now. Also why isn't it internally running on the LLM? Why did you make your own code for this?<br /><br />

This would give rise to the worst breed of imbecile. Someone who's probably intelligent in other ways, I'm sure, but you just wouldn't see it. This person's job is to "drive things forward". They must speak first on the call, wrap up proceedings on their schedule, and provide their opinion on every single matter. LLMs have turbocharged this brand of yappertron.<br /><br />

Imagine you are drafting a hundred lines of code for a future task. Before it's even completed, the yappertron, who's job has no relation to this, sends around an LLM-created summary of what your code does, including your managers, and provides their opinions on said LLM summary. They might also ask you to "check" the LLM summary for them<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[2]</a></sup>.<br /><br />

A leaderboard would be set up to see who submitted the most code involving "vibe coding". Security and best practice would go out the window. Envision a meeting where you are flat-out told that we can expedite a project timeline by foisting work on LLMs, submit the completed metrics to management, then "correct" them later if there's any issues. Whatever the LLM prescribes, implement that in prod. Don't worry about the LLM having no concept of data security, or data retention policies, or data privacy. Or local laws and regulations. That's not pertinent to the task at hand.<br /><br />

The classic phrase to describe this might be "move fast and break things". Large technology companies have often utilised this, it's not a new concept. LLMs simply provide a new unrivaled speed at which to do this.<br /><br />

I have no doubt where the future of such a workplace leads. Unconstrained LLMs will not make your work easier - they will set the new speed at which your work will be demanded, of which there will always be more. Plus the additional work of fixing stuff that the LLM inadvertently broke. Whatever skills you used to bring are now firmly secondary.<br /><br />

I was once brought aside in my totally separate workplace, and told that our executives had decided on a target of 30% growth rate. On every department, on every core metric (revenue, profit, user growth, etc), every year. How they reached that figure was never explained. It was simply decided, then it was so. Here is the result.

<h2>Disconnection</h2>

It's hard to maintain a level of knowledge to stay aware of this nonsense, and also stay sane. Similar to relentless negativity in the media, you can only detach yourself so much when you're living in the middle of it.<br /><br />

The pervasion of technology into our lives has been relentless. I'm strongly confident that it has broached the point of usefulness, and now actively impedes us. What do you stand to gain from another app on your phone?<br /><br />

As our lives grow ever-busier without purpose, the demand on technology to invent a solution grows stronger. I've seen friends on chatbot apps, slightly-more-raunchy chatbot apps, very-raunchy chatbot apps. Funny as it was in the first few days, the dawning realisation that their socialising was ever-increasingly dependent upon a machine was horrifying.<br /><br />

The ability to step back from this void grows increasingly difficult. My parents would often remind me that they would socialise via heading into the city centre, to the "old reliable spots", and running into whoever they ran into. How many of us are accessible this way now?<br /><br />

Being in the circles I'm in, even moreso than my distrust of technology, has been the catalyst for me to rebase my life centred around local communities. Yet the organisation of this still hinges on technology to hold it all together. The more you try to poke it, prod it, shift away from it, the more fragile it appears. 80% of my social life is dependent on Discord servers staying online.<br /><br />

When these services lean into LLMs with every update, it's tougher and tougher just to cling on.

<h2>The Secret Agenda</h2>
The truth is often stranger than fiction. But to wrap up this tirade, I don't have a grand conclusion. Sometimes the truth is drab and miserable.<br /><br />

There's money to be made here. Imagine a company forced to move at such breakneck speeds, complete so many Important Tasks every day, that the entire entity needed to be built and maintained with LLMs in mind. Imagine a solicitor who now doesn't have enough time to read through every page of a legal document, now that there's so much more to do. Imagine a doctor who, rather than providing their insight, relies increasingly on LLM output to reach a decision.<br /><br />

A company that provides such LLM services would have a wonderful stranglehold on the flow of information. The business competitive advantage would be immense - how could a fresh startup possibly hope to rival your LLM, when you've spent the last decade scraping and collating the entire Internet to use as a reference?<br /><br />

Venture capital investment throws itself at the nearest and loudest thing. Max risk, max reward is the name of the game. The Return on Investment is a fickle being, and must be sated with every offering at our feet. Imagine a game of bronze-ranked Rocket League where 6 cars blindly chase the ball without thought. It's not too dissimilar to that.<br /><br />

The capital demands a return. "AI" grabs headlines, attention, investment. Companies try to push boundaries to grow faster than their perceived rivals. All things you already knew.<br /><br />

In trying to find a solution to all this, my only finding was that there is no solution. To quote Abba Eban, men and nations behave wisely once they have exhausted all other alternatives.<br /><br />

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>Just like in real life.<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
        <p>The hypothetical recipient of this may be very tempted to get an LLM to review that summary and send it back.<a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>


</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is no clear threshold for when we've gone too far. It varies per person, per entity, per company, per nation. The consequences are never clear and understandable. Yet we are already in the middle of them after so little time, and I strongly fear it will get worse.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">THE LEGEND NEVER DIES</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/09/THE-LEGEND-NEVER-DIES.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="THE LEGEND NEVER DIES" /><published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/10/09/THE-LEGEND-NEVER-DIES</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/09/THE-LEGEND-NEVER-DIES.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
The year is 2012. Social media remains scattered. Youtube exists, but with massive restrictions on file size, length, and quality. Information is not centralised, and crucial information takes days or weeks to disseminate to a wider audience.<br /><br />

Gaming culture is, as it always has been, utter dogshit. Hatemail on Xbox Live remains at near-peak levels, and off in the recesses of Dark Souls 1 PvP, Games for Windows Live hosts an absolute shitshow of a community. Much like everywhere else.<br /><br />

Dark Souls, in its initial guise and still after the first few patches, horrendously unbalanced. Even up to 1.05, you could wear the heaviest tankiest armour in the game (<a href="https://darksouls.wiki.fextralife.com/Havel's+Set">Havel's Set</a>), yet still balance your stats to have a weight ratio of less than 50%, and therefore be able to ninjaflip (more invulnerability frames) with the <a href="https://darksouls.wiki.fextralife.com/Dark+wood+Grain+ring">Dark Wood Grain Ring</a>. This resulted in nigh-invincible rock men backflipping around until they stabbed you in the back with Darkmoon daggers for absurd damage. Because of the unpatched <a href="https://darksouls.wiki.fextralife.com/Hornet+Ring">Hornet Ring</a> of course. Nightmare material.<br /><br />

Patch 1.06 annihilated this meta, and with good reason. What still remained was the flavour of tryhard MLG bullshit that came in the form of hilariously bad hatemail, kill montages on youtube complete with awful music, and brain-dead herd mentality to follow the "meta".<br /><br />

The setting was perfect for OnlyAfro to unleash a weapon of absolute destruction on the Dark Souls and wider community. This <s>guy</s> <s>femboy</s> thing uploaded a parody of that style of tryhard dudebro nonsense, only to unleash an even more titanic wave of MLG terror:<br /><br />

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oyA8odjCzZ4?si=IwiTdSZUrItzyFUY" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe><br /><br />

It feels ridiculous to describe the impact this 180 second shitpost had. Those kinds of MLG-style montages turned into parodies overnight. /r/montageparodies owes most of its existence to this movement. Homodexuality remained a meme until Elden Ring released in 2022. Giantdad, not even a canonical character, is one of the most recognisable faces of Souls games. Half of the stylised words of this video materialised itself into the Souls community for years.<br /><br />

The slurs being patched out of the above video is strangely unfortunate. They're there as a parody, but there's little room for that level of irony on any level of the popular internet. Until Big Tech fully stops pretending to care of course.<br /><br />

Far funnier is the way little facts got rewritten over time. Giantdad was perceived as a "meta", but had no such impact outside of memes. Reading the swing of a Zweihander was mandatory to survive pre-1.06 patch, and didn't become any more difficult here. If you did get stunlocked, you could just toggle escape<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>.<br /><br />

Being a filthy tryhard at the time, I utilised the Giantdad build to wreck havoc in lower-level areas. By tweaking the build to operate at Level 11 instead of Level 99, I could swing the Bass Cannon at full power in the beginner areas, with the only downside being that I couldn't mid-roll. Not that you needed to, going up against someone thirty minutes into the game wielding a toothpick. This exploit took waves of attempts to fix - first in Dark Souls 2 using the dire <a href="https://darksouls.fandom.com/wiki/Soul_Memory">Soul Memory</a> mechanic, and later in Dark Souls 3 with the contentious <a href="https://darksouls3.wiki.fextralife.com/Summon+Range+Calculator">Weapon-Based Matchmaking</a>.<br /><br />

PvP was never the same after Dark Souls 1. It couldn't survive staying that way, mind you. But the outrageously unbalanced setup gave the community the tools to build weapons of mass destruction that ruined gaming for years (affectionate).<br /><br />

This post is an elaborate reminder for me to set up my shrine to Giantdad. Your understanding is appreciated.<br /><br />

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>Not that many knew this.<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>


</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The year is 2012. Social media remains scattered. Youtube exists, but with massive restrictions on file size, length, and quality. Information is not centralised, and crucial information takes days or weeks to disseminate to a wider audience.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I shortened I shortened every episode of anime bullshit to about a minute to about a blog post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/08/Abridgement.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I shortened I shortened every episode of anime bullshit to about a minute to about a blog post" /><published>2025-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/10/08/Abridgement</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/08/Abridgement.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
Whatever allure there is to immerse myself into hundreds of episodes of a show I watched years ago, the reality of the time investment has always been stronger. An infinitely growing list of things to do only makes this worse.<br /><br />

Abridged series of anime had a great run about a decade ago, running various series through layers of bullshit parodies, jokes and references that sometimes landed and often didn't. But they were charming. Little Kuriboh's Yu-Gi-Oh Abridged was the classic<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>, TeamFourStar's Dragonball Z Abridged had great quality, and PurpleEyesWTF's Code MENT gave me brain damage (affectionate).<br /><br />

Back in the modern world, I saw an anime abridged series that was done entirely using AI voices. That, plus the total drop-off in new interesting abridged series, seems to have killed off that sub-genre.

So for exploring old series that we all know aren't technically good, but hold affection in our hearts, yet demand boatloads of hours to assess again - what to do?<br /><br />

Caoimhe′ made me aware of the "I shortened Yu-Gi-Oh! down to about a minute" series, which has answered so many of my prayers. The joyfully-named Bing Bong 2.0 has done this for each episode of Yu-Gi-Oh, plus some other anime they took an interest in. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@bingbong2.0/playlists">None of them are short series</a>. The time investment for this project must be horrifying. <br /><br />

With thanks to Bing Bong, I've been able to watch some dumbass shows from my childhood and deliver thoughts and opinions as garbage as the shows themselves :3 

<h2>Yu-Gi-Oh</h2>
Season 1 has charm and stupidity in equal measure. "Screw the rules I have money" might have been coined by LittleKuriboh from Episode 1, but they shouldn't have bothered - no rules existed at this point. You play whatever cards you want, whenever you want, make up effects as you go along, and retcon stuff hoping that the kids won't notice.<br /><br />

Female characters are dire, and this does not improve as the series progresses. Kaiba is showing his potential of being a diva extraordinaire, but hasn't peaked yet. The plot does not stand up to being examined by a blind man who died 20 years ago. Best watched quickly to get to the slightly better stuff.<br /><br />

Season 2, the classic, is represented well. The overarching joke of this series is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xbXcRd0tVJ4">Egyptian God Cards</a>. If this confuses you, don't worry about it :)<br /><br />

Bing Bong now becomes far more comfortable ripping into the silliness of the English dub. The way every mention of death is just replaced with citing the Shadow Realm in increasingly unrealistic setups is particularly funny. Plus this moment that sent the entire watching party into hysterics:

<p>
    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/official_dueling_altitude.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;"></figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>
<p>

Also this moment that had me cackling hysterically in an otherwise empty house:

<p>
    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/ygo-2.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;"></figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>
<p>

Season 3 I had no time for as a kid, as I always resented it for ruining the pacing of the Battle City arc. The shortened version is solid as expected. But there's much less funny things to talk about here.<br /><br />

As a kid, I had no idea Season 4 was entirely filler. Watching it again, it makes a bit more sense. Way too much of the season is caught up in meaningless duels versus lackeys, and every side character inevitably getting a few episodes to themselves in a way that can't matierially change anything to the canon plot. A huge minus to Bing Bong here though - they didn't include this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_8tMN2aRE5w">absolute banger of an exchange</a>.<br /><br />

Season 5 was disappointing when I watched it half a lifetime ago, and even more disappointing now. Bakura is meaningless as a final villain if he was sidelined for so long. The plot meanders while he gets owned at every possible opportunity. Zorc is a stupid main boss with nothing interesting about him. Yu-Gi-Oh Forbidden Memories has a more cohesive plot finale than this for fucks sake.

<h2><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vBx9Fdx0Ir0&amp;list=PLQJu1XfXe2H8ShdPifL51I8oJZJ3R68UD">Naruto</a></h2>

Yes it's a cringe-ass anime series, but it has heart. Even if it has the worst second episode of an anime I can recall.<br /><br />

There's plenty of interesting fights, and this is amplified when there isn't any bullshit jutsus to throw around. Every fight involving either Shikamaru or Rock Lee is good. Almost every member of the Konoha 12 gets their spotlight, apart from Tenten of course, the sacrifical lamb for our amusement. More meaningful fights, like Orochimaru vs Hiruzen, are impactful and feel appropriately overwhelming in terms of power and skill versus what you've seen up until then.<br /><br />

Naruto is infamous for an absurd amount of filler. Kid me discovered the concept while wondering why the quality took a huge nosedive after the Sasuke Recovery Mission. Not even Bing Bong can make them good. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wU6tOsitpMw&amp;list=PLQJu1XfXe2H8ShdPifL51I8oJZJ3R68UD&amp;index=213">Apart from when they well and truly give up on trying</a>.<br /><br />

Female characters are not treated well in Naruto. This is a continuing trend here.<br /><br />

Bing Bong doesn't put parodies or comments into this series anywhere near as much as they did with Yu-Gi-Oh. Not 100% sure why.<br /><br />

<h2><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FbN0p6OJ-2U&amp;list=PLQJu1XfXe2H_M0vqmepXOZTGgOsdugpWk&amp;index=2">Naruto Shippuden </a></h2>

Oh how this series falls off a cliff. It starts pretty well, with the Kazekage Rescue Mission showing off a huge climb in power level since the timeskip. It feels appropriate though, and the Akatsuki are a great villainous team.<br /><br />

Akatsuki Suppression Mission is peak. Shikamaru gets a banger of an arc for him and his team. Kid me loved this arc more than any other, and they were right. Unfortunately it also shows the enormous glowing point where the series falls apart.<br /><br />

After significant build-up and two considerable fights, everything is derailed when Naruto himself shows up. He unironically asks the entire assault team to stand aside while he does it himself. He then proceeds to spam the same two jutsu over and over again, a trend that persists until the end of Shippuden. Fights become uninteresting, throwing away strategy for flashier and flashier hype moments.<br /><br />

The plot later rips itself to shreds. The 180-degree turn on Itachi's character was a huge mistake, dooming Sasuke into a world of eternal edginess.<br /><br />

The fucking Sharingan. It gains so many absurd abilities over Shippuden, rendering everything else in the show meaningless. Fuck Kamui, fuck Izanami, fuck Izanagi, fuck Amaterasu, fuck Kotoamatsukami, fuck Tsukuyomi, and especially fuck Susano'o. Over and over again, it reinforces that the truly strong people in this show were simply born with their abilities, and power scales them into the stratosphere. Hard work becomes a moot concept. Neji was right.<br /><br />

Also Hashirama Senju's DNA has been passed around in this world more than Genghis Khan's. And its abilities are bullshit.<br /><br />

The Fourth Great Ninja War arc, including the aimless filler that ruins it even further, is TWO HUNDRED AND EIGHTEEN EPISODES. Diabolically badly written and utterly irredeemable.<br /><br />

___<br /><br />

Tldr thanks Bing Bong you've helped me relive my childhood and speedrun the rage of thinking about Shippuden again

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>Technically this is still running, but it'll never finish either.<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>


</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</p></p></p></p></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whatever allure there is to immerse myself into hundreds of episodes of a show I watched years ago, the reality of the time investment has always been stronger. An infinitely growing list of things to do only makes this worse.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Games Roundup, Volume 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/02/Games-Roundup-Vol-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Games Roundup, Volume 1" /><published>2025-10-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-10-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/10/02/Games-Roundup-Vol-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/10/02/Games-Roundup-Vol-1.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
After over a month on ADHD medication, I'm beginning to feel confident in my ability to keep up hobbies again.<br /><br /> 

I haven't been able to finish a book in two years, struggle heavily to play games that aren't ones I've played to death, and overall fail to convert stray thoughts into new ideas that I could enjoy. It's early days, but the tide may be turning on this.<br /><br />

I've tried out a few new games recently. I find them easier than books to get engrossed in, and I don't feel as bad about discarding ones that don't sit right. There's enough games played recently that I feel confident compiling a few of them into a rambly little post.<br /><br />

Some of them are visual novels - yes they're games fuck off. And some of them are smutty. I aim to increase this percentage the more brazen I get.

<h2><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/236850/Europa_Universalis_IV/">Europa Universalis IV</a></h2>
It's an important virtue to give opportunities to those who may struggle with equal opportunities. I commend Paradox on their hiring of a team of blind imbeciles. Except for the part where they were tasked with the entire game's UI. I will have every single one of these people hunted down and executed.<br /><br />

The depth of the game appears to be impressive, though it's near-impossible to understand or interact with most of it. After several hours of attempts, I still have no fucking clue how trade routes work. The intricacies of diplomacy, the subtleties of warfare, the joys of empire building - EU4 presents all of this to you, shoved into a powered-on blender and politely asks you to stick your hand inside to check it out.<br /><br />

I will never achieve my goal of building a worldwide Cork empire.

<h2><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1392820/Milk_inside_a_bag_of_milk_inside_a_bag_of_milk/">Milk inside a bag of milk inside a bag of milk</a></h2>
Delightfully short and unnerving. Maybe the presentation on social anxiety and trauma will do something to you, maybe it won't. You'll find out quickly either way.<br /><br />

Impressive commitment to multiple languages considering the tiny size of the project. Also it's cheap.

<h2><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/310360/Higurashi_When_They_Cry_Hou__Ch1_Onikakushi/">Higurashi: When They Cry</a></h2>
<blockquote>Higurashi When They Cry is a sound novel. The music, backgrounds and characters work together to create a world that is the stage of a novel for the user to read. They laugh and cry and get angry. The user takes the point of view of the protagonist to experience the story.</blockquote>
Somehow an even stranger blurb for a visual novel than anything TYPE-MOON ever came up with.<br /><br />

Ryukishi07's work is a near-polar opposite to TYPE-MOON's slick presentation though: Higurashi is twisted and unsettling, clawing into your mind and gripping it until you simply won't care about the awful art style. You could apply the <a href="https://wiki.07th-mod.com/Higurashi/Higurashi-Getting-started/">07th Mod</a> to fix this, but you'll find it grows on you. Like an itch on your neck that grows and grows until you can't help but smile and laugh.<br /><br />

The slow burn throughout the chapters is almost painful. And the way the story turns near the end is contentious. But its unnerving narrative leaves a strong impression that simmers in your mind.

<h2><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1262350/SIGNALIS/">Signalis</a></h2>
See <a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/07/08/A-Halfway-Review-of-Signalis.html">here</a> for more detailed thoughts. I dropped it about halfway through.<br /><br />

The story may be good, but I saw none of it. The gameplay does little for me. Art style and sound design is neat though.

<h2><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1671210/DELTARUNE/">Deltarune: Chapters 3 &amp; 4</a></h2>
This was always going to be a delight. Toby Fox knocks it out of the park as usual.<br /><br />

The quality consistency in his games is astounding. His team simply does not drop the ball with banger boss fights, lovely soundtracks, and the silly humour you have to enjoy to appreciate.<br /><br />

Chapter 3 is oodles of fun, and Chapter 4 takes a fascinating different direction. Can't say more because Caoimhe′<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup> hasn't played the latter yet. Teehee.

<h2><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1989270/Slay_the_Princess__The_Pristine_Cut/">Slay The Princess</a></h2>
This is simply lovely. I adore games that fuck in a meta way with the narrative, and Slay The Princess goes above and beyond in delivering this.<br /><br />

Less is more when talking about this game. It exceeds expectations time and time again. Whenever you think you've figured it all out, there's another layer, another element, wrapped around a sweet little story with a cute bow tie on top.

<h2><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/392160/X4_Foundations/">X4: Foundations</a></h2>
I dreamed of my space empire simulator. Stellaris didn't click for me the first time, though a friend promised me that a revisit would unearth an entirely new game every time.<br /><br />

X4 targets the space trading and combat elements of empire building. I found it all a little tricky to process. The arbitrage mechanisms for trade seemed stupidly unrealistic and plain. No space empire would allow simple good transportation to work profitably like this. Nothing particularly wrong with the combat, but maybe it just wasn't for me.<br /><br />

The story isn't alluring in the slightest. The controls are overwhelmingly bizarre. The learning curve is absurd. Too many issues for me to consider spending more time here. I will keep hunting for my Frieza-core tyranny simulator for a while longer.

<h2><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/650700">Yume Nikki</a></h2>
Supposedly a beautiful work of art that can only be explored without a hint as to what's coming next. Except I didn't really care that much.<br /><br />

Sure you walk around, interact with the environment sometimes, and encounter bizarre oddities. But does any of it matter?<br /><br />

If it works for you, it works, I suppose.

<h2><a href="https://alexisroyce.itch.io/full-service-shop">Full Service Shop</a></h2>
Look it's a short VN about getting cyber genitals installed into you by a kinky technician of your choice. You either fuck with this or you don't.<br /><br />

Exit is based as fuck and I will commit corporate terrorism with her in exchange for 10 minutes of [REDACTED]. 

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>Pronounced "Caoimhe Prime". Also yes this is a different Caoimhe to me. Also hi Caoimhe :3<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>


</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[After over a month on ADHD medication, I'm beginning to feel confident in my ability to keep up hobbies again.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Girls &amp;amp; Boys</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/27/Girls-And-Boys.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Girls &amp;amp; Boys" /><published>2025-09-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-09-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/09/27/Girls-And-Boys</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/27/Girls-And-Boys.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
<a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt37441935/">Girls &amp; Boys</a> proposes a radical new train of thought: Can Trinity students be redeemed?<br /><br />

The path to redemption for Charlie (Liath Hannon) and Jason (Adam Lunnon-Collery) is aided primarily by their culchie accents, which makes every emotion delivered in the film far funnier. We need more of this.<br /><br />

Set over a single night in Dublin city, it touches on many aspects of the transfem experience, delves into macho rugby stereotypes and the personality suppression that inevitably follows, and highlights the eternal struggle of finding a reliable dealer on short notice. Overall a solid representation of the 21st century student lifestyle.<br /><br />

Liath Hannon is gorgeous and I will fawn over her for an extremely normal length of time. I have no idea what actions in her life led her to star in her first ever film, but I am very grateful for them. Her depiction of the transfem life nails a huge array of issues, anxieties, and fears, into 85 minutes. I wish we could have seen more expression of trans joy, but the plot didn't really allow for it.<br /><br />

Adam Lunnon-Collery does a good job of playing a stereotype that annoys me to hell - because I relate to it too much. Jason dodges meaningful questions, bases life decisions around the easy dependable route, and lacks the confidence to stand up for himself. Hence why he studies BESS<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>.<br /><br />

He does a solid job in sloppily hiding Jason's insecurities and past issues, resulting in delightful miscommunications and abandonments. By nature of wanting to punch past me in the face, I would also like to punch Jason in the face a similar amount. Sign of a good actor I suppose.<br /><br />

Actor Oisin Flynn handles the odious spiteful character Mark. His character's internship in the Irish Times was not explicitly shown but I see it in my heart.<br /><br />

The way various issues are presented throughout the film are done thoughtfully and mostly executed well. Donncha Gilmore did his homework and we are very appreciative for that.<br /><br />

In the first half, the main conflict is hinted at in many subtle ways. Almost everyone I've spoken to picked up on this via a different scene, or hint, or line of dialogue. Thinking about the first third of the film again, it takes on an interestingly different profile as a result.<br /><br />

The second half focuses directly on the conflict and resolution. Outside of being a touch too cliche in one or two scenes, each character is given space to trade barbs and lay out a very relatable history of painful events. Too many to list, frankly.<br /><br />

This post is mostly redundant as only the Lighthouse cinema in Dublin is showing this for a few more days. But if the opportunity ever presents itself, Girls &amp; Boys can safely be added to the "Too Fucking Real" watchlist.


<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>Business, Economics, and Social Sciences degree offered by Trinity College. I went to their open day in 2011, sat in the lecture hall for an introduction to BESS, and watched as a lecturer delivered the most diabolical one-liner I've ever heard in a university. "You could say we're the only university to offer economics and social sciences in the same course, but we prefer to say we're the best at it." I cannot exaggerate how much Trinity people actually think and act like this.<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>


</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Girls &amp; Boys proposes a radical new train of thought: Can Trinity students be redeemed?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What I’m Reading, Volume 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/02/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I’m Reading, Volume 4" /><published>2025-09-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-09-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/09/02/What-I&apos;m-Reading-Vol-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/02/What-I&apos;m-Reading-Vol-4.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
    Previous iterations:<br /><br />
    <ul>
        <li><a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/05/11/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-1.html">Volume 1</a></li>
        <li><a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/05/27/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-2.html">Volume 2</a></li>
        <li><a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/07/02/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-3.html">Volume 3</a></li>
    </ul>

<p><h1>Serious Reads</h1></p>

<h2><a href="https://blueberrylemonade.pika.page/posts/lets-make-up-fantasy-consoles-for-fun">Let’s make up fantasy consoles for fun</a></h2>
<blockquote>If you could wave a magic wand and wish a new fantasy console into the world…what would it be like? What constraints would it have to force developers to get creative? If it came with hardware, like the Playdate, what would the console physically be like?</blockquote>

I saw this a few weeks ago and loved the concepts. I've been on-off stewing over some ideas, but I think my first thought remains my favourite.<br /><br />

The DS and 3DS eras of Nintendo consoles had a stupendous long-term impact on console modding. Both, particularly the latter, are easy to bend to your will<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>, and can be supplanted with lovely choices of operating systems, software, and even emulation. This is a must - my dream console must have easily swappable hardware, and the software should be open to those who want to tinker away to their hearts content. Whatever a few hundred developers can achieve, the hundreds of thousands of fans should build on it in wonderful ways.<br /><br />

I'm also sticking with the split screen approach of the DS and 3DS. This was a radical design choice, and I have huge respect for games that experimented with this. Visual novels and other "passive" games could have the main activity on the top screen, and controls on the bottom, with the console providing an easy integration solution to avoiding screen clutter. Tactical and puzzle games often did similar. RPGs like Shin Megami Tensei<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[2]</a></sup> also fucked around and found out. It's very charming to me.<br /><br />

Accessibility is also critical. Modern phones, gaming controllers, etc, all demand dextrous hands to operate. I'm floored by how creative people become in their modding of games to be achievable (examples <a href="https://www.compusult.at/jouse">1</a>, <a href="https://quad.life/">2</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9fcK19CAjWM">3</a>, <a href="https://byowave.com/">4</a>), and to enable this further would be amazing. I don't think any default button configuration will ever fit most people's needs, but to allow this configuration - both in terms of physicial hardware and how the software interprets it - absolute freedom would be amazing. Similar to how <a href="https://frame.work">Framework laptops</a> allow for modular ports and slots, having this integrated into the surface of a game console, to allow you to switch in/out control types, would be really cool.<br /><br />

Going back to the DS and 3DS playbook, I do not care for massive hardware specs. If you want to put Crysis on this thing, do it yourself. Capping the hardware capabilities also mitigates an arms race of higher resolution textures, processing, rendering, that simply does not benefit the end product any more. So we're going 720p and you will like it. Get creative with your graphics again.<br /><br />

The closest console to broach these ideas might be the Steam Deck, which I respect Valve a lot for. Still, competition is always good.

<h2><a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2025/08/18/travel/budapest-diving-molnar-janos-cave"> Miles from the ocean, there’s incredible diving beneath the streets of Budapest </a></h2>
<blockquote>You can usually see as far as your torchlight reaches,” Csaba says. “But if people touch the walls or kick up the silt on the bottom of the passages, visibility drops to zero very fast.</blockquote>
Another half-article, half-photoset, but a really cool one nonetheless.

<h2><a href="https://jkap.io/cohost-postmortem/">(a) cohost postmortem: life after death</a></h2>
<blockquote>that's all I have for now. thank you for reading. if you used cohost, thank you for having used cohost. I'm told it was like a website in there.</blockquote>
Cohost is an odd area of interest for me. I was adjacent to it during its existence, creating an account in its opening weeks, dipping my toes in and out like an indecisive kid, never fully committing.<br /><br />

If I had taken the plunge, and landed among the type of communities I (eventually) found on Tumblr, I likely would have found yet more delightful niches to enjoy. I hear that they certainly did exist there, even ones I had never before heard of.<br /><br />

Cohost is now gone, and the lamentation over its passing fascinates me. There is a genuine loss of communities that I haven't observed throughout the Twitter migration, nor through various eras of Tumblr collapses.<br /><br />

What websites remain?

<h2><a href="https://www.sequencermag.com/ai-critical-thinking/">What AI can actually do to your critical thinking skills</a></h2>
<blockquote>In that sense, it’s not AI that will weaken every user’s critical thinking skills — but it might create a divide between people depending on whether it increases how much they engage with information, or reduces it. You can use AI as a springboard for ideas that spark creativity, or as a one-click replacement for creativity. Future AI agents may free up your working time to do more rewarding things, or it can embolden employers to demand that we “produce” more.</blockquote>
Every day I inch closer to being able to post my masterpiece on AI within Big Tech. This will do for now.<br /><br />

<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/08/enough-is-enough-i-dumped-googles-worsening-search-for-kagi/">Enough is enough—I dumped Google’s worsening search for Kagi </a></h2>
<blockquote>The feature that convinced me to start paying for Kagi was its Privacy Pass option. Based on a clean-sheet Rust implementation of the Privacy Pass standard (IETF RFCs 9576, 9577, and 9578) by Raphael Robert, this is a technology that uses cryptographic token-based auth to send an "I'm a paying user, please give me results" signal to Kagi, without Kagi knowing which user made the request. (There's a much longer Kagi blog post with actual technical details for the curious.)</blockquote>
Same as above re. my thoughts. I'm at the level of jadedness (read: age) where paying for a search engine seems increasingly viable.<br /><br />


<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2025/08/for-some-people-music-doesnt-connect-with-any-of-the-brains-reward-circuits/">For some people, music doesn’t connect with any of the brain’s reward circuits </a></h2>

<blockquote>The first thing that’s uncertain is whether specific musical anhedonia is a stable trait. Is the disconnection in the brain that seemingly causes it permanent, or can it be modulated through some kind of training, therapy, or even pharmacological interventions? Pallarés and his colleagues are already busy working on these questions, having started by looking at our DNA.</blockquote>
I've read this article twice, and in both cases I had video game music playing in the background. Each time, I stopped and realised that the music did little for me.<br /><br />

Fresh from new thoughts after an autism assessment this week<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[3]</a></sup>, I've been thinking about repetitive loops that I put myself through; sometimes out of perceived benefit, and sometimes out of sheer routine that does nothing for me. I'm increasingly finding that music falls into the latter for me.<br /><br />

I wouldn't call it a deficiency or issue of any kind, more that it simply does nothing for me, and I don't care to push myself to enjoy what other people enjoy just to keep up. There's many examples of this for me, and it gets easier with age, practice, and good company.<br /><br />

Exposure to many new types of people and inclinations has been great in this regard for me. I wonder if an asexual person would read this article and feel any thread of connection to Pallarés' research. Would someone who feels no attachment to food feel the same? Might do a full post on this train of thought.

<h2><a href="https://www.sequencermag.com/cyborg-rights-depend-on-new-and-better-legal-protections/">Cyborg rights depend on new and better legal protections</a></h2>
<blockquote>A new kind of technology is necessary to disrupt the status quo— one that further obscures the traditional distinction between body and device. The subject of my last piece, the heart-powered pacemaker (also called TECH), may do just that, potentially offering legal protections for cyborgs.<br /><br />

A key challenge is defining what constitutes that body and the corresponding rights it should be granted. Even when legal rulings feel black and white, the language underpinning them concerns nebulous philosophical questions. How do we compare the degree of embodiment between all of the different kinds of medical devices in a fair and precise manner?</blockquote>
Given my interests, I thought I'd have more background knowledge on this. But I don't, and it's a fascinating discussion that will only intensify into the future.<br /><br />

The varying needs and wants of technology implanted into the body is stunningly broad. I hold a diverse range of positions on this scale, depending on what my upcoming cardiac and MRI scans will report. Closer to the "wants" side of things, I would absolutely modify the fuck out of myself at the first opportunity<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[4]</a></sup>.<br /><br />

If, voluntarily or otherwise, I'm in a position where mechanical implants are essential to my continued wellbeing, do I still retain full legal control over myself?<br /><br />

A near-inverse thought - is there a risk that technology as a form of control could be strengthened by this movement? With the legal framework adjusted to protect "it" and not the host it's embedded into? There's very few real-life cases that come to mind. But I'm envisioning jobs that require augmented motor control (eg. exoskeletons for moving heavy items), or heightened senses (eg. a surgeon whose precision relies on perfected vision). If a corporation retains ownership of a device that's implanted into an employee, do they enjoy a higher degree of control over the individual via any future legislation?<br /><br />

I am confident in my view that there will eventually emerge a movement of people who wish to preserve the biological above the mechanical, holding a moral and ethical position that we should not be mandated to accept any kind of technological intrusion on the body. I strongly respect this position, and feel that this perspective is intertwined with the above debate. There are no easy answers.

<p><h1>Light Reads</h1></p>

<h2><a href="Link">Yearning for Meaning: Maddy Thorson’s Super Mario World Romhacks and the Metamodernist Impulse</a></h2>
Now you may be thinking: What is a title like that doing in the Light Reads section?<br /><br />
<blockquote> If personal things happening to Sonic is the theme of this sincerity amidst the chaos, then it is the most appropriate thing in the romhack that the final overworld event, after Sonic completes “Masterpiece” the level, is the revealing of letters spelling out “your gay.” Again humorous, especially with its purposeful misspelling, but also an honest revelation of the self. This is what we can take away: try to save the world and to make the perfect creation, but also know it’s enough to grow into and be yourself.</blockquote>
Yeah


<h2><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_English_words_containing_Q_not_followed_by_U">List of English words containing Q not followed by U</a></h2>
I'm gonna be playing Scrabble with Rain again soon and need to learn this page off by heart.<br /><br />

---<br /><br />

I don't really have anything else light to show off, so instead here's one of my favourite recent snippets of F1 radio banter (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=REPCLR0utMA">source</a>):

<p>
    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/f1-1.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Gianpiero Lambiase gives me life</figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>
<p>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>Cold metal following the thoughts of the human is <a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/08/12/Virtuous-Mechsploitation.html">very neat to me :3 </a><a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
        <p>Shoutout to SMT Devil Survivor for having the COMP demon-summoning device actually be a 3DS that the characters modded to run the Demon Summoning Program. Absolutely fucking radical <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
        <p>If this surprises you, please inform me via inefficient communication protocol of your choice so I can laugh at it more thoroughly <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4">
        <p>Let's be real here, I already do &gt;:3 <a href="#fnref:4" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>

<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</p></p></p></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Previous iterations: Volume 1 Volume 2 Volume 3]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sandy Lane</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/01/Sandy-Lane.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sandy Lane" /><published>2025-09-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-09-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/09/01/Sandy-Lane</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/09/01/Sandy-Lane.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
It's been almost two years since I moved into my house. This used to be an area of severe insecurity for me, and the feeling never really leaves. So I'm quite pleased with how it turned out.<br /><br />

The house is named after Sandy<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>, naturally. I thought getting a place without a garden would upset him. So I turned down a tiny red-brick house closer to town<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[2]</a></sup>, and a terraced city-centre hideaway around the corner from my old flat<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[2]</a></sup>.<br /><br />

Instead I chose a "maturing" neighbourhood. In non-estate-agent terms, a former council housing estate that's less rough than even a decade ago. The upsides being that the garden's huge<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[3]</a></sup>, the price was manageable, and it has a driveway: an increasing rarity in modern builds. And I like Takumi too much :3 <br /><br />

The downside was that the previous owner left the place like shit. Even in the eight months between the viewing and moving in, the garden had become totally overgrown, interior was not cleaned once, and there were horrors perfectly within my comprehension buried in the back garden. Fuck you [REDACTED].<br /><br />

It's taken a stupid amount of time, effort, and money to get it fixed up to the extent where I can host people. But after the final big project, I think we're finally there.<br />

<h2>Kitchen</h2>

<div class="gallery-with-caption">
  <div class="image-gallery">
    <div class="expandable-image" id="sl-1">
      <a href="#sl-1">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-1.jpg" alt="Kitchen Before" />
      </a>
      <div class="expanded-view">
        <a href="#" class="close-button"></a>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-1.jpg" alt="Kitchen Before" />
        <div class="navigation">
          <a href="#sl-2" class="next-prev-button">Next Image</a>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="expandable-image" id="sl-2">
      <a href="#sl-2">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-2.jpg" alt="Kitchen After" />
      </a>
      <div class="expanded-view">
        <a href="#" class="close-button"></a>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-2.jpg" alt="Kitchen After" />
        <div class="navigation">
          <a href="#sl-1" class="next-prev-button">Previous Image</a>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>

  <p class="image-caption">
    Hey look I can make images expand on a click now! <sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[4]</a></sup>
  </p>
</div>

The kitchen was the first room I looked into when I opened the front door for the first time. The floor was coated in layers of dirt, mostly carried from outside, via the previous owner's moving crew who deposited half the garden soil around the house.<br /><br />

Pictures do not convey the level of dirt on everything: the cupboard doors, handles, inside of the oven, <b>everything</b>.

I ripped this bitch to shreds only last month, via the following steps:<br />
<ul>
  <li>Pulling the wall tiles off - this required re-plastering of the wall in certain areas. Not fully completed as the right-hand side of this room will have new tiles put on. Left side is to be scraped and painted.</li>
  <li>Tearing out the original ceiling, fully replastering it, with integrated lighting</li>
  <li>Annihilate the old appliances and furniture from existence, and install new Ikea furnishings. Ikea quality is fine, perfectly befitting of a small room that will hopefully be extended and retrofitted in another decade or two.</li>
  <li>Entirely new appliances across the board. Mostly Bosch apart from the fridge freezer cos that shit's pricey. Magnetic induction hob is a treat and I love it</li>
</ul>

There's also some strip lighting for the countertop which was a neat addition. Pretty sure I didn't request it but Ikea added it anyways. Decent spend of €100.

<h2>Bathroom</h2>

<div class="gallery-with-caption">
  <div class="image-gallery">
    <div class="expandable-image" id="sl-5">
      <a href="#sl-5">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-5.jpg" alt="Bathroom Before" />
      </a>
      <div class="expanded-view">
        <a href="#" class="close-button"></a>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-5.jpg" alt="Bathroom Before" />
        <div class="navigation">
          <a href="#sl-6" class="next-prev-button">Next Image</a>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="expandable-image" id="sl-6">
      <a href="#sl-6">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-6.jpg" alt="Bathroom After" />
      </a>
      <div class="expanded-view">
        <a href="#" class="close-button"></a>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-6.jpg" alt="Bathroom After" />
        <div class="navigation">
          <a href="#sl-5" class="next-prev-button">Previous Image</a>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
<p class="image-caption">Pretty sure no plumber will ever work with me again after I handed this project to them</p>
</div>

This was absolute hell to work on from start to finish. When there were contractors in to help with the floorboards, one of them later confessed to me "I nearly burst into tears".<br /><br />

The existing floor was comprised of destroyed lino, secured via chipboard that was glued directly onto the floorboards. Every single one of these elements was in dire condition. You might be able to pull the lino off the chipboard, but hammers, chisels, and power tools couldn't pull most of the chipboard off.<br /><br />

You may notice the wall tiles don't reach the floor. This is because some of the pipes were added afterwards, and the previous owner decided to just shove them into a section that wouldn't fit them. Also see the top corner where they inserted a pipe through the ceiling with the help of a cluster grenade.<br /><br />

Also the shower was falling apart and leaking directly onto the floor and through the floorboards.<br /><br />

Every single item in this room had to be brand new. There's some cheaper items (toilet and radiator are on the budget side) but everything else was pretty nice. The tiles ended up working out really well - big cream ones on the floor are easy to clean, and the blue for the shower was a bit of a gamble but worked out ok.<br /><br />

Even the walls are new. There's waterproof membrane installed behind the tiles, which does make the room ultimately smaller, but eliminates moisture issues.<br /><br />

The light has day/night functions that I never use, but I appreciate the thought.<br /><br />

Also I may have put a lot of the budget into a good shower. Teehee.

<h2>Rear Bedroom</h2>

<div class="gallery-with-caption">
  <div class="image-gallery">
    <div class="expandable-image" id="sl-7">
      <a href="#sl-7">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-7.jpg" alt="Rear Bedroom Before" />
      </a>
      <div class="expanded-view">
        <a href="#" class="close-button"></a>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-7.jpg" alt="Rear Bedroom Before" />
        <div class="navigation">
          <a href="#sl-8" class="next-prev-button">Next Image</a>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="expandable-image" id="sl-8">
      <a href="#sl-8">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-8.jpg" alt="Rear Bedroom After" />
      </a>
      <div class="expanded-view">
        <a href="#" class="close-button"></a>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-8.jpg" alt="Rear Bedroom After" />
        <div class="navigation">
          <a href="#sl-7" class="next-prev-button">Previous Image</a>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
<p class="image-caption">You're not seeing the final result because I never put the sliding door on the wardrobe :3 <sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[5]</a></sup></p>
</div>

"The Orange Room", as my then-partner put it. Originally I tried a forest green on the walls, and found it dimmed the brightness too much. So we went with an ochre red that was initially trialled in the guest bedroom.<br /><br /> 

Also I did paint that final wall in ochre red, after a few weeks of doing nothing about it. Brighter than it looks.<br /><br />

Most of the dirt in the carpet comes from a fireplace in the corner. Why a fireplace was being ignited in a room containing only a tumble dryer and a treadmill, I do not know. Cream carpets were used for all of the upstairs bedrooms, and work pretty well.<br /><br />

One feature of this brand of council house is that the gas boiler is situated in a small sub-room within the rear-facing bedroom. Which the plumbers all find quite amusing.<br /><br />

That bedframe was my one treat for myself in this room. A stupidly-good-quality mattress is up next.<br /><br />

Plenty of wall decorations later went up - mostly artwork from local artists. I also got some art prints from the Crawford Art Gallery that I still need to put up.<br /><br />

<h2>Guest bedroom</h2>
<div class="gallery-with-caption">
  <div class="image-gallery">
    <div class="expandable-image" id="sl-3">
      <a href="#sl-3">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-3.jpg" alt="Guest Bedroom Before" />
      </a>
      <div class="expanded-view">
        <a href="#" class="close-button"></a>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-3.jpg" alt="Guest Bedroom Before" />
        <div class="navigation">
          <a href="#sl-4" class="next-prev-button">Next Image</a>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div>
    
    <div class="expandable-image" id="sl-4">
      <a href="#sl-4">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-4.jpg" alt="Guest Bedroom After" />
      </a>
      <div class="expanded-view">
        <a href="#" class="close-button"></a>
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/sl-4.jpg" alt="Guest Bedroom After" />
        <div class="navigation">
          <a href="#sl-3" class="next-prev-button">Previous Image</a>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
<p class="image-caption">The bed kinda takes up 70% of the room. Don't worry about it</p>
</div>

Probably the easiest room to improve. Floorboards needed no modification to fit carpets on top, two layers of paint did the walls, and triple-glazed windows (not pictured) were sufficient.<br /><br />

Another council house oddity - that storage on the left links directly to a ventilation hole in the exterior wall. So this took some amateur DIY to plug up and stop everything from freezing in winter. Bizarre architectural choice.

<h2>Other Works</h2>
<ul>
  <li>The front bedroom isn't pictured here because the current occupier moved their stuff in before I could get a good pic</li>
  <li>This house had the worst possible energy efficiency rating when I moved in. Triple-glazed windows at the front (rear already had double-glazed) and new exterior doors is my progress to-date. Next step would be exterior wall insulation, which is prohibitively expensive. Like €15,000 expensive.</li>
  <li>Living room didn't need much work apart from new couches and armchairs</li>
  <li>Garden work is still ongoing. Maybe to be finished this winter. Maybe.</li>
</ul>

I have a spreadsheet tracking the total spend on this house, and it's reached a horrifying number. But it's all been good investments so far. However, as the essential projects all get ticked off, my mind drifts towards catios at the back and flamethrower defences at the front. Teehee.<br /><br /> 


<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>Informally. If you search this house name online, you'll surely find others, but not this one<a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
        <p>Correctly, in hindsight<a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
        <p>A deliberate design choice. This would have been soon after World War 2 and The Emergency, and allowing families some semblance of agricultural self-sufficiency was a local government priority. Imagine that being pitched these days. <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4">
        <p>No you cannot move between pictures via keyboard presses. Or click to escape. That is Javascript heresy.<a href="#fnref:4" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:5">
        <p>I don't have a landscape picture of the original, no portrait picture of the new, and couldn't be arsed changing the code to make this bit look good<a href="#fnref:5" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>



<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</p></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been almost two years since I moved into my house. This used to be an area of severe insecurity for me, and the feeling never really leaves. So I'm quite pleased with how it turned out.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Degustation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/30/Degustation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Degustation" /><published>2025-08-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/30/Degustation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/30/Degustation.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
<blockquote>Eleven times you take the boat out here, where we introduce every dish, every single time. We tell you exactly what we are feeding you. We create elaborate stories. We make it fun. We even give you a copy of the menu to take home. Please tell me one dish you ate the last time you were here. Or the time before. One. Please.</blockquote>

At this section of watching <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt9764362/">The Menu</a>, I was stumped for a minute. I had previously dined in Ichigo Ichie twice<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[1]</a></sup>, back when it ran a thirteen-course menu and carried a prestigious Michelin star. And in this moment, I could only think of a single dish I fully remembered.<br /><br />

No disrespect to the restaurant of course. Both times I waddled out of there very pleased with myself. But the egg dashi broth, dish twelve out of thirteen, was the only one that's survived in the mind. The rest is a collection of accessories - crisp interior design, beautiful plates to compliment the foods, slick staff that operated to the highest degree. And a hefty price tag.<br /><br />

To twist the knife some more, I also have a framed copy of the menu from one of the visits. It's entirely in Hiragana and Kanji, and I still can't read half of it. Stunning.<br /><br />

Chef Miyazaki repurposed Ichigo Ichie almost two years ago, into a bistro restaurant that carried almost none of the ostentation, a clean and simple menu that still delivered, and the financial barriers to entry torn down. I imagine he's quite happier with this setup.<br /><br />

The level of artistic faff in The Menu is stupendous. Chef Slowik presents the first few courses with the camera framing him as some sort of religious prophet, even as the proceeding courses aim to push the clientele into seeing through the bullshit. His soft voice delivers the most venomous of lines with absolute beauty. He convinces you the viewer with ease that this is all beyond your comprehension, an act of culinary brilliance even as the counter-evidence sits directly in front of you: a pitiful shard of fish sitting atop some jaunty rocks. Or some broken emulsion.<br /><br />

It's put me on notice. Whatever about occasional restaurant visits, my own cooking was going to lean down this path if I didn't stop myself. Not to the same extent maybe, but definitely losing that touch of love that carries everything.<br /><br />

I cooked <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8-9EWcxtPPY">Lu Ruo Fan</a> for some friends that evening. Partly because it was a hearty-ish meal and I love doing that shit in big batches. Partially because it was from one of the cuisines I think I most enjoy<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[2]</a></sup>. And partially cos I thought it would impress people.<br /><br />

Maybe it did, but that should be a secondary thought at best. There's a vague gap between doing something new and cool to have fun exploring cuisines, and doing it to fuel the ego. The latter doesn't last, and it's hard to figure out when you're in the middle of this dance.<br /><br />

I'm certainly not too far gone yet. I think I can cook better than <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s597UDb8qkE">Tyler's Bullshit</a>, and haven't said anything to put myself on Chef Slowik's execution list<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">[3]</a></sup>. But maybe I should ease off on watching videos on Michelin-starred New York chefs preparing Korean barbeque.<br /><br />

I had more thoughts on The Menu, but they've slid from the mind since I started typing. Much like the clients, it doesn't entirely hold up to intense scrutiny. But the message is clear: cook for love.<br /><br />

Movie nights are going to be a regular thing at my place now. I'm thinking cheeseburgers next week.<br /><br />

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
    <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
        <p>Given that Ichigo Ichie means "once in a lifetime", this is additionally funny in hindsight <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
        <p>The others mainly being Cantonese, Shanghai (read: Xiaolongbao), Louisiana Creole, and Italian <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">↩</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
        <p>Yet<a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink"> ↩</a></p>
    </li>
    </ol>
</div>

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eleven times you take the boat out here, where we introduce every dish, every single time. We tell you exactly what we are feeding you. We create elaborate stories. We make it fun. We even give you a copy of the menu to take home. Please tell me one dish you ate the last time you were here. Or the time before. One. Please.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You Won’t BELIEVE This Game Exists! (NOT CLICKBAIT)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/25/You-Wont-Believe-This-Game-Exists.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You Won’t BELIEVE This Game Exists! (NOT CLICKBAIT)" /><published>2025-08-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/25/You-Wont-Believe-This-Game-Exists</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/25/You-Wont-Believe-This-Game-Exists.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
Yu-Gi-Oh: Forbidden Memories is the stupidest most broken appallingly imbalanced piece of shit video game ever created. I love it to bits.<br /><br />

Released in Japan in 1999, and elsewhere in 2002, this game ruined several years of my childhood as I spent countless hours trying to beat it. I never did, and have no desire to try again. Skill will only bring you so far - you require hours of grinding to get top-tier cards, in-depth game exploitation knowledge, and the most absurd run of RNG imagineable.<br /><br />

The gameplay attempts to track the Yu-Gi-Oh card game, with one slight flaw: development of Forbidden Memories began before the card game was released. So the devs had some knowledge of the cards that would come out, basic mechanics in terms of monsters/spells/traps, life points, etc. But everything else, Forbidden Memories just kind of... made up.<br /><br />

<p>
<ul>
    <li>You can only play one card onto the field each turn, and it must be before you interact with the field</li>
    <li>It introduces a monster Star Sign system to create weaknesses/strengths versus other Star Signs, which simply does not exist outside of this game</li>
    <li>Monster effects do not exist</li>
    <li>Most of the game takes place in ancient Egypt rather than with the actual Yu-Gi-Oh cast. I find this quite charming but kid me was not impressed</li> 
    <li>Trap cards will automatically activate at the earliest legal moment, whether you or the opponent wants it or not</li>
    <li> Each monster card - and there are hundreds of them - have individually crafted 3d models, specifically for battle animations that most players will never see because you have to press a different button to see the 3d battle format, and the game never tells you this</li> 
    <li>Ritual cards do exist, however they're disgustingly bad to the point of it being endearing. You have to sacrifice 2-3 specific monsters to obtain the ritual monster, except THE GAME NEVER TELLS YOU WHICH MONSTERS TO SACRIFICE. AND THE MONSTERS HAVE TO BE ON THE FIELD IN ORDER TO BE SACRIFICED, IN A GAME WHERE YOU CAN ONLY PLAY ONE CARD PER TURN WHAT THE FUCK</li>
    <li>The fusion system hahaha holy shit</li><br /><br />
</ul>

Beating an opponent gives you a reward card, which operates off an absurdly opaque system where it judges how aggressive/tactical your gameplay was, and how quickly you ended the battle, then rates you as either "Power" or "Technical" and gives you a grade. The higher the grade, the better the card in that "Power" or "Technical" category. Good luck grinding S-rank Technicals.<br /><br />

Your reward for this, once you clear some huge power spikes, is a final boss gauntlet run of 6 opponents in a row. Each of these opponents has twenty cards in their card, rather than your five. They can see your hand at all times, as well as your face-down cards. Some of them (read: Seto) have cards that are so absurdly powerful that if they play multiple of them, there is absolutely nothing whatsoever you can do. You can board wipe sure, but that leaves you open to another 4500 ATK direct hit the next round. In a game with 8000 life points. And he has three of the stupid bastards.<br /><br />

There is absolutely no strategy that will save you if the game decides to screw you on RNG. Bad hand - dead. Opponent plays multiple Blue-Eyes Ultimate Dragons DIRECTLY FROM THE HAND - dead. Game freezes at a very specific point because of a scratch in the disc - very dead. Last one might have been a me thing.<br /><br />

Did you think I wasn't going to elaborate on the fusion system? Well this is my blog and I do whatever I want, so enjoy:

<ul>
    <li>Cards are fused together in the hand without Polymerization</li>
    <li>The list of allowed fusions is manually coded in, with no tags in the code to specify which fusion material cards are beasts/machines/dark/male/female/whatever. <a href="https://gamefaqs.gamespot.com/ps/561010-yu-gi-oh-forbidden-memories/faqs/16613">Here is a quick summary of the fusions. It is insane.</a>
    <li>There are plenty of instances where fusing two monster will make one that is weaker in every single regard</li>
    <li>To copy a specific section I saw via a friend, here is some of the bizarre fusion rules coded in:
        <blockquote>[Female]<br />
        These are monsters that fuse with Stone Ogre Grotto to become Mystical Sand.<br />
        Notes:<br />
        - Performance of Sword, Spirit of the Harp and Spirit of the Winds are not
        female, even though they can be equipped with Cyber Shield and certainly look
        female.<br />
        - Mystical Sand, Empress Judge and Cosmo Queen can be
        considered female, as they can be equipped with Cyber Shield and look female,
        but they don't participate in any fusions as females because their attack level
        is too high.<br />
        - every female and every monster that can be equipped with Cyber Shield can be
        equipped with Electro-whip, but there are dozens of monsters that can be
        equipped with Electro-whip that aren't female and can't be equipped with
        Cyber Shield<br />
        - all females can be equipped with Malevolent Nuzzler<br />
        </blockquote>
    </li>
    <li>Some other funny segments that I found:
        <blockquote>Note: every dragon can be equipped with Dragon Treasure, but there are 36 monsters that can be equipped with Dragon Treasure that are not dragons.</blockquote>
        <blockquote>[Bugrothian]<br />
                    These are monsters with strictly less than 1850 attack points that have primary type Aqua or first guardian star Neptune and that are not Fish with strictly less than 1600 attack points nor Sea Serpents.</blockquote>
    </li>
    <li>You can fuse spell and trap cards together what the fuck</li>

<p>
    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/ygo-1.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">WHY IS THIS ALLOWED</figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>
<p>

Fuck this stupid baka piece of shit. Except I love it because the soundtrack slaps.<br /><br />

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iqp9jzmWhto?si=6MX5VADcgWmYXyrZ" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe><br /><br />

Obviously Konami had to make a sequel. And they continued to be incredibly normal about it :3 <br /><br />

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/ygo-1.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">👍</figcaption>
</figure>

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</p></li></ul></p></p></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yu-Gi-Oh: Forbidden Memories is the stupidest most broken appallingly imbalanced piece of shit video game ever created. I love it to bits.]]></summary></entry></feed>