<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-06-25T12:12:01+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/atom.xml</id><title type="html">Sandy’s Palace</title><subtitle>Rosa&apos;s gay little website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Test Recovery Please Ignore</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/23/Test-Recovery-Please-Ignore.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test Recovery Please Ignore" /><published>2025-06-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/23/Test-Recovery-Please-Ignore</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/23/Test-Recovery-Please-Ignore.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>

<b>Content warning: Abuse, PTSD &amp; Physiological effects of PTSD</b><br /><br />

A friend asked me recently to outline potential triggers for me. She was thinking of visual, auditory, or tactile stimuli. Anything that might cause a flashback or panic response. <br /><br />

Even after responding I know my words were lacking and took too long. The thoughts still only exist in a incomprehensible format, squashed into the back of my brain in the hopes that they'd rot.<br /><br />

--- <br /><br />

I was reading We Know The Devil recently. After Heaven Will Be Mine, I knew I'd be in for a good time; a short and sweet VN that would leave a lot resting on the mind. Of course, it did. <br /><br />

Each of the three main characters runs the risk of being isolated as the story takes hold. Each time you choose two of the three to interact, the third gets left behind. Saving a scenario where you tactically keep all three in equal contact, one of them is left exposed to their fears made manifest.<br /><br />

Second playthrough, I see Jupiter covered in blood, seeped into her hair and body. One of her myriad hands is gently cupping her chin. Another grips her from behind. Another holds a separate hand, reaching from impossible angles. It's only given a sparse few lines of text. I read through it all without a second thought.<br /><br />

Lying in bed afterwards, the imagery doesn't let go. I grab my Steam Deck and speed through through the entire thing again. This time I stare at it until my eyes hurt. Then stare at it until my face hurts, then my limbs, then my thoughts, then my thoughts, then my thoughts.<br /><br />

Jupiter's history is never quite said out loud. There might be an association, a hint that something has made her what she is, but you will never receive confirmation or closure. She tries, and fails, to create a combination of words that make sense. <br /><br />

There are no perfect descriptors, no perfect metaphors, but this one worked for me. WKTD achieved in 30 seconds what I failed to do for years. I didn't sleep for days after that. <br /><br />

---<br /><br />

In the medical world, there is this fundamental disconnect between practitioner and patient. The latter is always fighting to reach through to the former, to convince them that their experiences are real and worthy of more than brief, cursory attention. I've never once bridged this gap in a way that matters. <br /><br />

My mother and I used to look into the root cause of my seizures. The trail went cold after MRIs turned up ok - the desire to investigate them further disappeared once they couldn't tie back to symptoms identifiable in a book. When asked whether they could be brought on by other stresses, the neurologist folder her arms and stared at me in silence until I left.<br /><br />

It's so brushed aside that a consistent term still doesn't exist. The most modern version - functional seizures - drifts in between a mental and neurological space. To the extent that most medical professionals simply refer you back to the other category rather than think about it too hard.<br /><br />

Functional seizures can trigger based on a variety of stressors that I don't fully understand. Though I can identify the cascade of effects: from when the senses become overloaded, to when the body gives up, to when I'm on 5% of brainpower, fighting to ignore the tsunami of sensory signals from every direction, and just faintly aware that my tongue is stuck in my throat.<br /><br />

Tellingly, they most frequently happen when I'm on my own.<br /><br />

From a sensory perspective, the only thing that makes sense is that it doesn't make sense. All you can see is black but not quite black, yet the brightest thing you've ever seen. All you can hear is an advertisement for tinnitus. You'll taste something metallic and inorganic. You can feel the nerves in your limbs but not what they touch. <br /><br />

They were much easier to suppress when I didn't think about things very hard. Unfortunately I now care about my life, and my hormonal balance lets me actually feel emotion. Which has once again exposed this stupid bastard of a thing. <br /><br />

Things are better though. I can identify the slide towards a seizure, the 2-second warning before I hit the floor, and post-collapse recuperation. Two out of these three primarily involve Lucozade Sport, but if it works it works. <br /><br />

---<br /><br />

The wonders of modern medicine have left me to work on this myself. What seems like the biggest disconnect is a lack of easily-treatable symptoms. Sure you passed out from thinking about sharp things too much, but have you repeated it several times in a controlled environment? No? What a shame.

If the knife doesn't leave a visible mark, they don't seem to be too fussed about it. So I get to bother you lot about it instead :3<br /><br />

I am back to staring at a list of potential triggers. It's embarrassingly short. But writing one makes the next one easier. Some day they may come naturally. 
</p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Little Joys, Volume 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/16/Little-Joys-Vol-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Little Joys, Volume 1" /><published>2025-06-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-06-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/16/Little-Joys-Vol-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/16/Little-Joys-Vol-1.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
    This is a silly little thing that popped into my head today. I would like to write about the small things that give me far more enjoyment than they should.<br /><br />
    
    Similarly, the act of writing about it would give me a badly needed positivity push. The other thoughts I would put words to were worse; this is preferable for everyone involved.<br /><br />

    ---<br /><br />

    This week I was able to convert a friend-of-a-friend into a friend. Being in newfound proximity to so many cool people is one of my favourite blessings that has ever happened to me.<br /><br />

    Among some trinkets and cool things she brought over were these Danish liquorice sweets - one of them standard, one of them pre-salted. I nabbed the pre-salted ones.<br /><br />

    I haven't had liquorice since I was a kid, didn't particularly like it then, found it too strong. They somehow avoided me for twenty-ish years. So I thought it'd be a neat opportunity to try them out in a new context.<br /><br />

    I made the dire mistake of chewing into the first few I tried - do not do this. Suck for at least 30 seconds. Insert a joke of your choice here.<br /><br />
    
    They are utterly bizarre. Not quite tasting like liquorice that I've ever had before, nor liquorice that's had salt added into it. Another, possibly more horrifying, thing. Still unsure.<br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/gajol-1.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">This has earned its place in the cool gift collection</figcaption>
    </figure>

    Regardless, a cool little thing that I try out every day, and discover a different aspect to it every time.<br /><br />

    (Some research surfaced that the German language version of these treats are not allowed to be given to children, which also made me laugh.)<br /><br />

    ---<br /><br />

    I played Deltarune Chapters 3 and 4 last week and this week. The bar was high, but it was almost certainly always going to be great.<br /><br />

    Naturally, Toby served us up another couple of blinders. Chapter 3 is good fun, though not quite hitting the peaks of Chapter 2 - Queen was always going to be unbeatable. Chapter 4 throws us into the proper story of Deltarune, but reserves time to fuck around with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pZNO0FmyZ0U">delightful boss fights</a>.<br /><br />

    Fun new fact - I now hum this theme when enjoying bothering someone :3 <br /><br />

    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <img src="/assets/images/blog/deltarune.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">This happened organically and made me laugh far more than it should have</figcaption>
    </figure>

    ---<br /><br />

    I'm enjoying and appreciating physical contact with people for the first time in my life. Very new and very heartfelt.<br /><br /> 

    ---<br /><br />

    Muffin had his first birthday last week. I still want to do a huge page on this site for him, and another for Sandy. The little bastards deserve them :3<br /><br />

    ---<br /><br />

    <a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/03/09/Say-Hi-To-Takumi-The-Toyota-GT86.html">Takumi</a> gets a great audience from some kids I pass on the street.<br /><br />

    Passing some kids just leaving school, one of them belts out a "REV IT!!!!!" and I'm obliged to give Takumi maximum beans. Seeing him cheer in my rear view mirror made me laugh for a good week.<br /><br />

    Another kid walked past my driveway as I was letting Takumi idle on high, and I see him run over to his dad, then back to me, giving me a little hand signal to rev it. How could I not?<br /><br />

<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>

</p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a silly little thing that popped into my head today. I would like to write about the small things that give me far more enjoyment than they should. Similarly, the act of writing about it would give me a badly needed positivity push. The other thoughts I would put words to were worse; this is preferable for everyone involved.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Touch</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/01/Touch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Touch" /><published>2025-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/01/Touch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/01/Touch.html"><![CDATA[<div>
    <p>
        <p class="bolded">Content warning: Abuse</p>
    </p>
    <p>
    I wish I were mute.<br /><br />
    There is no sequence of words that make sense. Something fundamental sits in between me and every other person, something that twists every sentence into something I don't fully understand.<br /> <br />
    You can fight it, of course. Play the words out a hundred times in your head, and watch them change slightly every time. Wait for the perfect moment to say it, only for it to never arrive. Get the thoughts out, and they never land. <br /><br />
    Or, you can sit in silence, and watch the dread grow with every passing minute. It all goes the same way. <br /><br />
    You can lie with words. Most combinations of them will work. Say anything to me, and I'd probably believe it. <br /><br />
    There's plenty of other ways to lie as well. I can't read your expression, or hear your tone. Do things in total opposition to each other, and watch me struggle to tell the difference. <br /><br />
    The only honest sense is touch. Grab me by the leg, throw me to the floor, show me what you think I'm worth. <br /><br />
    The only honest sense is touch. Pin me to the wall, I cannot avoid you now. <br /><br />
    The only honest sense is touch. Stick that knife in my face, see what I can do about it. <br /><br />
    The only honest sense is touch. Show me that you love me, I don't care how. <br /><br />
    I'm enamoured with the thought of a hand for every type of touch. It's not a new wonder, but fresh in the mind once again. There is unavoidable truth in it, painful or joyful as each one might be. <br /><br />
    Hit me, I hit you back. Hold me, I hold you back. Don't touch me, or do. We will finally be even, no matter what. <br /><br />
    I wish I were mute. My only greater wish is that you are, too.  <br /><br />
    </p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Content warning: Abuse I wish I were mute. There is no sequence of words that make sense. Something fundamental sits in between me and every other person, something that twists every sentence into something I don't fully understand. You can fight it, of course. Play the words out a hundred times in your head, and watch them change slightly every time. Wait for the perfect moment to say it, only for it to never arrive. Get the thoughts out, and they never land. Or, you can sit in silence, and watch the dread grow with every passing minute. It all goes the same way. You can lie with words. Most combinations of them will work. Say anything to me, and I'd probably believe it. There's plenty of other ways to lie as well. I can't read your expression, or hear your tone. Do things in total opposition to each other, and watch me struggle to tell the difference. The only honest sense is touch. Grab me by the leg, throw me to the floor, show me what you think I'm worth. The only honest sense is touch. Pin me to the wall, I cannot avoid you now. The only honest sense is touch. Stick that knife in my face, see what I can do about it. The only honest sense is touch. Show me that you love me, I don't care how. I'm enamoured with the thought of a hand for every type of touch. It's not a new wonder, but fresh in the mind once again. There is unavoidable truth in it, painful or joyful as each one might be. Hit me, I hit you back. Hold me, I hold you back. Don't touch me, or do. We will finally be even, no matter what. I wish I were mute. My only greater wish is that you are, too.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What I’m Reading, Volume 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/27/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I’m Reading, Volume 2" /><published>2025-05-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-05-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/27/What-I&apos;m-Reading-Vol-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/27/What-I&apos;m-Reading-Vol-2.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
    This is a little bit close to <a href="https://sandyspalace.ie/2025/05/11/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-1.html">Volume 1</a>, but it's been a shit few weeks and I'm getting worse by the day.
</p>

<p><h1>Serious Reads</h1></p>

<h2>The first prototype of the MingKwai Chinese typewriter has been rediscovered</h2>

Spread across three links below, this is the story of the MingKwai, a revolutionary typewriter that was radically ahead of its time.<br /><br />

<a href="https://news.stanford.edu/stories/2025/05/mingkwai-chinese-typewriter-prototype-stanford-libraries">Here is the article talking about how the first ever prototype model has just been found:</a>

<blockquote>Lin invented a machine that altered the very act of mechanical inscription by transforming inscription into a process of searching,” Mullaney said. “The MingKwai Chinese typewriter combined ‘search’ and ‘writing’ for arguably the first time in history.</blockquote><br />

Next up, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WVPFU3TK9fU">a video of the prototype itself.</a><br /><br />

Third, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yNoWMaOyWHY">an in-depth video explaining how it functions.</a>The machine translation of this video is pretty solid, but even just the video has some useful animations to explain how the typewriter's search mechanics work.<br />

<h2><a href="https://medium.com/@brentcsutoras/the-em-dash-dilemma-how-a-punctuation-mark-became-ais-stubborn-signature-684fbcc9f559">The Em Dash Dilemma: How a Punctuation Mark Became AI’s Stubborn Signature</a></h2>

<blockquote>And now? Humans are ditching em dashes, not because they don’t like them, but because they’re terrified their writing will look fake. One commenter on Hacker News even called it out directly, saying ‘the em dash is now a GPT-ism and is not advisable unless you want people to think your writing is the output of a LLM.</blockquote><br />

Not 100% accurate on the finer details of how LLMs are constructed, but ultimately the ripple effect is real.<br />

<h2><a href="https://oxfordamerican.org/oa-now/the-alabama-landline-that-keeps-ringing">The Alabama Landline That Keeps Ringing</a></h2>

<blockquote>About 13 million people in the US and 2.6 billion people globally don’t use the internet, whether for reasons of availability, desire, cost, or religion. Some may have it but don’t feel confident using it. To their callers, who dial from all over the world, these students are the internet. And lucky for callers, these students are remarkably non-judgmental when it comes to the questions they’re asked.</blockquote>

<p><h1>Light Reads</h1></p>

<h2><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FV36QPB0pew">A bizarre Evangelion Horse Racing advertisement from the 1990s</a></h2>
Neon Genesis Evangelion if it made far more sense.

<h2><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c1ldnedvde9o">Case quacked: Flying duck caught by Swiss speed camera is repeat offender</a></h2>
Partially here for the funny title, and mostly because it's just funny.<br /><br />

And finally, because it makes me laugh every single time I think about it. Every time you wonder if you're just pretending, that you're not enough, that you don't deserve success, just remember: the Ferrari Formula 1 team continues to pay its radio engineers 6-digit figures.<br /><br />

<video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
<source src="/assets/videos/blog/leclerc.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
</video>
<br /><br />
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a little bit close to Volume 1, but it's been a shit few weeks and I'm getting worse by the day.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Heaven Will be Mine</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/Heaven-Will-Be-Mine.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Heaven Will be Mine" /><published>2025-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/Heaven-Will-Be-Mine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/26/Heaven-Will-Be-Mine.html"><![CDATA[<p class="bolded">I'm of the opinion that a properly good piece of media, at least one that doesn't rely on "twists", cannot be spoiled in a meaningful way. If you disagree, avoid this post until after you read HWBM. Which you will.</p>
<p><br /></p>

<div>
<blockquote>We love these places anyway. They're becoming more and more like home. All we need are more of us.<br /><br />And they come, descending in waves, trying to take us back. We beat them back every time, and sometimes one or two look around, and decide "I'd rather stay here." And then there's more of us.<br /><br />Sometimes they succeed, and take one of us back home. That's just as fine with us. We should go where we wish, live as we wish, and if our sisters get taken home, they bring a small part of us back to the Earth. That can't go unchanged.</blockquote><br />

My brain has been fundamentally rewired again. It happens on select occasions, when the right piece of media hits me at the right time, and I engage with it in the right mindset.<br /><br />

Heaven Will Be Mine is short and sweet. A full playthough is roughly five hours. Within that time, it packs a narrative of the trans struggle for identity and recognition, the search for meaning in a perpetually hostile world, the never-ending quest of humans' self-discovery and exploration, and of course cool mechs beating each other up.<br /><br />

Gameplay is delivered in the typical visual novel format, with choices along the way deciding your ultimate faction alignment, and what girls you get to make out with. <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1579698535">Here's how to do that by the way.</a><br /><br />

You play across three main characters, each fulfilling various archetypes and personalities. Broadly, I enjoyed all three characters, but felt there was scope to expand and elaborate on their thoughts and feelings. Like the over-arching story itself, much is left up to the reader to decide.<br /><br />

Luna-Terra, the ace pilot, is the most "tired" of the three. Fighting through struggles without the self-respect to meaningfully change anything.<br /><br />

Pluto, a human that's gone beyond humanity. Absurdly powerful in her new form, but rejects the image of overwhelming strength that others assume of her.<br /><br />

And Saturn; unconventional, unpredictable, aggressively flirty. L33t h4xor extraordinaire.<br /><br />

I resonate strongly with Luna-Terra, and am looking respectfully at Saturn. Make of that what you will.<br /><br />

<blockquote> Through gravity, humans are ruled by each other. Anti-matter, anti-gravity, anti-culture; all exists as a resistive force to this gravity. The refusal of humanity to accept these parts of itself cause its own undoing. When we let our children develop in the lightness of space, they chose their bodies, genders, souls, hearts of their own volition. They became human in the ways they wished to become human.</blockquote><br />

The fight against Gravity is relentless. The pull of the Earth is not just measured in F = G(m1m2)/R2. It's measured in the mass of human history, the difficulty in breaking free of "normal", and the violence that follows resistance.<br /><br />

This was one of the most interesting metaphors in the game. In the context of gravity, one could choose stand on the surface of planet Earth, and cease resistance. Alternatively you could orbit the planet, still caught in its field, but with some measure of distance. To truly break free of it, how far would you need to go?<br /><br />

Creation of one's own gravity field, or connecting to a totally different one, can be seen as the liberation that these characters crave. I won't say more here, but the game does broach this in interesting ways.<br /><br />

<blockquote> In time, the shape conforms to the human inside. This in part confirms the specific theory: the human part isn't the ear, but the hole in the lobes for your earrings, lipstick is real, lips are not, and we see humanity defined in its gravitational output.</blockquote><br />

Ship-selves are another crucial aspect to this. They cannot survive on the surface of planet Earth. They are with form, but contort to replicate the user over time. Luna-Terra's is untouchable, Saturn's is bold and brave, Pluto's is warm and all-encompassing.<br /><br />

It is through Ship-selves that the pilots can fight against gravity, fight against each other, fight against the world. They are constructed in such an intricate way that they cannot kill another. There is a joy in it that cannot be found or replicated anywhere else, lonely as it may be.

<blockquote>No one should die in space. No one should die, period. No one has to die, because Ship-Self combat is shimmering missiles of light, cosmic explosions, electricity that sears through the soul. Blade sciences impossible for a human to produce! Dances of combat without end!<br />A fight against ideas with toys. Humans would never show that sort of compassion to each other.</blockquote>

The true capabilities of the Ship-selves are very ambiguous, more created as a tool of interpretation, as opposed to acting as the centrepiece of the VN.<br />

<p><blockquote>&gt;I worry about what we would be like if that hadn't happened. For me or for you. [...] Would it have taken us even longer? I already feel like I became a person too old. Would we spend our lives without ever-<br /><br />&gt;We'd have found another way. Somehow. In Earth or space, no one is ever born whole. We got there eventually, didn't we?<br /><br />&gt;Ha, I think so too. So I would like to believe that no matter what, we could live and be happy?<br />&gt;Even in mortal bodies, on our boring, awful home.<br />&gt;I mean, they can't undo what we have done.<br />&gt;When they take us back, they will have to make us a part of them.</blockquote></p>

There is pain and reassurance in seeing these thoughts said out loud. Just living can often be sufficient - both as an individual and in the cultures that we create.<br /><br />

You can interpret a relentless sadness from any of the situations put forward in HWBM. To live free of Earth's gravity means losing and sacrificing aspects of us, not because they are necessarily incompatible with us, but because the rest of humanity refuses to allow it to exist.<br /><br />

Yet there is joy in fighting for ourselves and each other, and this persists beyond the endless struggle.<br /><br />

---<br /><br />

Heaven Will Be Mine: <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/836450/Heaven_Will_Be_Mine/">Steam</a> | <a href="https://pillowfight.itch.io/heaven-will-be-mine">Itch</a>

<div>
</div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm of the opinion that a properly good piece of media, at least one that doesn't rely on "twists", cannot be spoiled in a meaningful way. If you disagree, avoid this post until after you read HWBM. Which you will.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chili</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/25/Chili.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chili" /><published>2025-05-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-05-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/25/Chili</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/25/Chili.html"><![CDATA[<div>
    <p>
        Today would have been my cat Chili's second birthday.
    </p>
    <p>
        She was found by a then-partner of mine, miles out of the city, barely able to walk. Her mother was nearby, but seemingly wasn't able to help her.
    </p>
    <p>
        <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/chili-1.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
        <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">First pic ever taken of Chili</figcaption>
        </figure>
    </p>
    <p>
        She had multiple infections, most predominantly in the eyes. It took weeks of treatment before she was able to see properly, and I suspect they never fully healed.
    </p>
    <p>
        She was a wild cat since birth, and acted like it. She was troublesome but clingy at the same time. Litter training her was the most difficult of any cat, as it was tough to dissuade her from going whenever she needed.
    </p>
    <p>
        Interestingly, the vet who performed her surgeries described her as "borderline intersex". During development, the positioning of body parts suggested it was anticipating male organs, but she got female ones instead. The vet described this using very helpful diagrams.
    </p>
    <p>
        Once she cleared the first few weeks, I introduced her to Sandy, my other idiot, who was roughly 1 year old at the time. They bonded faster than any other cats I've seen.
    </p>
    <p>
        <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/chili-2.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
        <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">They would do this wihout any intervention needed, every single day</figcaption>
        </figure>
    </p>
    <p>
        Having two cats was a huge motivator for me to get a more stable roof over my head. The thought of letting down them was more worrying than the thought of disappointing myself.
    </p>
    <p>
        With the typical delays in buying and moving house, Chili was a year old by the time we finally moved. Outside of visits to the family home, she never had any real opportunity of exploring the outdoors in a safe way.
    </p>
    <p>
        <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/chili-3.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
        <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">The only living things to enjoy this couch</figcaption>
        </figure>
    </p>
    <p>
        One of my fondest memories of her is the day of moving - October 30th 2023. The two cats didn't know what to make of everything. The house smelled something bizarre, and they were totally unused to any new environment that wasn't friendly to them. Yet they ran their Sniffy Inspection Squad through every single room to keep me safe :3
    </p>
    <p>
        Currently testing these video players in a live environment, don't mind me :&gt;
    </p>
    <p>
        <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
        <source src="/assets/videos/blog/chili-1.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
        <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
            <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Sniffy Inspection Squad, in your neighbourhood</figcaption>
        </figure>
        </video>
        
    <p>
        The house move was super difficult for many reasons. I was sleeping on a mattress on the floor, that I shifted between the two liveable rooms in the house, whenever I needed to work on the other. Chili would join me every night for the first few weeks.
    </p>
    <p>
        She also took time out to look after Sandy, who wasn't finding the move very enjoyable. On the first night, Sandy saw the miserable-looking mattress that I was hopping on top of, realised he wasn't going back to the flat, and did the closest thing to crying I've ever seen a cat do. Chili was on the case. 
    </p>

    <p>
        <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
        <source src="/assets/videos/blog/chili-2.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
        <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
        <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">:3</figcaption>
        </figure>
        </video>
    <p>
        She loved the outdoors, and took to the area like a natural. The back garden is removed from the local roads, and the area cats have no need to put themselves in danger unless they feel like it. Chili didn't wander much, but she loved the big pine tree my neighbour has.
    </p>
    <p>
        <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/chili-4.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
        <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">They never did forgive me for cutting down the overgrown garden.</figcaption>
        </figure>
    </p>
    <p>
        Chili thoroughly enjoyed her new lifestyle for the next 6 months. It was the ideal setup, two cats that looked after each other, barely fought, and gave each other space when needed.
    </p>
    <p>
        Chili didn't return home one random night. I set up the usual for her: both dry and wet food indoors and outdoors, fresh water bowls, and put some used clothes in the garden to mark her home.
    </p>
    <p>
        She returned the following day, but something was off about her. Despite no visible injuries, she seemed unnerved, shook, or maybe just super curious about something I didn't understand. She ate food happily, but after that was bursting to leave again. She suddenly had no interest in the safe indoors, and only had eyes for whatever was on her mind outside.
    </p>
    <p>
        <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/chili-5.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
        <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">The last photo of Chili</figcaption>
        </figure>
    </p>
    <p>
        I kept her inside for three days, but it fixed nothing. Every time I even glanced at a window or door, she was there by my feet.
    </p>
    <p>
        Eventually she did slip between my feet and escape. She was never a catchable cat, but I decided to trust her anyways. Whatever had caught her attention, I hoped that she'd take care of it and come back. Of course, she didn't.
    </p>
    <p>
        We never did find her. I still hope to this day that she popped into someone else's home, preferred the couch, and decided to stay. No other explanation makes sense or gives hope.
    </p>
    <p>
        So, happy birthday Chili. Your cat yoghurt is waiting for you in the fridge, same as last year.
    </p>
</p></p></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today would have been my cat Chili's second birthday. She was found by a then-partner of mine, miles out of the city, barely able to walk. Her mother was nearby, but seemingly wasn't able to help her. First pic ever taken of Chili She had multiple infections, most predominantly in the eyes. It took weeks of treatment before she was able to see properly, and I suspect they never fully healed. She was a wild cat since birth, and acted like it. She was troublesome but clingy at the same time. Litter training her was the most difficult of any cat, as it was tough to dissuade her from going whenever she needed. Interestingly, the vet who performed her surgeries described her as "borderline intersex". During development, the positioning of body parts suggested it was anticipating male organs, but she got female ones instead. The vet described this using very helpful diagrams. Once she cleared the first few weeks, I introduced her to Sandy, my other idiot, who was roughly 1 year old at the time. They bonded faster than any other cats I've seen. They would do this wihout any intervention needed, every single day Having two cats was a huge motivator for me to get a more stable roof over my head. The thought of letting down them was more worrying than the thought of disappointing myself. With the typical delays in buying and moving house, Chili was a year old by the time we finally moved. Outside of visits to the family home, she never had any real opportunity of exploring the outdoors in a safe way. The only living things to enjoy this couch One of my fondest memories of her is the day of moving - October 30th 2023. The two cats didn't know what to make of everything. The house smelled something bizarre, and they were totally unused to any new environment that wasn't friendly to them. Yet they ran their Sniffy Inspection Squad through every single room to keep me safe :3 Currently testing these video players in a live environment, don't mind me :&gt; Sniffy Inspection Squad, in your neighbourhood The house move was super difficult for many reasons. I was sleeping on a mattress on the floor, that I shifted between the two liveable rooms in the house, whenever I needed to work on the other. Chili would join me every night for the first few weeks. She also took time out to look after Sandy, who wasn't finding the move very enjoyable. On the first night, Sandy saw the miserable-looking mattress that I was hopping on top of, realised he wasn't going back to the flat, and did the closest thing to crying I've ever seen a cat do. Chili was on the case.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What I’m Reading, Volume 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/11/What-I'm-Reading-Vol-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I’m Reading, Volume 1" /><published>2025-05-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-05-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/11/What-I&apos;m-Reading-Vol-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/11/What-I&apos;m-Reading-Vol-1.html"><![CDATA[<div>
    <p>
        <p class="bolded">Content warning: Both the article author and I mention abuse and violence in Article 2: The Violence of Chaos.</p>
    </p>
    <p>
        Not a particularly original idea, but it'd be good to put proper thoughts to good things I read.
    </p>
    <p>
        Layout and style of this is mostly mirroring <a href="https://oakreef.ie">Oakreef</a>, but I had this general layout planned beforehand I swear
    </p>

    <p><h1>Serious Reads</h1></p>
    <p>
    <h2><a href="https://oakreef.ie/bog/irish-health-service">My Experiences With The Irish Health Service</a></h2>
    </p>
    <p>
        <blockquote>But when it comes to disability, how well one performs academically or economically is often seen as the primary metric. Getting a person to produce the desired outputs of those systems is the goal, and if someone does, then they may not be seen as needing assistance, no matter how much they are being ground down as an ill-fitting cog in the machine.</blockquote>
    </p>
    <p>
        A thorougly sobering read, that should be ground into the mind of every policy-maker and power-holder in every country.
    </p>
    <p>
        In an ideal world, people like us would never have needed to write articles like this. In the HSE's ideal world, we would not exist.
    </p>

    <p>
    <h2><a href="https://illuminesce.net/blog/posts/2025-04-06-The-Violence-of-Chaos/">The Violence of Chaos</a></h2>
    </p>
    <p>
        <blockquote>And I am reminded of this every day when I open the news. It is a hidden abuse that was done to me — and to all of us — that it is normal to live in this way. That to live in a country with liberty, we must give up our liberty to feel safe and supported. And we have been living in fear, I believe, for a long time. To my friends still living in the U.S. and who are afraid - consider this your validation. It is not normal for you to live like this. It was never normal to live like this.</blockquote>
    </p>
    <p>
        Some strong thoughts on abuse and violence here. It hits too close to home, even when I live 6,000km from the US.
    </p>
    <p>
        The entity wielding the weapon in your face often isn't even thinking about you at all.
    </p>

    <p>
    <h2><a href="https://time.com/6337835/ai-mediocrity-essay/">AI and the Rise of Mediocrity</a></h2>
    </p>
    <p>
        <blockquote>Can we recognize the loss of creativity caused by AI as it’s happening? Do we know there is less that is truly new in the world, and fewer avenues for personal expression? Many of us may not. Absence of choice is hard to sense, and mechanization’s real innovation is in creating a complacent buyer with reduced expectations. Once you’ve done that, you can sell them whatever you want. What is being mechanized by AI is our tastes—our ability to discern quality (or originality) at all.</blockquote>
    </p>

    <p><h1>Light Reads</h1></p>

    <p>
    <h2><a href="https://715-999-7483.com/">715-999-7483</a></h2>
    </p>
    <p>
        Described as a "phone-powered multiplayer website builder". Call +1 (715) 999-7483, and you'll be prompted to describe the changes you'd like to make to the website, with a 30-second time limit.
        
        I'm playing the long game here, waiting for eager followers of the Tom Scott newsletter to get bored of this service, before I hijack it with pics of Sandy and Muffin :3
    </p>

    <p>
    <h2><a href="https://blog.cat-girl.gay/magic-wand-3/">A Hackable, Custom, Magic Wand (Plus) Board</a></h2>
    </p>
    <p>
        :&gt;
    </p>

    <p>
    <h2><a href="https://pubs.aip.org/aip/pof/article/37/4/044122/3345324/Phase-behavior-of-Cacio-e-Pepe-sauce">Phase Behaviour of Cacio e Pepe sauce</a></h2>
    </p>
    <p>
    <blockquote>We identify starch concentration as the key factor influencing sauce stability, with direct implications for practical cooking. Specifically, we delineate a regime where starch concentrations below 1% (relative to cheese mass) lead to the formation of system-wide clumps, a condition determining what we term the “Mozzarella Phase” and corresponding to an unpleasant and separated sauce. Additionally, we examine the impact of cheese concentration relative to water at a fixed starch level, observing a lower critical solution temperature that we theoretically rationalized by means of a minimal effective free-energy model.</blockquote>
    </p>
    <p>
        Italy was conceived for this scientific wonder of a paper.
    </p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Content warning: Both the article author and I mention abuse and violence in Article 2: The Violence of Chaos. Not a particularly original idea, but it'd be good to put proper thoughts to good things I read. Layout and style of this is mostly mirroring Oakreef, but I had this general layout planned beforehand I swear]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Caoimhefication Instrumentality Project</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/10/Caoimhefication-Instrumentality-Project.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Caoimhefication Instrumentality Project" /><published>2025-05-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-05-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/10/Caoimhefication-Instrumentality-Project</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/10/Caoimhefication-Instrumentality-Project.html"><![CDATA[<div>
    <p>
        Changing your name once is so out - changing it three times is so in.
    </p>
    <p>
        Once because I searched for a name that both guys and girls use, something that would let me hide behind a veneer of ambiguity. As suspected, it became stale and meaningless.
    </p>
    <p>
        Then once because I realised my love for cute things, and wanted a cute name to go with it. The comfort with it never grew beyond the honeymoon phase, and I did feel lacking for not picking something Irish.
    </p>
    <p>
        And once again after I changed my name as a joke on a Discord server, got unsuspectingly called by that name the following day, and something clicked in my brain. Nothing major, simply a "that felt nice". Something I was lacking up until then.
    </p>
    <p>
        Being queer leaves one more open to this kind of this thought process than most, I feel. Already being so distanced from the rest of society, what's another identity shift? What do I have to lose?
    </p>
    <p>
        I know and love myself more than I ever did before. This has only been strengthened by this kind of self-searching that may never conclude. Far from a weakness that people trapped by normality and fear would have you or I think.
    </p>
    <p>
        Frankly my main concern wasn't other people's perception. It was moreso the dread of what I'd already semi-completed before: The arduous process of changing hundreds of usernames and email logins. A password manager was absolutely mandatory, and frankly it's reinforced my horror of people who don't use one. Use Bitwarden today &#128591;
    </p>
    <p>
        <i>Full disclaimer - I am moderately influenced by the fact that two of my most favourite people around are already named Caoimhe. Hi btw &#x1F496;</i>
    </p>
    <p>
        After only a short amount of time, it's been already worth it. There's a deep joy in hearing it said out loud. A statement of trust and love shown by those I've opened myself up to. All else is secondary. 
    </p>
    <p>
        The legal name change is further down the road, but the hard work has already been done. I've fought state departments, civil servants, and bureaucrats long enough to know that I'll feel no validation from their acknowledgement of my existence. If I were being more cynical, I'd say I was looking down the road of future hate, steeling myself for when the vague tolerance of me is stripped away. We will live far beyond that.
    </p>
    <p>
        The pivotal moment here came much earlier in this process. A friend shuffled next to me in the pub, asking simply "Hey Caoimhe how's it going?" I spent a while stumbling to answer (normal), not immediately noticing the glint that was forming in her eye. "I just wanted to see your reaction when I called you that".
    </p>
    <p>
        I intend to think fondly about this for many years.
    </p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Changing your name once is so out - changing it three times is so in. Once because I searched for a name that both guys and girls use, something that would let me hide behind a veneer of ambiguity. As suspected, it became stale and meaningless. Then once because I realised my love for cute things, and wanted a cute name to go with it. The comfort with it never grew beyond the honeymoon phase, and I did feel lacking for not picking something Irish. And once again after I changed my name as a joke on a Discord server, got unsuspectingly called by that name the following day, and something clicked in my brain. Nothing major, simply a "that felt nice". Something I was lacking up until then. Being queer leaves one more open to this kind of this thought process than most, I feel. Already being so distanced from the rest of society, what's another identity shift? What do I have to lose? I know and love myself more than I ever did before. This has only been strengthened by this kind of self-searching that may never conclude. Far from a weakness that people trapped by normality and fear would have you or I think. Frankly my main concern wasn't other people's perception. It was moreso the dread of what I'd already semi-completed before: The arduous process of changing hundreds of usernames and email logins. A password manager was absolutely mandatory, and frankly it's reinforced my horror of people who don't use one. Use Bitwarden today &#128591; Full disclaimer - I am moderately influenced by the fact that two of my most favourite people around are already named Caoimhe. Hi btw &#x1F496; After only a short amount of time, it's been already worth it. There's a deep joy in hearing it said out loud. A statement of trust and love shown by those I've opened myself up to. All else is secondary. The legal name change is further down the road, but the hard work has already been done. I've fought state departments, civil servants, and bureaucrats long enough to know that I'll feel no validation from their acknowledgement of my existence. If I were being more cynical, I'd say I was looking down the road of future hate, steeling myself for when the vague tolerance of me is stripped away. We will live far beyond that. The pivotal moment here came much earlier in this process. A friend shuffled next to me in the pub, asking simply "Hey Caoimhe how's it going?" I spent a while stumbling to answer (normal), not immediately noticing the glint that was forming in her eye. "I just wanted to see your reaction when I called you that". I intend to think fondly about this for many years.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Say Hi To Takumi, The Toyota GT86</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/09/Say-Hi-To-Takumi-The-Toyota-GT86.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Say Hi To Takumi, The Toyota GT86" /><published>2025-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/03/09/Say-Hi-To-Takumi-The-Toyota-GT86</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/09/Say-Hi-To-Takumi-The-Toyota-GT86.html"><![CDATA[<div>
    <p>
        Hello did you know I have incredible taste and terrible spending habits :3
    </p>

    <p>
        <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/takumi1.jpg" alt="Description of the image" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
        <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Excuse the editing, it's not my day job.</figcaption>
        </figure>
    </p>
    
    <p>
        This is my new love, a Toyota GT86 imported from Britain. First-gen ZN6 model, with a decent modding and maintenance scene supporting it. It seems to have aged really well as a platform, with only the valve spring recall being a particularly notable problem.
    </p>

    <p>
        It's a classic old school 2+2, sacrificing raw power for reduced weight, low centre of gravity, and a setup that's incredibly driver-focused. I still haven't had a proper test of it on winding    country roads, but it's been super fun every chance I get to bring it around.
    </p>

    <p>
        I would dearly like to meet the previous owner. She's put on some rather interesting boy racer mods, but after almost 100,000 miles, there's barely a scratch on it, or heavy wear on the mechanicals. The front aero splitter, carbon side skirts, ducktail spoiler, and Invidia exhaust are all great looks and really elevate the machine.
    </p>

    <p>
        <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/takumi2.jpg" alt="Description of the image" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
        <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Very useful for supermarket car parks yknow</figcaption>
        </figure>
    </p>

    <p>
        Performance-wise, there's a small improvement from the Invidia exhaust, but otherwise no power modifications. I'm curious to push the platform, but don't think I'll make any excessive changes. 220 HP (160KW) is honestly fine for Irish roads, as we don't have the wonderful country roads of America or Britain, or any continental European country for that matter. Too many fucking bumps. 
    </p>

    <p>
        Plus... it already has 100k miles on it. Pushing it beyond 300 HP is questionable at its current age.
    </p>

    <p>
        It's great to drive, which is the entire point of the car so that shouldn't come as a huge surprise. The steering is incredibly direct, and wonderfully hooked up at all speeds. Suspension is borderline too stiff for daily driving, particularly on the rear, but has great responsiveness.
    </p>

    <p>
        The Invidia exhaust adds a huge amount of depth to the noise, but honestly I love the whines from the engine, and wish I could hear them more. If it wasn't an economically terrible idea, a supercharger would be a fantastic addition if only for the audible aesthetics.
    </p>

    <p>
        <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
        <img src="/assets/images/blog/takumi3.jpg" alt="Description of the image" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
        <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Mm yes very wise</figcaption>
        </figure>
    </p>

    <p>
        From a practical perspective, there's a bit too much drone when off-throttle. It's currently my biggest gripe, but not worthy yet of modifying the exhaust.
    </p>

    <p>
        I adore the reactions received. Kids will ask to hear some revs, and I love dishing it out. Only tonight a guy pulled up next to me, beaming and glowing with enthusiasm. I gave him a standing start procedure as thanks :D
    </p>

    <p>
        I'm planning its first track day, but might get adjustable coilover springs first. It would be super fun on track, and might also improve the bumpiness on the drive home afterwards.
    </p>

    <p>
        Finally the one big sting... I paid as much in import costs as much as I paid for the car itself. The uprising against the Irish state has therefore been brought forward several weeks. 
    </p>

</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello did you know I have incredible taste and terrible spending habits :3]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hetzner vs Leaseweb vs OVH - Server Consolidation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/26/Hetzner-vs-Leaseweb-vs-OVH-Server-Consolidation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hetzner vs Leaseweb vs OVH - Server Consolidation" /><published>2025-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/02/26/Hetzner-vs-Leaseweb-vs-OVH-Server-Consolidation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/26/Hetzner-vs-Leaseweb-vs-OVH-Server-Consolidation.html"><![CDATA[<style>
  table {
    width: 100%;
    border-collapse: collapse;
    table-layout: fixed; /* Important! */
  }

  th, td {
    border: 1px solid #ddd;
    padding: 8px;
    text-align: left;
    overflow: hidden; /* Prevent content overflow */
    white-space: nowrap; /* Prevent text wrapping */
    text-overflow: ellipsis; /* Add ellipsis for clipped text */
  }

  th:nth-child(1), td:nth-child(1) { width: 150px; } /* Column 1 */
  th:nth-child(2), td:nth-child(2) { width: 100px; } /* Column 2 */
  th:nth-child(3), td:nth-child(3) { width: 100px; } /* Column 3 */
  th:nth-child(4), td:nth-child(4) { width: 100px; } /* Column 4 */
</style>

<div>
    <p>
        Good news! I have acknowledged my hubris out loud, and am consolidating down to one server that's actually affordable and can handle all the current needs, plus keeping space for future requirements. 
    </p>
    <p>
        Took a while to get here mind you.
    </p>
    <p>
        I did have an interesting opportunity though. With three servers live at the same time, I tried to run some real-life benchmarks to see what was actually performing as expected.
    </p>
    <p>
        My first test was sending files directly from server to server using the scp command. I chose a single 1GB file, to reduce latency for different system handling of block allocation. The quality of the line connection is most important to me, I'm not bothered about CPU/RAM/HDD efficiency.
    </p>
    <p>
        The file was an episode of Serial Experiments Lain, because I figured this is basically enrichment for Lain :3
    </p>
    <p>
        <table>
        <thead>
            <tr>
            <th></th>
            <th>Time to Complete</th>
            <th>Average Speed (MBps)</th>
            </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
            <tr>
            <td>Hetzner → Leaseweb</td>
            <td>00:10</td>
            <td>91.3</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
            <td>Hetzner → OVH</td>
            <td>00:46</td>
            <td>21.0</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
            <td>Leaseweb → Hetzner</td>
            <td>00:10</td>
            <td>93.8</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
            <td>Leaseweb → OVH</td>
            <td>00:43</td>
            <td>22.5</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
            <td>OVH → Hetzner</td>
            <td>00:56</td>
            <td>17.4</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
            <td>OVH → Leaseweb</td>
            <td>01:00</td>
            <td>16.2</td>
            </tr>
        </tbody>
        </table>
    </p>
    <p>
        Absolutely dire performance from OVH on both download and upload performance. The fact that these speeds are replicated in both directions, while pointing at different servers, who each performed well in separate tests, is incredibly damning. Leaseweb and Hetzner are pretty comparable and as advertised.
    </p>
    <p>
        Second experiment was just a network data sample of an average day's activity. I used vnstat to pull the daily upload total (in TB) for each server:
    </p>
    <p>

        <table>
        <thead>
            <tr>
            <th></th>
            <th>Hetzner</th>
            <th>Leaseweb</th>
            <th>OVH</th>
            </tr>
        </thead>
            <tbody>
            <tr>
            <td>2025-02-23</td>
            <td>3.18</td>
            <td>2.51</td>
            <td>0.99</td>
            </tr>
        </tbody>
        </table>
    </p>
    <p>
        OVH is completely unsuitable for my needs, has speeds nowhere near advertised levels, and I've cancelled the service almost as soon as I ordered it.
    </p>
    <p>
        For choosing between Hetzner and Leaseweb, I still have concerns over the former's monitoring of torrents, given that the torrents it flagged on my IP address had seemingly nothing to do with my activity. However the peering is excellent, and there's a significant benefit in peer-to-peer file transfer rates. Server-to-server transfer rates are pretty much exactly the same as Leaseweb.
    </p>
    <p>
        Hetzner is therefore being prepped as the single server going forward, and Leaseweb will be used as a primary backup until its next renewal date. My home PC will be the future primary backup, which does suffer poor upload speed, but otherwise is safe and secure... and cheaper.
    </p>
    <p>
        Coincidentially, I had to wipe and restart Hetzner this week due to a setup error in the RAID 10 configuration, and was wasting 4TB of usable space in the root partition. This also gave me the opportunity to clean my my media library, assign a domain name to the media server (which subsequently makes transitioning to Jellyfin easier), fix some stupid nginx issues, and have the server running at peak efficiency. I'm extremely smug that, on maximum server utilisation, we only need 1.2GB RAM. Eat shit, Chrome. 
    </p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>