<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-08-08T00:43:23+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/atom.xml</id><title type="html">Sandy’s Palace</title><subtitle>Rosa&apos;s gay little website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">K_____</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/07/K_____.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="K_____" /><published>2025-08-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/07/K_____</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/07/K_____.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
I am a huge fan of characters that don't speak very much or at all. This may not come as a huge surprise.<br /><br />

Even better when they can hold their own, without any compromises to their character or what they're trying to achieve. There is motivation here for me that outstrips pretty much anything else a piece of media could say.<br /><br />

Kimiko from the TV show The Boys has been a treat to watch. There is clear reason in her silence, which adds to her character rather than detracts or constrains it. Also she's cute when she rips people's heads off :3 <br /><br />

Moving to, as my friend has ungenerously put it before, a show for babies: Miraculous Ladybug has Kagami whom I attune with a very normal amount. She does talk, but only when necessary and saying only what's needed. Plenty of examples of this in media, I just stumbled upon this one and quite enjoy it.<br /><br />

This is where the trend ends for fictional characters whose names begin with K and are 6 characters long. I am very interested in continuing this mind you.<br /><br />

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/kimiko-1.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">:33333333</figcaption>
</figure>

Something about Komi from Komi-san Can't Communicate didn't click with me. It felt permanently like an attempt to be adorable to the ogling reader, before any point it tried to deliver.<br /><br />

Shōko Nishimiya	from Koe no Katachi wrecked me when I first watched it almost a decade ago. It's been too long to remember the subtleties, but it hits too close to home for me to call it my favourite rendition of this thought. Good film though.<br /><br />

A search online for mute characters pulled up Shizune Hakamichi, who comes from a time where I was shitposting on corners of the internet that I would rather erase. So that one's a bit cursed still. Also her route was SHIT<br /><br />

Chell, Doomguy, and Gordon Freeman all fit the bill, but I don't feel it as much with video game protagonists. Maybe there's this expectation that they don't <i>have</i> to speak in that type of media. I can't immediately think of nonverbal NPCs, though this would likely appeal to me far more.<br /><br />

Most words I speak are weighed down with unease, and the sense that I'm always a step behind what I'm <i>supposed</i> to say feels inescapable. The more casual the talk, the worse it becomes. I don't understand how anyone can reach deep into their decades of knowledge, pull out the exact silly media fact or quip required, and belt it out all in a microsecond. By the time I've stewed over a sentence long enough to trust it, we're talking about anarchist communes or some shit.<br /><br />

The thought of dropping it all feels nice. Even with the knowledge that I'd lose that necessary connection to people that's (mostly) required to get closer to them.<br /><br />

It remains unrealistic. I'd have to drop too much from my life to be able to continue with stability. So I watch these fictional little characters and squee with glee and envy.
</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am a huge fan of characters that don't speak very much or at all. This may not come as a huge surprise.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tachanka</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/02/Tachanka.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tachanka" /><published>2025-08-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/08/02/Tachanka</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/08/02/Tachanka.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
In 2015 I spent €120 on a laptop with the physical properties of a battering ram. Tachanka has served me for 10 glorious years, and he has finally been allowed to rest after much faithful service.<br /><br />

Tachanka the Thinkpad T410 has no outrageous tech specs to speak of. i5-520M, 2GB RAM, 250GB HDD, TFT LCD screen. Where he becomes outstanding is the way it's all put together. Everything is socketed, not soldered, into place. Virtually every component is hot-swappable, and a surprising proportion of them can be done while the machine is still running. A full magnesium shell shrouds the heart, still indestructible despite my best efforts.<br /><br />

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/tachanka-1.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">You wish your laptop was also a landline phone so bad it makes you look stupid</figcaption>
</figure>

Almost everything got upgraded, bar the CPU. Several years and some lost screws later, Tachanka was rocking 8GB RAM, 1TB of SSD storage, doubled battery capacity, and a lightweight Linux distro that gave zero fucks about raw processing power.<br /><br />

His drawback - massive weight - was also his party piece, as you could drop him on a table with zero disregard for the subsequent earthquake. Glass tables were for weaklings anyway.<br /><br />

The foolish masses never understood. Tachanka was the equivalent of a Mercedes Grosser, delightfully overengineered. Unfortunately my D&amp;D group did not appreciate my ability to reload the spare SATA slot like an AK-47:<br /><br />

<p>
    <video controls="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block; margin: 0 auto;">
    <source src="/assets/videos/blog/tachanka-1.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
    <figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
    <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">This reload could have been done in 5 seconds if I wasn't frothing with rage</figcaption>
    </figure>
    </video>
<p>

I used him as a daily driver far beyond his usual shelf life, having been manufactured in 2010 and running happily until 2023. However the troubles eventually began to pile up.<br /><br />

The keyboard had to be removed every time you needed to access the front of the motherboard, and the clips had loosened and weakened the corners. The screen's ability to rotate 180 degrees had worn out the hinges. The ability to charge him became inconsistent, and it dropped power on rare occasions.<br /><br />

The charging issue became so troublesome, I had to perform a few operations. The first, a full disassembly, attempted to find any loose wires or other easy fixes. No such luck of course. The second operation was an attempt to replace some core cables, strip the machine to its bare insides (hot), and try jump-starting it under various conditions.<br /><br />

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/tachanka-2.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">About halfway through the operation</figcaption>
</figure>

When it became clear that no accessory was causing problems, I resorted to changing the charging port and some electrical sections. No luck. Either I'd missed something, or the issue was on a main board that was discontinued over a decade ago.<br /><br />

With Tachanka already in a million pieces, I made the brave decision to keep the core components and scrap the rest. No modern machine uses a magnesium shell anyways.<br /><br />

I have no idea what to do with a BGA1288-socketed CPU. But if I thought of something cool, it might keep Tachanka still kicking in a sense. I have a drawer full of CPUs, maybe some weird art piece could work.

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</p></p></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2015 I spent €120 on a laptop with the physical properties of a battering ram. Tachanka has served me for 10 glorious years, and he has finally been allowed to rest after much faithful service.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">McIntyre Monday</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/30/McIntyre-Monday.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="McIntyre Monday" /><published>2025-07-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-07-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/30/McIntyre-Monday</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/30/McIntyre-Monday.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
April 7th, 2024. Wrestlemania 40, the opening act of Night 2. A 6ft buff Scotsman struts down the catwalk to the ring, through a saber arch with bagpipes blasting. I turn to my friend and remark that this is the dumbest shit I've ever seen, with a big smile on my face.<br /><br />

His opponent, another 6ft buff lad, continues his tradition of dressing himself by running through his wife's curtains. They kind of dropped this gimmick in 2025, unfortunately. I miss Mardi Gras Seth Rollins.<br /><br />

They pretend to kick the shit out of each other for 10 minutes, mostly by actually throwing each other around in increasingly wacky scenarios, with the Scotsman taking a brief break to send a tweet mid-match. <a href="https://x.com/dmcintyrewwe/status/1777114915678937236">Not a joke</a>.<br /><br />

Scotsman wins, before becoming the definition of hubris by mocking another rival in the commentary box to the extent that he gets beaten up for shits and giggles, before the Money In The Bank holder (winner of a silly match that gives the holder an instant no-questions-asked world championship match on demand) sprints into the ring, performs the world's quickest ass-kicking, steals the title off him and leaves. This proceeds to set off the biggest feud of 2024, containing several months of the most idiot babygirl promos, and three banger matches. It's funnier the less I explain.<br /><br />

This, and many other idiotic storylines, has confirmed to me the theory that professional wrestling is advanced drag. The wrestlers are playing complete caricatures, love to show off skin, are supremely talented in ways that aren't immediately obvious, and have extremely tacky soundtracks following them around. Prove me wrong.<br /><br />

The more indie you go, the sillier it gets. Turn to AEW for blood matches, storylines that revolve around being bald, and the single greatest kayfabe actor of all time (MJF). Turn to the national indies (in my case, OTT) for shouting "you fat bastard" at a ripped British dude while a big schmeaty Irish lad is doing a striptease to rapturous applause. We love and support Big Damo around here. Also there's a lad who's main gimmick is vaping in the middle of matches.<br /><br />

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/joshi-1.png" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">Joshi wrestling is also delightfully stupid</figcaption>
</figure>

You can't force yourself to enjoy it, it's just utter nonsense that one day may or may not make sense. And it makes you look like a lunatic if you try to explain it. Hi btw &lt;3 <br /><br />

For almost a full year I carried the tradition of McIntyre Monday, a weekly celebration of why you the worshipper were so much better than everyone else. Drew was in the middle of his heel run and it just made sense. It made for strangely satisfying motivation. Also Drew (real name Andrew) is a real-life babygirl who goes to cat cafes and looks after all the women wrestlers when travelling and on nights out. Great dude to support.<br /><br />

The interest has dropped off a bit recently - WWE is having a poor run, and is politically rancid. AEW is picking itself up after a weak few months. OTT is only up in Dublin even if I'd like to go up maybe once a year. But it's still delightfully stupid and makes me laugh.<br /><br />

Happy McIntyre Monday bitches. No I don't care if it's Wednesday it's a state of mind you fool

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/drew-1.jpg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">I'm not explaining shit.</figcaption>
</figure>


</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[April 7th, 2024. Wrestlemania 40, the opening act of Night 2. A 6ft buff Scotsman struts down the catwalk to the ring, through a saber arch with bagpipes blasting. I turn to my friend and remark that this is the dumbest shit I've ever seen, with a big smile on my face.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">1086 Days</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/28/1086-Days.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="1086 Days" /><published>2025-07-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-07-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/28/1086-Days</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/28/1086-Days.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
I've been free for 1086 days. There's nothing particularly special about the round numbers, nor the annual anniversaries. It was simply nice to realise.<br /><br />

"Free" is relative. I was worse off for many of those early days. But overall it's been a lovely time period to reflect on.<br /><br />

Sandy has been in my life for 1038 days. He has been a wonderful little tether of motivation.<br /><br />

I've had a stable roof over my head for 656 days. Acutely conscious of how fortunately the cards played out on this one. Many of us weren't that lucky. But whatever hand I had to play in it, I'm happy with.<br /><br />

I've been on HRT for 652 days. By far the most influential act of my life, and also one of the best. Still in the early game with this one :3<br /><br />

591 days since my first piercing. I left the shop already giddy for the next one. 340 days since my most recent ones. The cuntiness is still a work in progress but I grow happier and happier with it.<br /><br />

488 days since my first laser appointment. Still stings a bit. Worth it.<br /><br />

477 days since I had my moment of realisation that professional wrestling was the biggest dumbest shit ever and I loved it. Just felt nice to put something silly on this list. There's a specific story I can tell another time.<br /><br />

224 days since an intense awakening of mine. This is a public site and I will say no more. Teehee.<br /><br />

117 days since I called a long-distance friend of mine for the first time. We yapped about fashion, surgeries, cuddles, and bread.<br /><br />

34 days of legally being Caoimhe.<br /><br />

I've been in a safer place for 1086 days. At the same time, more vulnerable, excited, timid, loving, fearful, enthusiastic, rattled, motivated. Everything is more intense now. There is too much to do, and too many people to cling onto for dear life. But this will always beat a black hole and a dead end.

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've been free for 1086 days. There's nothing particularly special about the round numbers, nor the annual anniversaries. It was simply nice to realise.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Analogue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/21/Analogue.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Analogue" /><published>2025-07-21T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-07-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/21/Analogue</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/21/Analogue.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
I swear I was ahead of the curve on this one. But modern technology has run out of usefulness to me.<br /><br />

It was obvious enough with the kind of blog I run. Sandy's Palace is HTML and CSS only (apart from 2 lines but don't worry about it), a haphazardly-run shambling mass of a thing. I adore it because it's mine, and I made it mine.<br /><br />

Virtually no aspect of modern tech allows this any more. Smartphones are walled gardens, hemming you in with the power of convenience, sleekness, and obfuscation. If you're on Android, you can fight back, but you need to Know in order to even begin. If you're on iPhone, forget it.<br /><br />

Every item that can be enshittified is in the process of being turned into an appliance. Something designed to break whenever it feels like, totally unrepairable, leaving you powerless to take ownership and control.<br /><br /> 

Modern cars disgust me. I don't consider them appealing at any price bracket. Frankly the more high-end you go, the worse it gets. <a href="https://arstechnica.com/cars/2025/07/everything-we-learned-from-a-week-with-apple-carplay-ultra/">Apple CarPlay takes greater priority on a new Aston Martin than anything else it determines on the fly.</a> A surprising aspect of conspicuous consumption to me was that people will happily pay for an appliance that is shit at what it does, as it displays the user's affluence even more effectively, not even needing their pricey toy to work. Also see: Cybertruck.<br /><br />

I made the leap to digital banks and briefly enjoyed it. Then they added a tab for investments. Then for crypto. Then popups for savings goals, trending tickers, brand discounts, analytics, RevPoints, 'Benefits', premium tiers... Trade Republic doesn't even let me see cashback accumulation any more.<br /><br />

Complaining stops here. I try to only bitch when I can do something about it.<br /><br />

Cars - no buying anything that contains the word 'infotainment'. If there's a head unit, ensure it's isolated from the rest of the car. Then replace said head unit with your own CIA-backed puppet. Mechanical switches only for everything important: car controls, air conditioning, cruise control, and ideally the handbrake. Mechanical tach and speedometer is a must.<br /><br />

Banks - It's time to Retvrn to your local credit union. Unlike AIB, BOI, PTSB, etc, these guys bail <i>you</i> out.<br /><br />

Every home appliance must be fixable with a hammer and/or a blowtorch. No exceptions.<br /><br />

Once the banal stuff is out of the way, how do we enjoy ourselves?<br /><br />

Digital photography still has plenty of skill curve left for me to climb, but it doesn't feel fruitful any more. Once you hit a certain level of playing with settings on a screen, it all feels academic. The thought of approaching the same hobby while being forced to relearn how everything works - now that's fun. I desperately want to jump into this with a silly little €20 thing and actually fuck around and find out.<br /><br />

Cooking is unenshittifiable... right? Aside from online recipes. Make your own cookbook. And put chicken chasseur in there. You will thank me later.<br /><br />

I've never been good at arts and crafts, but if a cute girl taught me how to stitch and sew I'd be doing it all day everyday. Mostly to sew gay little patches onto things.<br /><br />

And saving all that, there's always domestic terrorism.<br /><br />

<b>Edit:</b> Forgot to mention. Streaming services are evil and Jellyfin servers are the gigachad solution 👍

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I swear I was ahead of the curve on this one. But modern technology has run out of usefulness to me.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Something Somewhere Sometime</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/18/Something-Somewhere-Sometime.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Something Somewhere Sometime" /><published>2025-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-07-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/18/Something-Somewhere-Sometime</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/18/Something-Somewhere-Sometime.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
Another WhatsApp notification buzzes. It's the family group chat, for the tenth time this morning. I swipe it away as always, but refuse to mute it.<br /><br />

I check the password manager daily for logins that still use my deadname. Thirteen. Four relate to work and are therefore stuck for the medium-term. Seven relate to companies that are stubborn, backwards, or just plain broken. Two are last-gasp backups.<br /><br />

Ignore the ninty-three victories, and the stray five logins that are stuck on a different name of mine. The thirteen are the only ones on the mind.<br /><br />

Of course, it won't end once everything is converted. There's always something, or someone, that stands in our way, refusing to budge its worldview of us by an inch. A more wholesome way to approach this would be to embrace only that which accepts us, but alas I am a petty bitch.<br /><br />

There's a few enties that I wouldn't mention on a publicly viewable blog post, but if they prove troublesome I will drag them kicking and screaming into acknowledging our existence. It's been proven time and time again that this is the only reliable solution.<br /><br />

And then what? My brain can't settle for anything. There always has to be another hill to climb.<br /><br />

There's been some very nice moments recently that are brand new to me. Falling asleep with friends nearby, a view of Sandy and Muffin loafing observing their garden, the comfort of visiting a couple's place talking casual things for hours. A lot of it still does not feel real.<br /><br />

Maybe reinforcement of these lovely things is all that's needed. I don't need much more than what's already within reach.<br /><br />

Though I would enjoy breaking the Irish land speed record. 161mph is pathetic. But OTHER than that, I may just have to be content with being content.<br /><br />
</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another WhatsApp notification buzzes. It's the family group chat, for the tenth time this morning. I swipe it away as always, but refuse to mute it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Burning Ink</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/17/Burning-Ink.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Burning Ink" /><published>2025-07-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-07-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/17/Burning-Ink</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/17/Burning-Ink.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
I handwrote a letter today. It was burned into ash, and will never meet another pair of eyes.<br /><br />

The words were in my head for a few years. Mostly formless. Only in the last twelve months did I even begin to believe they were worth legitimising.<br /><br />

It took a lot of external pushes, often accidental ones. I would see another depiction of me, in another lifeform or entity or piece of media, and see myself as I feared I might.<br /><br />

A friend talked to me recently about allostatic load, the concept of repeated wear and tear on the mind and body causing it to fall apart. Initially we thought it related to rocks and I figured it was a very cool metaphor. I loved the thought of a rock still cracking despite the environment around it reducing its pressure and weight, likening that to the experience of having to fall down and become worse before we could get better. Unfortunately I could not find any rocks that behave like this, and allostasis is entirely a physiological thing. Still cool though.<br /><br />

I had seen myself as I had most feared, and knew it was part of me. I felt the thoughts in my mind, and knew they had been restless with nowhere to go for so long. In my case, I wrote them down, forcing myself to believe every word of it. In better circumstances, you may benefit from a different approach.<br /><br />

I may write them down again, with better phrasing, better examples of what I experienced, or better knowledge going into it. But it doesn't feel as necessary as the first time.<br /><br />

Our thoughts are very real. They are worth doing something about. Put them on a sheet of paper, then send it, burn it, or frame it on the wall. Say them to someone who matters. Type them into a letter, or make them into an art piece. But never in your life should you deserve to let them feed on you.<br /><br />

And, just as importantly, never again.<br /><br />
</p>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I handwrote a letter today. It was burned into ash, and will never meet another pair of eyes.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Serial Experiments Lain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/11/Serial-Experiments-Lain.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Serial Experiments Lain" /><published>2025-07-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-07-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/11/Serial%20Experiments-Lain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/11/Serial-Experiments-Lain.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
Lain met me at a strange time in my life. This is always the case for newcomers, as long as she finds you and not the other way around.<br /><br />

Serial Experiments Lain is a cultural icon for good reason. It becomes increasingly a horror piece the more fragmented our online personas become, the more they bleed into the real world, and the less that all of this feels unusual. I don't think it was entirely a deliberate choice from the creators, which makes it all the more interesting. <br /><br />

I'm not going to bother describing the plot or its metaphors. There's hundreds of YouTube videos and online articles that can do that far better than I could. There's a few elements of the show that have stuck themselves into my brain far more than the over-memed one-liners, or the aesthetic vibe pics of Lain that have since gained a life of their own.<br /><br />. 

This show adores the use of silence. It permeates everything. There more you hide from your own thoughts, the worse this sensation picks at you. Lain happily takes advantage of this, throwing overly bright lights at you, or otherwise just uncomfortable situations. The more your ears search for a distraction, the more they pick up a faint buzzing, that infiltrates almost every scene of this show. The Wired, both physical cables and metaphysical thoughts, is always with you.<br /><br />

You cannot escape the phone in your pocket. Not since it became the only way you could hear from your friend. How would you find them otherwise?<br /><br />

Lain's descent into silence should instil fear in you. It's born out of discomfort with herself, that she can only exist as her true self in the Wired. You can do everything there, and nothing here. When the Wired begins to mesh with reality, Lain finds herself phasing out, watching her digital self take over, watching in muted terror as the fake-smile Lain walks away with her life.<br /><br />

I've felt it myself, when the digital me can say things that physical me can't. When either form can't manage it, it's a different kind of dread. Either serves the same purpose, pushing you away from others and into a blank space where you topple at the slightest push.<br /><br />

It might be a strange comparison, but I like to think of this section in a similar vein to what happens in Steins;Gate - a watershed moment that brings all your conceptions and mistakes crashing down upon you.<br /><br />

<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4tm-8HIOHlA">Here's the scene that brings all of these thoughts together.</a> It still hurts to watch, and probably always will.<br /><br />

In Lain's case, with everything else lost, what keeps her final shred of sanity intact is connection. Her love with Alice is one of my favourites in media because of how simple it is. I see it in my friendships, my partnerships. A fragile touch of contact is enough to keep Lain real, even at her worst. The tiniest touch, even in silence, means the world to me.<br /><br />

There are multiple Alices in my life and in yours. We are nothing without them.<br /><br />

I don't really have any closing thoughts. The above has been a jumble in my mind that only became clearer once I was able to push my life forward. It will likely mean something different to me in the future. In a still-novel joy, I look forward to it.<br /><br />

<figure style="margin: 1rem auto; text-align: center;">
<img src="/assets/images/blog/lain-1.jpeg" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; display: block;" />
<figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #666; margin-top: 0.5rem; font-style: italic;">I think about this a normal amount</figcaption>
</figure>

</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lain met me at a strange time in my life. This is always the case for newcomers, as long as she finds you and not the other way around.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Halfway Halfassed Review of Signalis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/08/A-Halfway-Review-of-Signalis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Halfway Halfassed Review of Signalis" /><published>2025-07-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-07-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/08/A-Halfway-Review-of-Signalis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/08/A-Halfway-Review-of-Signalis.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
    Signalis is stupendously well-reviewed. I'm less convinced, and am writing halfway thoughts on the knowledge there's a 50% chance I won't see the finish.<br /><br />

    Aesthetically born from the era of CRT televisions, analogue error codes, and fifth-generation video game consoles. Narratively created via H.P. Lovecraft, Stanley Kubrick, David Lynch, and plenty more I didn't pick up on.<br /><br />
    
    Visually you will feel very at home here if you're familiar with analogue horror. PS1-era graphics and icons help this along, to the extent that you can see the direct inspiration from specific games - Metal Gear Solid comes to mind for some of the more subtle instances.<br /><br />

    Sound design is quite neat. I'm a big fan of the subtle touch, and there's enough audio cues to nudge the player into uncertainty without coming off as in-your-face.<br /><br />

    Mechanics is where the game falls down quite hard. It pulls far too enthusiastically from the old Resident Evil games - you get a key that forces you to backtack two levels, which lets you unlock a safe that gives you a key, which makes you traverse one floor in order to open a door leading to a desk that contains a key, which opens a lift on a different floor that leads to... another key. Utterly obnoxious.<br /><br />

    Heavily limiting the player's inventory would be fine, except for the occasional room contiaining 2-3 key items, forcing you to backtrack multiple floors to the single storage point available to you.<br /><br />

    Puzzles are fine, combat is fine, but the above drags the game to a state where I simply don't care to carry on. The plot is working towards something interesting, but the interest simply isn't there any more. There's nothing wrong with a slightly shorter game.
</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Signalis is stupendously well-reviewed. I'm less convinced, and am writing halfway thoughts on the knowledge there's a 50% chance I won't see the finish.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blood on the Clocktower</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/08/Blood-On-The-Clocktower.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blood on the Clocktower" /><published>2025-07-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-07-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/07/08/Blood-On-The-Clocktower</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/07/08/Blood-On-The-Clocktower.html"><![CDATA[<div>
<p>
    An instant community in a box! How could I say no?<br /><br />
    
    <a href="https://bloodontheclocktower.com/">Blood on the Clocktower</a> is a social deducation game best played in the shaded section of a comfy bar that runs board game nights. I was already suffering from the heat of the upstairs section and the timing was impeccable.<br /><br />

    We had a party of 18, which seemed unmanageable but for the excellent gamemaster who somehow kept on top of every piece of intrigue, truth, lie, and shittalk that was happening. 14 townsfolk, 4 outsiders. I chose outsider due to its handy ability of not tying the player to the game for its entire duration - very handy for someone who likes to step out dramatically and without warning.<br /><br />

    Dennis talked me into playing the Gunslinger. A chaotic role that allowed me to rooty tooty point and shooty one person per night, as long as they voted to execute another player. My strategy for this role revolved around a few core thoughts:<br /><br />
    <ul>
        <li>I had no idea how the intricacies of the game would function</li>
        <li>Chaos is funny when done right</li>
        <li>I could sit back and observe other players, rather than jump straight into accusations that I didn't fully understand</li>
        <li>"???"</li>
        <li>I was sitting at the corner of the circle and can't comprehend shit in large spaces</li>
    </ul>
    Day 1, and another player zooms up to me as soon as the day phase began. He begged me to shoot him, claiming to be the Angel that absolutely should not be executed on pain of instant team failure. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4f7Gh-EABf0">My mind may have been elsewhere during this very interesting conundrum.</a><br /><br />

    I shot him in the face on Night 1 or 2, can't remember which. Either way, he wasn't playing me, and I wouldn't have known otherwise if he was. Good start.<br /><br />

    Days 2 and 3 are where my masterplan come to fruition. At this point I have little clue what the fuck is going on, Matteo is devising a prosecution statement as long as the entire script of Fate/Stay Night, and there's growing confusion as to who has what roles. Unveiling my grand strategy of Shut The Fuck Up, I refuse to shoot anyone for two nights in a row. This has several key benefits:
    <ul>
        <li>Opting not to shoot someone suspected of being Good, AND someone suspected of being Evil, casts me out of this argument by confusing everyone involved</li>
        <li>Enhances my pretty and mysterious demeanour sitting in the corner teeheeheeing because I have no poker face</li>
        <li>Less is more (a good life strategy in general)</li>
    </ul>
    
    Day 4 proceeds, and the gamemaster nudges us along to speed things up. It's been about 90 minutes, and half the townsfolk are still alive. The discussion that night was lively, plenty of votes put forward on all sides, and there was a growing likelihood that our numbers will be thinned significantly by the next morning.<br /><br />

    Naturally, I take out my gun for the first time in over an hour, and shoot the demon in the face on first attempt. Ending the game in the silliest possible way, and a first according to the gamemaster in his 2-3 years of running it.<br /><br />

    This wouldn't be half as funny except for the fact that, out of the three players I was suspecting, I was wrong about all but one of them. And I picked my target randomly.<br /><br />
    
    Don't tell the other players though. I'm sure they won't find out.<br /><br />

    9/10 great game ye should try it
</p>
<script defer="" src="https://comments.oakreef.ie/comentario.js"></script>
<comentario-comments></comentario-comments>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An instant community in a box! How could I say no? Blood on the Clocktower is a social deducation game best played in the shaded section of a comfy bar that runs board game nights. I was already suffering from the heat of the upstairs section and the timing was impeccable.]]></summary></entry></feed>